<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>danielsjourney</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml" />
  <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2011-04-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>loss</subtitle>

  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Baby</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/28/baby.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/28/baby.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Obviously we are thrilled to announce that Carissa is pregnant. I had hoped that this announcement, whenever it came, might...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5661852854/ 7 weeks 5 days sonogram' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5225/5661852854_2b85931e1b_z.jpg' alt='7 weeks 5 days sonogram' />
<p>Obviously we are thrilled to announce that Carissa is pregnant.</p>

<p>I had hoped that this announcement, whenever it came, might be the final post of this blog. I&#8217;m realizing that is probably not the case. There are still some things I&#8217;m going to have to figure out about this experience and this blog has been a half decent place to work out some of those things. (That said, clearly I won&#8217;t be posting here past December, at the latest.)</p>

<p>I&#8217;m hoping Lucy&#8217;s* development, arrival and life is the most beautiful and amazing thing ever experienced by mankind. It will be. It has to be. She has a perfect big sister to make proud.</p>
<p class='date'>April 28, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>* &ldquo;<a href='http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2011/04/baby-miller.html'>Think girl thoughts</a>.&rdquo;</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Fathers do you want...</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/26/fathers.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/26/fathers.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>
  djdc.connected = function() {
    $("img.callout").css("max-width","640px");
  };
</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by niznoz http://www.flickr.com/photos/niznoz/5658108216' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5190/5658108216_01d21a540e_z.jpg' /><script type='text/javascript'>
  djdc.connected = function() {
    $("img.callout").css("max-width","640px");
  };
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Iesus Nazarenus, Rex Iudaeorum</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/24/easter.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/24/easter.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I&#8217;ve always been more interested in the death of Jesus than his resurrection. The resurrection feels like a cop out....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='# http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/04/18/us-france-art-idUSTRE73H4JR20110418' src='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/download.jpeg' />
<p>I&#8217;ve always been more interested in the death of Jesus than his resurrection. The resurrection feels like a cop out. Like the authors and architects of my religion had to make it conform to the standards of mythology and epic narrative.</p>

<p>There are stories of believers who did not immediately learn of the resurrection. They remained faithful for years to the Christ who had died on a cross, before learning that he had afterwards walked through walls and floated up into the sky. Part of me wants to be part of a secret sect who was never brought the News. We would believe because of the man who lived, not the man who lived again. Those of us who died&#8211;our elderly and our children&#8211;would join Him, wherever he was. Not because he had floated into the sky, but because he had gone before us, and stayed there.</p>

<p>Because that some messiah was raised from the dead but then allowed my perfect daughter to go before me is absurd, and I refuse to pretend otherwise. I do not lose hope that there is some explanation, mind you. I would simply point out that your social network proclamations of &#8220;He is risen!&#8221; ring a little flat this season.</p>

<p>Some zealous believers <a href='http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/04/18/us-france-art-idUSTRE73H4JR20110418'>damaged an image of Christ on the cross</a> this week because they thought it defaming. They struck his image in the face. Here He was in his most blatantly symbolic&#8211;molded in cheap plastic by those who claim to honor him, then surrounded by our human waste&#8211;and they erased his face. In their attempts to keep Him separate&#8211;holy and resurrected&#8211;they removed him from us, and left us only with our waste.</p>

<p>They enforce the voice that says this is punishment for historic acts. They remove the hope of rescue from this mire, that this life is not as it seems, that time and its suffering are just a constraint she has been saved from.</p>

<p>There are some who will find the above paragraphs telling of a lost or misguided faith (&#8220;<a href='http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=1%20Corinthians%2015:14-18&amp;version=NASB'>1 Corinthians 15</a>!&#8221; I hear you flipping to), perhaps even compelled to intervene (with a Facebook comment&#8211;LOL!) or pray.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s a great <a href='http://thoughtcatalog.com/2011/easter-jesus-was-way-cool/'>post about Easter</a> that references <a href='http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Mark+8%3A22-24&amp;version=NASB'>Mark 8</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&#8230;This passage has always stuck with me. I don&#8217;t believe that Jesus walked on water or multiplied loaves and fishes. &#8230;But that strange statement by the blind man at the end&#8211;&#8220;I see men like trees, walking around.&#8221; It&#8217;s strange. It&#8217;s beautiful. And it sounds real. It doesn&#8217;t sound fake. It sounds like something that a blind man, upon seeing the world for the first time, might actually say. Groping for something to compare the sight of fellow human beings to, he might say that they remind him of trees; landlocked trees that he has touched and felt before&#8211;trees that are suddenly uprooted and are moving around.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>It&#8217;s an eerie passage&#8230;<span>it</span> does seem oddly convincing&#8211;in a way that is different from so much of the Bible, which so often does not seem oddly convincing. And so, did a bunch of people actually see Jesus restore sight to a blind man? &#8230;Well? &#8230;Did they?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I&#8217;ve always been more convinced by curious disbelief than by firm, rational beliefs.</p>
<p class='date'>April 24, 2011</p><p class='postscript'><a href='http://www.kesterbrewin.com/2011/04/19/piss-christ-sanitising-death-and-torture/'>Here is another good analysis of the Piss Christ vandalism by my friend Kester</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Music is a world within itself with a language we all understand</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/23/music.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/23/music.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>My friends from Albuquerque, Lousy Robot, were in town last night and I rather enjoyed their set of music at...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Dandee Fleming and Joey Gonzales of Lousy Robot, photo by Kate Mackley http://www.flickr.com/photos/katemackley/5645792898/in/photostream' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5064/5645792898_2cd64f2237_z.jpg' />
<p>My friends from Albuquerque, <a href='http://music.lousyrobot.com/'><em>Lousy Robot</em></a>, were in town last night and I rather enjoyed their set of music at the Double Wide. I had a lot of profound thoughts during the show but I must have washed them all away with IPA. Simply put: music is awesome.</p>

<p>Dandee (pictured) really enjoys playing and it shows when he is on stage. The world could do for a few more musicians like Dandee and a few more bands like Lousy Robot.</p>
<p class='date'>April 23, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">&amp;ldquo;Busy day&amp;hellip;but there&amp;rsquo;s always time for the paper.&amp;rdquo;</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/20/busy.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/20/busy.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Things have been busy and will continue to be so. There is more good news to come. There is work...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='&ldquo;Busy day in Manhattan&hellip;but there&rsquo;s always time for the paper.&rdquo; via From Me To You http://fromme-toyou.tumblr.com/post/4778641278/busy-day-in-manhattan-but-theres-always-time-for' src='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/tumblr_ljyjrpJZIz1qzcq51o1_500.gif' />
<p>Things have been <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/withextrasauce/status/60026226236080128'>busy</a> and will continue to be so. There is more good news to come. There is work to be done. It still comes and goes in waves. There are still a couple things I wrestle with and perhaps will make observations about on this blog but for the most part this is wrapping itself up and I am trying to strategize a move back to&#8211;and re-inclusion of the archives of&#8211;my regular blog.</p>

<p>Here are some pics of recent life:</p>
<a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5631350506/' title='Soccer Picnic by carissabyers, on Flickr'><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5024/5631350506_f18bfaed10.jpg' height='334' alt='Soccer Picnic' width='500' /></a><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5609519035/' title='Lakewood Spring Carival by carissabyers, on Flickr'><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5224/5609519035_2888310e75_z.jpg' alt='Lakewood Spring Carival' /></a><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5610098872/' title='Lakewood Spring Carival by carissabyers, on Flickr'><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5145/5610098872_a1a00a86bc.jpg' height='334' alt='Lakewood Spring Carival' width='500' /></a><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5600708590/' title='Deep Ellum Arts Festival by carissabyers, on Flickr'><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5064/5600708590_0ed44e0c80.jpg' height='334' alt='Deep Ellum Arts Festival' width='500' /></a><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5607442933/' title='Goalie Penn by carissabyers, on Flickr'><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5106/5607442933_015ee04684.jpg' height='334' alt='Goalie Penn' width='500' /></a><p class='date'>April 20, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">There is so much going on in this video it kind of freaks me out</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/15/so-much.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/15/so-much.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='390' width='640'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/3i-zYdOPG2k?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0&amp;hd=1' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/3i-zYdOPG2k?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0&amp;hd=1' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='390' width='640' /></object></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Perhaps because it is the most beautiful sport, it is the most trouble-ridden</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/12/dope.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/12/dope.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I mentioned a while ago that I might write a long post about the doping issue in professional cycling. At...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='http://www.flickr.com/photos/slabbers/23072082/ Photo by Bastiaan Slabbers' src='http://farm1.static.flickr.com/18/23072082_0571604453.jpg' />
<p>I <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/07/super-bowl.html'>mentioned a while ago</a> that I might write a long post about the doping issue in professional cycling. At the time I was catching up on all the information available, specifically about Lance Armstrong and in light of the <a href='http://nyvelocity.com/content/interviews/2011/landiskimmage'>very long interview of Floyd Landis</a> I spent quite a few days reading and analyzing. If you&#8217;re really interested in this subject, I suggest you read it.</p>

<p>In the meantime, Bicycling magazine&#8217;s Bill Strickland has <a href='https://www.readability.com/articles/hfwviezu'>published a really well done piece in their latest issue</a> which says everything I wanted to say but with more writing talent, insight and experience than I have.</p>
<p class='date'>April 12, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Confused by the situation in Libya? Me too. Read this.</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/11/libya.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/11/libya.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Adam Curtis is one of my favorite thinkers. His blog on the BBC&#8217;s website rarely disappoints and this analysis of...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by Maud Tessa Benardeau &apos;50,000 people commemorated Sunday, July 11, 2010, the 15th anniversary of Srebrenica massacre in Bosnia. 775 identified bodies, 15 years later.&apos; http://www.flickr.com/photos/phileasmoon/4856442135/in/photostream/' src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4142/4856442135_277d81fd18.jpg' />
<p>Adam Curtis is one of my favorite thinkers. His blog on the BBC&#8217;s website rarely disappoints and this analysis of the historical precedents that have led to the international response in Libya is no exception: <a href='http://www.bbc.co.uk/blogs/adamcurtis/2011/03/goodies_and_baddies.html'>Goodies and Baddies</a>.</p>

<p>The videos are both horrible and slow. I read the article first w/o watching the video and it&#8217;s honestly better that way. Although the first is rather interesting and reminiscent of Curtis&#8217; documentary <em>The Century of Self</em> which I also highly <a href='http://www.google.com/search?q=century+of+self'>recommend</a>.</p>

<p>About &#190; of the way through&#8211;as I mentioned yesterday&#8211;the Bosnian crisis is brought up, specifically Srebrenica. Honestly I did not get very far through that video before I had to stop it. Somehow the Balkans have been the epicenter for so much of the confusing mire that is human political interaction and conflict. The result has certainly left its scar on the people there. There aren&#8217;t many places like it.</p>

<p>We&#8217;re really a complicated and horrible people, it turns out.</p>
<p class='date'>April 11, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Mofiasco</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/10/mofiasco.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/10/mofiasco.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I said in January that I should re-post this story. Took a while. I read a really amazing blog post...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='http://www.flickr.com/photos/nigel321/2254589407/ photo by Nigel Swales' src='http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2355/2254589407_4160be1ea0.jpg' />
<p>I <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/24/reamericana.html'>said in January</a> that I should re-post this story. Took a while. I read a really amazing blog post today and its narrative involved the Bosnian crisis, so it inspired me to finally re-post this. I&#8217;ll share that blog post tomorrow.</p>

<p>I should set the scene: August 2003. I&#8217;ve been in Bosnia since the beginning of April. I have recorded an EP, my first project since a CD I hastily put together my last semester in college in 1997. I have a band comprised of three Balkan misfits I already have a great affection for. My drummer, Elvis, also produced the EP. I have a &#8220;CD release&#8221; gig at the longest-established rock club in Sarajevo (it existed&#8211;in some form&#8211;during the siege). I&#8217;m leaving in the days following the gig for the Slovakian mountains&#8211;a vacation with my wife&#8217;s family&#8211;and the Greenbelt festival in the UK, where I have a gig. This is the day of the gig:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>So we have an ok rehearsal yesterday afternoon, I&#8217;m sure there will be some fuck ups tonight at the gig, but we&#8217;ll plow through them and in general rock, as long as there is a good crowd with some energy. I will definitely have NO voice after the gig. Just as well.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>After we were done, around 7:30, the guys took me to pick up the CD&#8217;s. I immediately got a bad feeling when I was no longer dealing with the guy I had been dealing with all along, but was picking up the CD&#8217;s from these two gangster-looking guys working out of their low-rider Benz. I got back in our car with the CD&#8217;s and immediately Elvis goes, &#8220;Were they mofia or what?&#8221; I said, &#8221;I&#8217;m never doing business with that guy again.&#8221; But I got my CD&#8217;s, they didn&#8217;t look half bad, so that was that. I thought.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>I got home and first thing stuck one in the CD player. I was never concerned about the music reproduction because, after all, this is now digital to digital reproduction, exactly like when you or I burn a CD on our computer: an exact copy, and you don&#8217;t have to be a techie to burn a CD on a computer, right? I was checking the disk more for skips or improper tracking (the pirated CD&#8217;s here are almost never tracked correctly, meaning &#8220;track 1&#8221; is the first song plus a split second of song 2&#8211;a major pain in the ass when you have your CD player on &#8220;random&#8221;)&#8230;&#8230;but I popped it in and immediately, within a second, could tell something was horribly wrong&#8230;</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>You&#8217;re thinking: &#8220;The CD contained Bosnian turbo-folk music!&#8221; NO! That, my friend, would have been great&#8211;at least some hilarity to go along with my shock, disappointment and confusion.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>The sound quality was simply horrible. It sounded like an analog recording reproduced 100 times (you know, like a tape of a tape of a tape &#8230; + 98 more times). My heart immediately sunk to the ground floor (we live on the 4th). I tried another one in disbelief&#8230;how could they fuck this up? &#8230;but it was exactly the same shitty quality. I had one of my 2 masters sitting right there, so I confirmed that it was fine; it was. I thought maybe the master I gave them was fucked up somehow, so I ran and grabbed it from the other room; it was fine too. I tried yet another CD off a different spindle and it was the same. I was fucked.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>I called M in hysterics, I didn&#8217;t even know where she was or if she was going to help me. It was almost 9pm on a Tuesday and I was alone in a city that loves to hate me, up against some mobsters who had just ripped me off.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>Now that was mostly just fucked right up the ass. Excuse my colorful metaphor. But this being the last minute and all, there was no fixing this problem in time.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>M was out somewhere, and she offered to help me out and asked if I wanted her friends to come with. I said, yeah, that might be good. I called the guy I got the CD&#8217;s from, told him the problem, and we decided to meet right away to talk about it. M came and picked me up and we went to where those friends were hanging out. One friend in particular is this older guy with tons of connections all over the city. He first called the guy I was dealing with&#8230;then things got a little out of control&#8230;</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>I just wanted some emotional backup, but I got a touch more than that&#8230;M&#8217;s friend called the kind of guys* everyone is afraid of, apparently. Already long story short, the 4 of us went up the restaurant with the CD&#8217;s, I explained to Jr. Gangster Kid the problem, he just shrugged his shoulders and said, &#8220;What do you want?&#8221; I said a refund, there was some hooing and hawing&#8230;and then, and this I did not see at all, only heard about it&#8211;those guys everyone is afraid of&#8211;showed up, they had just pulled their car into the parking lot, and within a few seconds I was getting my money back.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>I bought the CD sleeves from somebody else, so I now have 280 CD sleeves and no CD&#8217;s. Today I&#8217;m burning copies of the disk to take to GB, to at least give away to people. Funny thing is, I could&#8217;ve probly burnt the 280 in 2 days with my two burners&#8230;even with my shit software I could&#8217;ve done a better, faster job by myself, with just some CD labels, than this guy did. When I get back in September, I&#8217;ll start looking at companies in the States who do CD printing, and it will be the end of the year before I see any CD&#8217;s that way, but at least I know they&#8217;ll be OK.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>&#8230;the end&#8230;how things changed after that. I was actually back in the States in September, never to return to Bosnia again&#8230;</p>
<p class='date'>April 10, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>* They were known as the <em>gray eminence</em>, which I had never heard of at the time and thought sounded a bit funny but it turns out is a <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%89minence_grise'>real thing</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">...guess he was sleep golfing?</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/08/sleep-golfing.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/08/sleep-golfing.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I&#8217;ve had a couple of dreams lately about passing out on golf courses. Last night&#8217;s was really involved. I was...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='349' width='560'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/nr1XgsjL6HQ?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/nr1XgsjL6HQ?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='349' width='560' /></object></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve had a couple of dreams lately about passing out on golf courses. Last night&#8217;s was really involved. I was having to pay for my clothes having been dry cleaned while I was asleep. The bill was <span style='font-family: Georgia, serif'>$</span>170 and there were clothes in the bag that weren&#8217;t mine. While they were adjusting the bill and telling me it wasn&#8217;t going to make that much of a difference&#8211;there was some serious subtext from the staff that I was really being charged for spending the night at the golf course&#8211;I finally had the realization: if my clothes had been dry cleaned and lay now in front of me on the counter, what clothes was I wearing now and how did I get into them? At that point I think the dissonance was too much for the Dream Plot Generator and I woke up. It was a few minutes later that I remembered the Donnie Darko scene.</p>

<p>There&#8217;s a lot to unpack and not much of it is too mysterious, really. I&#8217;m just curious: why golf courses?</p>
<p class='date'>April 08, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>The beginning of this scene&mdash;when the jet engine falls through the house&mdash;always seems to me to be overacted by Maggie Gyllenhaal. Sure, the sky is falling&mdash;literally&mdash;but would that really reduce a 19 year old woman to cowering and tears? (The next sentence will make NO sense if you haven't seen the movie.) The only way my brain has been able to interpret that performance is that she had some precognition of the other/real timeline, and her reaction in this scene ties to the final scene when the plot's main timeline ends and you're returned to this point. I've thought about that final scene a lot lately.</p><p class='postscript'>Life's been pretty ok lately, actually. I want to share but none of the good things are shareable...yet. I thought my experience would make all other life stressors&mdash;good and bad&mdash;easier to navigate. It hasn't, really&mdash;those things are just as stressful as ever, it's just that they're relatively not a big deal. Monsters are smaller. Recovery is faster.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">(Anything but) Existential Indifference</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/02/existential-indifference.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/02/existential-indifference.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I somewhat recently discovered Oliver Burkeman and have found his columns rather good. This week&#8217;s is no exception: &#8230;Garcin is...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='http://www.flickr.com/photos/92661859@N00/2311071031/ I like Mike Bitzenhofer&apos;s approach to existentialism: &apos;Eggistentialism&apos;' src='http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3129/2311071031_d977ff5c1c.jpg' />
<p>I somewhat recently discovered <a href='http://twitter.com/oliverburkeman'>Oliver Burkeman</a> and have found his columns rather good. This week&#8217;s is no exception:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&#8230;Garcin is having an existential crisis, as people tend to do in Sartre. (These days, he could just pick up a copy of <a href='http://www.purposedrivenlife.com/en-US/Home/home.htm'>The Purpose-Driven Life</a> and be done with it.) He&#8217;s facing the Big Question: how to deal with life&#8217;s apparent meaninglessness? Of course, many other philosophers, not to mention self-help gurus, would argue that life isn&#8217;t meaningless&#8211;that meaning&#8217;s to be found in family, or work, or spirituality. But intriguing new research suggests that, for a sizeable chunk of the population, a different answer to the Big Question may be more pertinent: who cares?</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href='https://www.readability.com/articles/00qcgokg'>&#8230;read the rest</a>.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve long been interested in meaning formation as a primary motivator of human behavior and a majority stakeholder in any person&#8217;s happiness (I&#8217;m a big fan of <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man&apos;s_Search_for_Meaning'>Frankl</a>). As I&#8217;ve tried to parse the recent events of my life, this is often the lens I use. I&#8217;m often confused by others who appear to have this existential indifference that Burkeman refers to. On one hand, I want to be able to move through life with more aplomb. On the other hand, it sure seems like a lot of us here sharing this planet just don&#8217;t care.</p>

<p>Of course existential crisis is not required to do important work. I have a friend who spends a lot of time thinking about how to work better and does excellent work partly due to that intention (he&#8217;s also just a hard worker). About a year age were discussing his strategies for maintaining focus and doing meaningful work&#8211;I was just starting work on <a href='http://todoblin.com'>Todoblin</a> and particularly interested (as I always am, really) in <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grok'>groking</a> how people work. I asked him, &#8220;Don&#8217;t you ever have moments of existential crisis?&#8221; He just kind of gave me a look that said something like, &#8220;You speak of this &#8216;existential crisis&#8217; like it&#8217;s something that actually happens to people.&#8221;</p>
<p class='date'>April 02, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">...lonely is healing if you make it</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/29/how-to-be-alone.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/29/how-to-be-alone.html</id>
    <updated>2011-03-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I feel like I&#8217;ve posted this already, I think because I&#8217;ve tweeted it twice now. It was good to be...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='390' width='640'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/k7X7sZzSXYs?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/k7X7sZzSXYs?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='390' width='640' /></object></p>
<p>I feel like I&#8217;ve posted this already, I think because I&#8217;ve tweeted it twice now. It was good to be reminded of it again today.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">&amp;ldquo;Real men go on&amp;rdquo;</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/24/real-men-go-on.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/24/real-men-go-on.html</id>
    <updated>2011-03-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>&#8230;real men tough it out in life, they get up and go on living despite setbacks&#8230;[it takes] maturity to deal...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by Rob Brewer http://www.flickr.com/photos/rbrwr/271634009/' src='http://farm1.static.flickr.com/82/271634009_6a2d67a360.jpg' />
<blockquote>
<p>&#8230;real men tough it out in life, they get up and go on living despite setbacks&#8230;[it takes] maturity to deal with the blows&#8230;</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href='http://blogs.dallasobserver.com/dc9/2011/03/bill_holstons_take_on_last_nig.php'>Bill Holston, paraphrasing Frank Campagna at Adam Carter&#8217;s memorial</a>.</p>
<p class='date'>March 24, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Michigan</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/23/michigan.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/23/michigan.html</id>
    <updated>2011-03-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>
Carissa posted pictures and a blog post about our trip to Michigan&#8230;
















March 23, 2011</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='# http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5550534620/in/faves-dealingwith/' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5296/5550534620_abe31267a7_z.jpg' />
<p>Carissa posted <a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/sets/72157626201223847/'>pictures</a> and a <a href='http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2011/03/michigan-2011.html'>blog post</a> about our trip to Michigan&#8230;</p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5263/5550536544_0c61bfae54_z.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5057/5549954813_11f8e24032.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5305/5550543436_d2522abfbb_z.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5179/5550545742_f859d2a244.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5022/5549968663_a83df64e9f.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5258/5550551220_738436bff4.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5030/5550553918_1aa9826f72_z.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5023/5549973637_6a55628cb1_z.jpg' alt='' /></p>
<p class='date'>March 23, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Determinedistic</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/22/determined.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/22/determined.html</id>
    <updated>2011-03-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Kings of Convenience - Scars on Land I&#8217;ve said before that there are certain questions that are now &#8220;best escorted...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_1'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/13%20Scars%20On%20Land.mp3'>Kings of Convenience - Scars on Land</a></span></span></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve said before that there are certain questions that are now &#8220;<a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/24/what-now.html'>best escorted out of the park by security</a>&#8221; &#8230;and maybe you noticed that was the first of a trilogy: &#8220;What now?&#8221; &#8220;<a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/28/I-can-not-go-on.html'>I&#8217;ll go on.</a>&#8221; &#8220;<a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/07/bikes.html'>Not because [I want] to but because [I have] to.</a>&#8221;</p>

<p>The problem with the deeper questions surrounding our loss and our lives is that they are the questions that have existed for all time and our answers&#8211;or lack thereof&#8211;are the same as well. The search for meaning evolves into a search to be more human, to connect to&#8211;not a Truth&#8211;but the truth of what it means to here with others.</p>

<p>So today I was reading some posts by my friend Kester Brewin and he wrote <a href='http://www.kesterbrewin.com/2011/03/15/free-will-determinism-heaven-hell/'>something that made a tiny bit of sense</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&#8230;we cannot prove if heaven and hell exist, but it&#8217;s a natural response to want the world to be fair, to be sorted out and judged at some point so that justice is done. A deterministic universe it might be&#8211;just chemicals and electrons&#8211;but this is not a world that we find &#8220;human&#8221; precisely because it makes a nonsense of ideas of love&#8211;and hate too.</p>
</blockquote>
<p class='date'>March 22, 2011</p><p class='postscript'><blockquote style='font-style:italic'>The weight of lead<br />
On floors of sand<br />
The idea reduced again<br />
To outcome<br />
<br />
No chain stays unbroken<br />
All aims get forgotten</blockquote></p><script type='text/javascript'>  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/13%20Scars%20On%20Land.mp3",  
        titles: "Scars on Land",  
        artists: "Kings of Convenience"});
  });
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
