<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>danielsjourney</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml" />
  <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2011-10-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>loss</subtitle>

  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Steve</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/10/06/steve.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/10/06/steve.html</id>
    <updated>2011-10-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>The problem is I'm older now, I'm 40 years old, and this stuff doesn't change the world. It really doesn't....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/steve-jobs-at-home-1982.jpg" title=""></p>

<blockquote><p>The problem is I&rsquo;m older now, I&rsquo;m 40 years old, and this stuff doesn&rsquo;t change the world. It really doesn&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry, it&rsquo;s true. Having children really changes your view on these things. We&rsquo;re born, we live for a brief instant, and we die. It&rsquo;s been happening for a long time. Technology is not changing it much&mdash;if at all.</p>

<p>&ldquo;These technologies can make life easier, can let us touch people we might not otherwise. You may have a child with a birth defect and be able to get in touch with other parents and support groups, get medical information, the latest experimental drugs. These things can profoundly influence life. I&rsquo;m not downplaying that.</p>

<p>&ldquo;But it&rsquo;s a disservice to constantly put things in this radical new light&mdash;that it&rsquo;s going to change everything. Things don&rsquo;t have to change the world to be important.&rdquo; [<a href="http://www.wired.com/wired/archive/4.02/jobs_pr.html">Wired, February 1996</a>]</p></blockquote>

<hr>


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;We think the Mac will sell zillions, but we didn&rsquo;t build the Mac for anybody else. We built it for ourselves. We were the group of people who were going to judge whether it was great or not. We weren&rsquo;t going to go out and do market research. We just wanted to build the best thing we could build.</p>

<p>&ldquo;When you&rsquo;re a carpenter making a beautiful chest of drawers, you&rsquo;re not going to use a piece of plywood on the back, even though it faces the wall and nobody will ever see it. You&rsquo;ll know it&rsquo;s there, so you&rsquo;re going to use a beautiful piece of wood on the back. For you to sleep well at night, the aesthetic, the quality, has to be carried all the way through.&rdquo; [<a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/43945579/Playboy-Interview-With-Steve-Jobs">Playboy, Feb. 1, 1985</a>]</p></blockquote>

<hr>


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Design is a funny word. Some people think design means how it looks. But of course, if you dig deeper, it&rsquo;s really how it works. The design of the Mac wasn&rsquo;t what it looked like, although that was part of it. Primarily, it was how it worked&hellip;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Creativity is just connecting things. When you ask creative people how they did something, they feel a little guilty because they didn&rsquo;t really do it, they just saw something. It seemed obvious to them after a while. That&rsquo;s because they were able to connect experiences they&rsquo;ve had and synthesize new things. And the reason they were able to do that was that they&rsquo;ve had more experiences or they have thought more about their experiences than other people.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Unfortunately, that&rsquo;s too rare a commodity. A lot of people in our industry haven&rsquo;t had very diverse experiences. So they don&rsquo;t have enough dots to connect, and they end up with very linear solutions without a broad perspective on the problem. The broader one&rsquo;s understanding of the human experience, the better design we will have.&rdquo; [Wired, February 1996]</p></blockquote>

<hr>


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;So when these people sell out, even though they get fabulously rich, they&rsquo;re gypping themselves out of one of the potentially most rewarding experiences of their unfolding lives. Without it, they may never know their values or how to keep their newfound wealth in perspective.&rdquo; [Fortune, Jan. 24, 2000]</p></blockquote>

<hr>


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;[Innovation] comes from saying no to 1,000 things to make sure we don&rsquo;t get on the wrong track or try to do too much.&rdquo; [<a href="http://www.businessweek.com/bwdaily/dnflash/oct2004/nf20041012_4018_db083.htm">BusinessWeek, Oct. 12, 2004</a>]</p></blockquote>

<hr>


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Being the richest man in the cemetery doesn&rsquo;t matter to me&hellip;Going to bed at night saying we&rsquo;ve done something wonderful&hellip;that&rsquo;s what matters to me.&rdquo; [The Wall Street Journal, May 25, 1993]</p></blockquote>

<p class="no-caps"><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2011/08/24/steve-jobss-best-quotes/">Steve Jobs's Best Quotes</a></p>


<p><a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/%23ThankYouSteve">#ThankYouSteve</a></p>

<p class="date">October 06, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">Update: Wow, <a href="http://daringfireball.net/2011/10/universe_dented_grass_underfoot">John Gruber with a really beautiful and fitting piece, <span style="font-style:italic">Universe Dented, Grass Underfoot</span></a>.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">This is not a continuation of the last post</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/10/04/this-is-not.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/10/04/this-is-not.html</id>
    <updated>2011-10-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Today I rode by bicycle to work for the second day in a row. I changed the gearing on this...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/commute-panda.jpg" title=""></p>

<p>Today I rode by bicycle to work for the second day in a row. I changed the gearing on this particular bike to be somewhat easy to pedal as well as making it a fixed gear bicycle* (it can be &ldquo;flipped&rdquo; between fixed and free). This makes it much easier to get started from a stop, especially given the total weight of bike, cargo-carrying accessories, and cargo itself combined. It also keeps me at a slow optimal speed and therefore a lower level of perspiration. The one thing the fixed gear specifically requires, however, is using the legs for braking power. And wow have my legs been sore from that!</p>

<p>There are many things I want to complain about today, but then I think about how I had lunch at <a href="http://www.charliepalmer.com/Properties/CharliePalmerAtJoule/">Charlie Palmer</a> and <a href="http://www.cigarzpizza.com/">Cigarz</a>** pizza and <a href="http://www.boston.com/lifestyle/food/blogs/99bottles/2011/08/review_stone_escondidian_imper.html">Stone Black IPA</a> for dinner (followed by a Full Sail Sanctuary), and rode one bike to work and another bike after work and I realize that I can&rsquo;t complain, really.</p>

<p>(I was going to say something profound here but didn&rsquo;t. Instead of letting this post lay in drafts I&rsquo;m just going to publish it as-is.)</p>

<p class="date">October 04, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">* the move to fixed had its own reasoning&mdash;the freewheel was making all kinds of annoying noises. To get a non-noisy freewheel, apparently, takes some dough. (This is my second &ldquo;cheap&rdquo; freewheel so far.) The inconvenience of riding fixed will take some time to justify spending $100 on a good one.<br><br>** Dallas people if you have not had this pizza it's OMG good. Get the Greek Pizza.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">So what now? The problem with desire.</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/10/02/desire.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/10/02/desire.html</id>
    <updated>2011-10-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I now have a series of posts lined up but I'm not sure if I'll finish any of them, so...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/HWG6VW9pkE4?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>


<p>I now have a series of posts lined up but I&rsquo;m not sure if I&rsquo;ll finish any of them, so I&rsquo;m just going to post stuff as it becomes concise enough to post, which means it will probably be out of order and incoherent as a whole. Also please excuse me if on this post and possibly others I&rsquo;m just re-writing <a href="http://peterrollins.net/">Pete Rollins</a> in my own words and for my own benefit.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Wiley Coyote Retires&rdquo; (which is NSFW unless you work somewhere awesome like Extra Sauce) does a really good job of addressing what happens when one achieves their desire, when their desire is achievable (for example, as we say in the technology startup world, &ldquo;fuck you money&rdquo;). Of course those who have had success rarely retire early to their <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gqjGPIYJsh0">special island</a>, they usually insert themselves into others' brilliance by becoming an angel investor or venture capitalist or special advisor (which somehow seems like retiring from porn to become a fluffer), or they just go do <a href="http://denniscrowley.com/">the exact same thing over again</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://mlkshk.com/p/7TL4"><img src="http://mlkshk.com/r/7TL4"></a></p>

<p>Or, as my former business partner Dan and I used to joke, they develop a mandatory coke habit. And the idea that having enough money means a freedom from anxiety about money <a href="http://www.dailymotion.com/video/x1xdq0_notorious-big-mo-money-mo-problem_music">just isn&rsquo;t true</a>. Besides, where would you be without all that misplaced anxiety? You&rsquo;d simply misplace it elsewhere. Billionaires and soccer moms and spoiled children are all pretty much the same thing.</p>

<iframe width="490" height="279" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/R8vJgYQU_lY?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><a href="http://peterrollins.net/?p=1795">Pete&rsquo;s answer to this problem is</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Perhaps there is another possibility, if we are lucky enough to find it. And that is in finding and being with the one we love. In being with the one we love we gain what we desire while remaining at a distance from it. When we love someone they are present to us as a mystery. They are the opening to, and encounter with, otherness itself. They are a vast and endless ocean.</p></blockquote>

<p>Which at the moment just leaves me here in my loss, and in my fears of potential loss. (Pete is probably talking about an existential love with some more abstract &ldquo;other&rdquo; but I&rsquo;ll allow him his own continued thinking on these matters and not conjecture further on his conclusions.)</p>

<p>I feel like I&rsquo;m close to wrapping my head around a third way that might illuminate a way forward. This stuff gets all smashed together with meaning and identity formation&hellip; [to be continued]</p>

<p class="date">October 02, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">This is the Problem</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/29/the-problem.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/29/the-problem.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Tracy Chapman - Mountain O' Things All I want is to have Margot back. I don't want anything else. I...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_1"><a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/06%20Mountains%20O'%20Things.mp3">Tracy Chapman - Mountain O' Things</a></span></span></p>


<p>All I want is to have Margot back.</p>

<br><br>


<p>I don&rsquo;t want anything else.</p>

<p>I would give up every penny I have, every penny I will ever have, to have her back.</p>

<p>I would give up everything, every last moment of pleasure, to have her back.</p>

<p>Hell. I would give up all of it for 5 minutes with her.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s hard to be motivated by desire when your only desire is impossible.</p>

<p class="date">September 29, 2011</p>




<script type="text/javascript">  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/06%20Mountains%20O'%20Things.mp3,http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/11%20For%20You.mp3",  
        titles: "Mountains O' Things, For You",  
        artists: "Tracy Chapman"});
  });
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">...an interesting case study in how life never allows for clear distinctions, or for real existential comfort whatsoever</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/28/different-values.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/28/different-values.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>In conversation yesterday the date December 8th came up and I slipped, "December 8th is Margot's--I mean Lucy's--due date." I...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/69/202159949_eac7a631df.jpg" title="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zenitram/202159949/ photo by susie martinez"></p>

<p>In conversation yesterday the date December 8th came up and I slipped, &ldquo;December 8th is Margot&rsquo;s&mdash;I mean Lucy&rsquo;s&mdash;due date.&rdquo; I was smiling&mdash;the emotion and anticipation of Lucy&rsquo;s arrival thrown across my face&mdash;as I made the mistake and the dissonance between what I was thinking and what my ears heard my mouth say was distinct.</p>

<p>Certainly, things are getting easier, in terms of emotionally surviving every day, in terms of emotionally surviving the constant reminders and triggers. But Lucy being both an unspeakable joy and a trigger is certainly an interesting case study in how life never allows for clear distinctions, or for real existential comfort whatsoever.</p>

<hr>


<p>On the other hand, I often feel oddly privileged by my lack of concern for those things that often trouble those untouched by such unfortunate experiences. But while I&rsquo;m much more able to exist in the moment, I also live in constant fear of what the following moment could contain.</p>

<p>Money, and its concerns either in abundance or decline? No problem! My family driving <em>anywhere</em> without me? Horror at the innumerable threats that stand between them and their safe return.</p>

<p>Strife&mdash;others' conflicts, stressors, disfunctions&mdash;when it finds its way into my experience? Ha! But let your toddler wander farther than five feet from you and I get a shot of fear-induced adrenaline through my veins.</p>

<hr>


<p>But those concerns reflect values, and I&rsquo;m left observing my own from a strange distance, noticing how they have changed in a way I probably would have never known except perhaps through old age. Still, these values won&rsquo;t make me more successful in the world&rsquo;s eyes (although I&rsquo;m open to the chance, don&rsquo;t get me wrong). They don&rsquo;t make me immune to anything in particular. They&rsquo;ve just given me access&hellip;to what I&rsquo;m still trying to determine.</p>

<p class="date">September 28, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">L'Eroica</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/27/leroica.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/27/leroica.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Finally we realize, that people nowadays still like cycling as a formative discipline. . .Cycling, above all, is about effort. It is...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<div class="media"><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/20622427?portrait=0" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen allowFullScreen></iframe></div>


<blockquote><p>Finally we realize, that people nowadays still like cycling as a formative discipline&hellip;Cycling, above all, is about effort. It is also about adventure and travel but above all, the effort.</p></blockquote>

<p class="date">September 27, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">&amp;#8220;le fini d&amp;eacute;fini par le non fini&amp;#8221;</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/25/le-fini.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/25/le-fini.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>In 1965, in his studio in Warsaw, Opa&#x142;ka began painting a process of counting &#x2013; from one to infinity. Starting...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/RomanOpalka2.jpg" title="Roman Opalka"></p>

<blockquote><p>In 1965, in his studio in Warsaw, Opa&#x142;ka began painting a process of counting &#x2013; from one to infinity. Starting in the top left-hand corner of the canvas and finishing in the bottom right-hand corner, the tiny numbers were painted in horizontal rows. Each new canvas, which the artist called a &lsquo;detail&rsquo;, took up counting where the last left off. Each &lsquo;detail&rsquo; is the same size (196 x 135 cm), the dimension of his studio door in Warsaw. All details have the same title, &ldquo;1965 / 1 &#x2013; &infin;&rdquo;; the concept had no end, and the artist pledged his life to its execution: &lsquo;All my work is a single thing, the description from number one to infinity. A single thing, a single life.&rsquo;</p>

<p>The final number he wrote was 5,607,249</p></blockquote>

<p class="postscript">Via the internet via <a href="http://mlkshk.com/p/7NH7">ftrain</a>. Text from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roman_Opa%C5%82ka">wikipedia</a>. Image from <a href="http://opalka1965.com/en/index_en.php">the official website</a>.

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Where can we go to feel?</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/21/where-can-we-go.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/21/where-can-we-go.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Wheeler Sparks: . . .to swallow ground by bus and train and foot and still only just reach the crest of the...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2558/3703829924_8800c4e88f.jpg" title="http://www.flickr.com/photos/37324043@N00/3703829924/ road blocks in Siberia by Copper Kettle"></p>

<p><a href="http://wheelersparks.com/2011/09/a-note-from-author-john-graves/">Wheeler Sparks</a>:</p>

<br><br>


<blockquote><p>&hellip;to swallow ground by bus and train and foot and still only just reach the crest of the wave where everyone else is headed soon, of course there is a sadness there. A fading sense of discovery. Where can we go to feel we have truly explored?</p></blockquote>

<p>Time is marching on as it tends to do. Bad days are less frequent and more vague in their symptoms (yet today is one). I feel like so much of what I&rsquo;ve written about here is about running away from <em>then</em> either into the distant past or into some more present present, like exploring geographic and emotional territories on my bicycle (actually the bicycle is the perfect combination of nostalgia and forward movement). Oh, and drinking. To some extent I&rsquo;ve allowed myself all of this due to the simple fact that the pain of thinking about Margot&mdash;even typing her name&mdash;is so horrible, so vast, so overwhelming that I&rsquo;ve had no choice but avoid it or be consumed by it.</p>

<p>But it calls like a distant wind. The trees rustle on the periphery and there is no stopping that invisible force, it will soon be on your face. And while it is sometimes a touch, this is Texas and it is usually a punch.</p>

<p>It seems that for her, and for her sister&rsquo;s sake, I will need to turn and face it. I just wish I knew what that meant.</p>

<p class="date">September 21, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Why Do I Exist?</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/14/whats-for-lunch.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/14/whats-for-lunch.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>
</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/why-do-i-exist1.jpg" title="from here http://www.heylamington.com/archives/70"></p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Into My Arms</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/13/into-my-arms.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/13/into-my-arms.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>

</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<div class="media"><iframe width="480" height="390" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/73UXRl_ILZ0?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Peace</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/11/peace.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/11/peace.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I wonder how many people are out there who wish you would not use the anniversary of their loss to...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1169/1471413413_f0b8f52760.jpg" title="'island' by fastboy http://www.flickr.com/photos/fastboy/1471413413/in/set-72157601853999996/"></p>

<p>I wonder how many people are out there who wish you would not use the anniversary of their loss to be patriotic. To repeat trite adages. To hashtag where you were when they lost the person that was most important to them. To make their loss about the flag and about terrorists and about yourself.</p>

<p>You extract meaning from their pain. You think the event is important to you. But this moment means nothing to you compared to them.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s possible they would just like to spend a moment in mourning and then move on.</p>

<p><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_1"><a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/07%20The%20Way%20The%20Wind%20Blows.mp3">Rush &ndash; The Way the Wind Blows</a></span></span></p>

<p class="date">September 11, 2011</p>




<script type="text/javascript">  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/07%20The%20Way%20The%20Wind%20Blows.mp3",  
        titles: "The Way the Wind Blows",  
        artists: "Rush"});
  });
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Three Day Weekend (Day Three)</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/06/three-day-weekend-day-three.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/06/three-day-weekend-day-three.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>...cycling for me is about swinging your leg over that bloody bike and pedaling, and leaving all that bullshit behind....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://cl.ly/1f2m3D272t422Q3T3S3N/Screen_shot_2011-09-06_at_10.17.05_PM.png" title="you totally can't really tell from this google street view shot, but trust me, it's kind of epic"></p>

<blockquote>...cycling for me is about swinging your leg over that bloody bike and pedaling, and leaving all that bullshit behind.</blockquote>


<p>Day three of the three day weekend I went on a 60 mile ride, deep into the country of south Dallas. I fell over just trying to exit the driveway, one of those humiliating slow tip-overs; this one, I think, due to very inattentively allowing my front wheel to fall in the crack between my driveway and my lawn. Despite no visible damage, my bike noisily protested for the rest of the ride. (Today, after a little caressing, she was silent once again.)</p>

<p>Despite the beautiful temperature, which had dropped another 10 degrees from the day prior (for those counting that makes for a 80-something high instead of a 100-something high), I should have taken this as an omen. Not a ride-ending omen, mind you, just a sign of things to come.</p>

<p>The route I had <a href="http://g.co/maps/a8ep">planned</a> involved some serious south Dallas country roads. I was not unaware of what that might mean. What it did mean was a mile-long section of not-originally-a-dirt-road-but-now-pretty-much-a-dirt-road. Some additional sections of road that were well on their way to similar status. Lots of dogs; fortunately, unlike <a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/07/28/vacation.html">in Oklahoma</a>, most behind fences. There were two dogs, both discovered in the middle of the road, both very sad, clearly homeless dogs. One was even a tiny little dog, the kind an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uptown_Dallas">uptown</a> girl might own. Except this was about 20 miles from uptown. Then there was riding through what I was convinced the most run-down country spot in town only to ride upon a <a href="http://g.co/maps/pbxbk">brand new elementary school</a> (too new for street view, apparently).</p>

<p>Then there was the wind. The wind I should not have complained about <a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/04/three-day-weekend.html">the day prior</a>. Because with the 10 fewer degrees came an additional 10 mph worth of north wind. And my route had a 20+ mile mostly due-north return section.</p>

<p>Ouchypoo.</p>

<p>Oh, and then I got a flat tire on my twice-ridden new front tire, right downtown, just a few miles from the end of the ride.</p>

<p>I went on that day to eat well north of 2000 calories and sleep for 13 hours.</p>

<hr>


<p>I&rsquo;m still a little sore a day later, but I did manage a very short recovery ride and my legs feel both wrecked and more strongly willed at the same time. A hard thing to describe if you haven&rsquo;t done endurance sports before.</p>

<p>Right towards the end of the ride today, right as I was riding through one of <a href="http://g.co/maps/g9w5w">my favorite spots</a> in fact, someone was headed the opposite direction, walking their one year old baby girl. She sat up in her stroller and either sneezed or made a scrunchy face at me. It was really cute and really heartbreaking.</p>

<p>Riding is very much about the above quote for me. About the rhythm, solitude, and meditative qualities of moving at speed under one&rsquo;s own power. But it sure is easy to break that rhythm, little girl.</p>

<p class="date">September 06, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">Quote from <a href="http://www.flammecast.com/what-are-you.html">here</a>.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Three Day Weekend</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/04/three-day-weekend.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/04/three-day-weekend.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>My first weekend off since July and not only is a three day weekend but the temperature just dropped by...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/17/19409792_1ecef67472_o.jpg" title="photo by Salim http://www.flickr.com/photos/salim/19409792/"></p>

<p>My first weekend off since July and not only is a three day weekend but the temperature just dropped by about 10 degrees. This morning on my traditional Sunday morning group ride we were all obviously stunned by the sudden feeling of not <em>immediately</em> suffering prior to any pedal rotations. I felt great and after a relative conquering of the hill loop the smooth (<em>super</em> rare in Dallas), flat road ahead inspired me and I had quite a fun time charging down the road at high speed. It was not lost on me at the time that I had a tailwind (a North tailwind, another rarity) &hellip;I just didn&rsquo;t realize that it was a <em>20+ mph tailwind</em> and that upon turning northward, my previous efforts would be rewarded with what might be considered a 17.5 mile climb back home. Fortunately I had a friend to draft off of for some of those miles but I still started cramping about halfway back. Now I&rsquo;m in emergency recovery mode because tomorrow, when the temperature is supposed to drop again, I have every intention to do it all over again.</p>

<hr>


<p>The real problem with a three day weekend is that everyone else has tomorrow off as well, so I can&rsquo;t use the day to catch up on the <em>pile</em> of errands I&rsquo;ve been accumulating all month.</p>

<p>The fact that I&rsquo;m too tired to do much of anything notwithstanding.</p>

<hr>


<p><a href="http://www.fastboycycles.com/teachingcancertocry/?p=710">Thoughts with fast boy</a>.</p>

<hr>


<p>I just noticed that this blog has been around for a year. Fitting that I&rsquo;m getting ready to shutter it.</p>

<p class="date">September 04, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">&amp;ldquo;How am I supposed to heal if I can&amp;rsquo;t feel time?&amp;rdquo;</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/25/how-am-i-supposed-to-heal.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/25/how-am-i-supposed-to-heal.html</id>
    <updated>2011-08-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I have to believe in a world outside my own mind. I have to believe that my actions still have...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<div class="media"><iframe width="420" height="345" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/AzUHCc5Vvk0?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>


<blockquote><p>I have to believe in a world outside my own mind. I have to believe that my actions still have meaning&hellip;</p></blockquote>

<p class="date">August 25, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">Narrative (and art) are beginning to find their way back into my life...this feels important...it is as if as long as we can still construct stories, even thought there is still no meaning, there is at least hope for meaning.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Heat, The Heat, The Heat</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/18/the-heat.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/18/the-heat.html</id>
    <updated>2011-08-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>It would seem the heat is driving everyone insane. For a while we were kept excited about breaking the 100...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_1"></span></span></p>


<p><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2552/5856352593_c8e72e7c74.jpg" title="Photo by NASA http://www.flickr.com/photos/gsfc/5856352593/"></p>

<p>It would seem the heat is driving everyone insane. For a while we were kept excited about breaking the 100 degree consecutive-day record. Then we had one 98 degree day and fell short by a few days. The worst thing you can offer a hopeless society is a short moment of hope. It then returned to 100+ degree temps and we all just got quiet and stopped discussing it and all started acting a little insane. Our driving skills diminished. Our irritability increased. Our general sense of hope and well being decreased&hellip;</p>

<blockquote><p>It&rsquo;s summertime and I can understand if you still feel sad.</p></blockquote>

<p><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6191/6057668732_1b91564a6d.jpg"></p>

<p class="date">August 18, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">...my work load increased, my riding time decreased, the anniversary passed...and I got stuck in survival mode.</p>




<script type="text/javascript">  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", 
      {
        soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/Summertime.mp3",  
        titles: "It's Summertime",  
        artists: "The Flaming Lips"});
  });
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
