<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>danielsjourney</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml" />
  <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2011-09-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>loss</subtitle>

  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">&amp;#8220;le fini d&amp;eacute;fini par le non fini&amp;#8221;</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/25/le-fini.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/25/le-fini.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>In 1965, in his studio in Warsaw, Opa&#x142;ka began painting a process of counting &#x2013; from one to infinity. Starting...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/RomanOpalka2.jpg" title="Roman Opalka"></p>

<blockquote><p>In 1965, in his studio in Warsaw, Opa&#x142;ka began painting a process of counting &#x2013; from one to infinity. Starting in the top left-hand corner of the canvas and finishing in the bottom right-hand corner, the tiny numbers were painted in horizontal rows. Each new canvas, which the artist called a &lsquo;detail&rsquo;, took up counting where the last left off. Each &lsquo;detail&rsquo; is the same size (196 x 135 cm), the dimension of his studio door in Warsaw. All details have the same title, &ldquo;1965 / 1 &#x2013; &infin;&rdquo;; the concept had no end, and the artist pledged his life to its execution: &lsquo;All my work is a single thing, the description from number one to infinity. A single thing, a single life.&rsquo;</p>

<p>The final number he wrote was 5,607,249</p></blockquote>

<p class="postscript">Via the internet via <a href="http://mlkshk.com/p/7NH7">ftrain</a>. Text from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roman_Opa%C5%82ka">wikipedia</a>. Image from <a href="http://opalka1965.com/en/index_en.php">the official website</a>.

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Where can we go to feel?</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/21/where-can-we-go.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/21/where-can-we-go.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Wheeler Sparks: . . .to swallow ground by bus and train and foot and still only just reach the crest of the...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2558/3703829924_8800c4e88f.jpg" title="http://www.flickr.com/photos/37324043@N00/3703829924/ road blocks in Siberia by Copper Kettle"></p>

<p><a href="http://wheelersparks.com/2011/09/a-note-from-author-john-graves/">Wheeler Sparks</a>:</p>

<br><br>


<blockquote><p>&hellip;to swallow ground by bus and train and foot and still only just reach the crest of the wave where everyone else is headed soon, of course there is a sadness there. A fading sense of discovery. Where can we go to feel we have truly explored?</p></blockquote>

<p>Time is marching on as it tends to do. Bad days are less frequent and more vague in their symptoms (yet today is one). I feel like so much of what I&rsquo;ve written about here is about running away from <em>then</em> either into the distant past or into some more present present, like exploring geographic and emotional territories on my bicycle (actually the bicycle is the perfect combination of nostalgia and forward movement). Oh, and drinking. To some extent I&rsquo;ve allowed myself all of this due to the simple fact that the pain of thinking about Margot&mdash;even typing her name&mdash;is so horrible, so vast, so overwhelming that I&rsquo;ve had no choice but avoid it or be consumed by it.</p>

<p>But it calls like a distant wind. The trees rustle on the periphery and there is no stopping that invisible force, it will soon be on your face. And while it is sometimes a touch, this is Texas and it is usually a punch.</p>

<p>It seems that for her, and for her sister&rsquo;s sake, I will need to turn and face it. I just wish I knew what that meant.</p>

<p class="date">September 21, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Why Do I Exist?</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/14/whats-for-lunch.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/14/whats-for-lunch.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>
</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/why-do-i-exist1.jpg" title="from here http://www.heylamington.com/archives/70"></p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Into My Arms</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/13/into-my-arms.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/13/into-my-arms.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>

</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<div class="media"><iframe width="480" height="390" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/73UXRl_ILZ0?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Peace</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/11/peace.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/11/peace.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I wonder how many people are out there who wish you would not use the anniversary of their loss to...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1169/1471413413_f0b8f52760.jpg" title="'island' by fastboy http://www.flickr.com/photos/fastboy/1471413413/in/set-72157601853999996/"></p>

<p>I wonder how many people are out there who wish you would not use the anniversary of their loss to be patriotic. To repeat trite adages. To hashtag where you were when they lost the person that was most important to them. To make their loss about the flag and about terrorists and about yourself.</p>

<p>You extract meaning from their pain. You think the event is important to you. But this moment means nothing to you compared to them.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s possible they would just like to spend a moment in mourning and then move on.</p>

<p><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_1"><a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/07%20The%20Way%20The%20Wind%20Blows.mp3">Rush &ndash; The Way the Wind Blows</a></span></span></p>

<p class="date">September 11, 2011</p>




<script type="text/javascript">  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/07%20The%20Way%20The%20Wind%20Blows.mp3",  
        titles: "The Way the Wind Blows",  
        artists: "Rush"});
  });
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Three Day Weekend (Day Three)</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/06/three-day-weekend-day-three.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/06/three-day-weekend-day-three.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>...cycling for me is about swinging your leg over that bloody bike and pedaling, and leaving all that bullshit behind....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://cl.ly/1f2m3D272t422Q3T3S3N/Screen_shot_2011-09-06_at_10.17.05_PM.png" title="you totally can't really tell from this google street view shot, but trust me, it's kind of epic"></p>

<blockquote>...cycling for me is about swinging your leg over that bloody bike and pedaling, and leaving all that bullshit behind.</blockquote>


<p>Day three of the three day weekend I went on a 60 mile ride, deep into the country of south Dallas. I fell over just trying to exit the driveway, one of those humiliating slow tip-overs; this one, I think, due to very inattentively allowing my front wheel to fall in the crack between my driveway and my lawn. Despite no visible damage, my bike noisily protested for the rest of the ride. (Today, after a little caressing, she was silent once again.)</p>

<p>Despite the beautiful temperature, which had dropped another 10 degrees from the day prior (for those counting that makes for a 80-something high instead of a 100-something high), I should have taken this as an omen. Not a ride-ending omen, mind you, just a sign of things to come.</p>

<p>The route I had <a href="http://g.co/maps/a8ep">planned</a> involved some serious south Dallas country roads. I was not unaware of what that might mean. What it did mean was a mile-long section of not-originally-a-dirt-road-but-now-pretty-much-a-dirt-road. Some additional sections of road that were well on their way to similar status. Lots of dogs; fortunately, unlike <a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/07/28/vacation.html">in Oklahoma</a>, most behind fences. There were two dogs, both discovered in the middle of the road, both very sad, clearly homeless dogs. One was even a tiny little dog, the kind an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uptown_Dallas">uptown</a> girl might own. Except this was about 20 miles from uptown. Then there was riding through what I was convinced the most run-down country spot in town only to ride upon a <a href="http://g.co/maps/pbxbk">brand new elementary school</a> (too new for street view, apparently).</p>

<p>Then there was the wind. The wind I should not have complained about <a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/04/three-day-weekend.html">the day prior</a>. Because with the 10 fewer degrees came an additional 10 mph worth of north wind. And my route had a 20+ mile mostly due-north return section.</p>

<p>Ouchypoo.</p>

<p>Oh, and then I got a flat tire on my twice-ridden new front tire, right downtown, just a few miles from the end of the ride.</p>

<p>I went on that day to eat well north of 2000 calories and sleep for 13 hours.</p>

<hr>


<p>I&rsquo;m still a little sore a day later, but I did manage a very short recovery ride and my legs feel both wrecked and more strongly willed at the same time. A hard thing to describe if you haven&rsquo;t done endurance sports before.</p>

<p>Right towards the end of the ride today, right as I was riding through one of <a href="http://g.co/maps/g9w5w">my favorite spots</a> in fact, someone was headed the opposite direction, walking their one year old baby girl. She sat up in her stroller and either sneezed or made a scrunchy face at me. It was really cute and really heartbreaking.</p>

<p>Riding is very much about the above quote for me. About the rhythm, solitude, and meditative qualities of moving at speed under one&rsquo;s own power. But it sure is easy to break that rhythm, little girl.</p>

<p class="date">September 06, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">Quote from <a href="http://www.flammecast.com/what-are-you.html">here</a>.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Three Day Weekend</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/04/three-day-weekend.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/04/three-day-weekend.html</id>
    <updated>2011-09-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>My first weekend off since July and not only is a three day weekend but the temperature just dropped by...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/17/19409792_1ecef67472_o.jpg" title="photo by Salim http://www.flickr.com/photos/salim/19409792/"></p>

<p>My first weekend off since July and not only is a three day weekend but the temperature just dropped by about 10 degrees. This morning on my traditional Sunday morning group ride we were all obviously stunned by the sudden feeling of not <em>immediately</em> suffering prior to any pedal rotations. I felt great and after a relative conquering of the hill loop the smooth (<em>super</em> rare in Dallas), flat road ahead inspired me and I had quite a fun time charging down the road at high speed. It was not lost on me at the time that I had a tailwind (a North tailwind, another rarity) &hellip;I just didn&rsquo;t realize that it was a <em>20+ mph tailwind</em> and that upon turning northward, my previous efforts would be rewarded with what might be considered a 17.5 mile climb back home. Fortunately I had a friend to draft off of for some of those miles but I still started cramping about halfway back. Now I&rsquo;m in emergency recovery mode because tomorrow, when the temperature is supposed to drop again, I have every intention to do it all over again.</p>

<hr>


<p>The real problem with a three day weekend is that everyone else has tomorrow off as well, so I can&rsquo;t use the day to catch up on the <em>pile</em> of errands I&rsquo;ve been accumulating all month.</p>

<p>The fact that I&rsquo;m too tired to do much of anything notwithstanding.</p>

<hr>


<p><a href="http://www.fastboycycles.com/teachingcancertocry/?p=710">Thoughts with fast boy</a>.</p>

<hr>


<p>I just noticed that this blog has been around for a year. Fitting that I&rsquo;m getting ready to shutter it.</p>

<p class="date">September 04, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">&amp;ldquo;How am I supposed to heal if I can&amp;rsquo;t feel time?&amp;rdquo;</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/25/how-am-i-supposed-to-heal.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/25/how-am-i-supposed-to-heal.html</id>
    <updated>2011-08-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I have to believe in a world outside my own mind. I have to believe that my actions still have...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<div class="media"><iframe width="420" height="345" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/AzUHCc5Vvk0?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>


<blockquote><p>I have to believe in a world outside my own mind. I have to believe that my actions still have meaning&hellip;</p></blockquote>

<p class="date">August 25, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">Narrative (and art) are beginning to find their way back into my life...this feels important...it is as if as long as we can still construct stories, even thought there is still no meaning, there is at least hope for meaning.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Heat, The Heat, The Heat</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/18/the-heat.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/18/the-heat.html</id>
    <updated>2011-08-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>It would seem the heat is driving everyone insane. For a while we were kept excited about breaking the 100...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_1"></span></span></p>


<p><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2552/5856352593_c8e72e7c74.jpg" title="Photo by NASA http://www.flickr.com/photos/gsfc/5856352593/"></p>

<p>It would seem the heat is driving everyone insane. For a while we were kept excited about breaking the 100 degree consecutive-day record. Then we had one 98 degree day and fell short by a few days. The worst thing you can offer a hopeless society is a short moment of hope. It then returned to 100+ degree temps and we all just got quiet and stopped discussing it and all started acting a little insane. Our driving skills diminished. Our irritability increased. Our general sense of hope and well being decreased&hellip;</p>

<blockquote><p>It&rsquo;s summertime and I can understand if you still feel sad.</p></blockquote>

<p><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6191/6057668732_1b91564a6d.jpg"></p>

<p class="date">August 18, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">...my work load increased, my riding time decreased, the anniversary passed...and I got stuck in survival mode.</p>




<script type="text/javascript">  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", 
      {
        soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/Summertime.mp3",  
        titles: "It's Summertime",  
        artists: "The Flaming Lips"});
  });
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">New Year</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/14/new-year.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/14/new-year.html</id>
    <updated>2011-08-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>And so a new morning arrived. And I rode 55 miles, in the company of people I enjoy, 40 of...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2026/2350547629_5c87aa4065.jpg" title="Photo by Ed Lisieski http://www.flickr.com/photos/redredbuttons/2350547629/"></p>

<p>And so a new morning arrived. And I rode 55 miles, in the company of people I enjoy, <a href="http://www.endomondo.com/workouts/mVQYeo7T-tg">40 of which were on roads I&rsquo;d never seen before</a> and were rather nice for cycling. Some of them even reminded me of the roads I grew up riding on in PA. It was the perfect way to start a new year.</p>

<hr>


<p>At first I thought Lucy&rsquo;s conception would change something. Then the year mark. Of course things never work that way. This will stay with me forever. How I live within it changes. I wish I could be to the place where I could see her pictures. I didn&rsquo;t expect to yet be to the place where I could watch video or listen to the audio I&rsquo;d captured of her talking and singing. But I had hoped to be able to see her beautiful, perfect face, not fear seeing it for risk of losing my shit.</p>

<hr>


<p>I had more to say but have run out of time multiple times. Thank you all for your well-portioned reaching-outs yesterday. So for now, a small mix.</p>

<p class="media"><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_1"></span></span></p>


<p>(<a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/NewYear/">Here is the directory with all the tunes, for your time-shifted enjoyment</a>. There is one bonus track in there, not included in the player because there is a reader of this blog for whom it would be too difficult to hear.)</p>

<p class="date">August 14, 2011</p>




<script type="text/javascript">  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", 
      {
        soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/NewYear/03%20Don't%20Stop%20Believing.mp3, http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/NewYear/01%20New%20Years%20Day.mp3, http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/NewYear/01%20So%20am%20I.mp3, http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/NewYear/01%20Faithfully.mp3",  
        titles: "Don't Stop Believing, New Years Day, So Am I, Faithfully",  
        artists: "Clem Snide, Andy Zipf, Andy Zipf, Clem Snide"});
  });
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">One Year</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/13/one-year.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/13/one-year.html</id>
    <updated>2011-08-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>

365 days ago, my daughter, my only child, died.

August 13, 2011

</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3278/3052763269_ec3cdc70b9.jpg" title="Photo by Ed Lisieski http://www.flickr.com/photos/redredbuttons/3052763269/"></p>

<p>365 days ago, my daughter, my only child, died.</p>

<p class="date">August 13, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">New Day</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/11/new-day.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/11/new-day.html</id>
    <updated>2011-08-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Yesterday improved. My meeting went really well and then I took the opportunity to visit my new friend Gerhard in...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://mlkshk.com/r/60D0" title="# http://mlkshk.com/p/60D0"></p>

<p>Yesterday improved. My meeting went really well and then I took the opportunity to visit my new friend Gerhard in <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=Roanoke,+tx">Roanoke</a>. Gerhard is the person I vaguely mentioned <a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/03/get-over-yourself.html">in the footnote of this post</a> and the story is long and important and I don&rsquo;t want to do it injustice so I&rsquo;m not going to attempt to tell it right now.</p>

<p>Had a cigar, talked about life, <a href="http://mlkshk.com/p/5ZM5">ate too much</a>, drank delicious German beer. Soul restorage.</p>

<p class="date">August 11, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">This Day</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/10/this-day.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/10/this-day.html</id>
    <updated>2011-08-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>This morning I had to get up and get downtown to appear in court for a ticket I got while...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6124/6014958642_e9e0aca1a6.jpg" title="http://www.flickr.com/photos/beth19/6014958642 photo by Bethan"></p>

<p>This morning I had to get up and get downtown to appear in court for a ticket I got while riding my bike around White Rock Lake. The Dallas Police enjoy hiding out near the stop signs on the roads cyclist frequent, especially on the weekend when they know they will be able to pick off rider after rider rolling through stop signs. Fortunately my case was dismissed.</p>

<p>365 days ago I woke up from the first of a number of nights sleeping in the ICU.</p>

<p>Today I&rsquo;m just trying to find some focus. I have client meetings today and tomorrow. I have two huge deliverables in the next five days. I&rsquo;ve only ridden my bike twice in the last five days.</p>

<p>But it&rsquo;s hard.</p>

<p class="date">August 10, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Before/After</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/04/before-after.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/04/before-after.html</id>
    <updated>2011-08-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>The Chemistry Set - Love (Dance on the one that brought you) I used to define my life in terms...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_1"><a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/ChemSet/05%20Love%20(Dance%20on%20the%20one%20that%20brought%20you).mp3">The Chemistry Set - Love (Dance on the one that brought you)</a></span></span></p>


<p>I used to define my life in terms of before and after certain relationships. But the one that lasted from 2009 to 2010 has trumped everything and defined my life into a binary before/after that makes all others simply lumped into one amorphous before.</p>

<p><a name="a"></a>But that time from <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FJXiL-DPxbE">late 2007</a> to 2010 was a magical journey through love and contentment and family and fatherhood that I will always cherish&mdash;and I hope to be able to return to those emotions again. {<a href="#foot_a" class="foot">1</a>}</p>

<p><a name="b"></a>Part of that time period involved <a href="http://dealingwith.wordpress.com/2008/01/12/many-thoughts-after-my-show-and-the-chemistry-set-show-last-night/">going</a> to <a href="http://tinyurl.com/3kfr956">Chemistry Set</a> shows with Carissa. Yesterday I mentioned my favorite song of all time, <em>Wake Me</em> by Tom Conlon. But I might have to rate the Chemistry Set as my favorite band of all time. {<a href="#foot_b" class="foot">2</a>} &hellip;If you weren&rsquo;t following the Dallas music scene in the first decade of this century you probably never heard of the Chemistry set. But I suggest you go grab both{<a href="#foot_c" class="foot">3</a>} their records while you still can. They disbanded a few years ago.</p>

<p><a name="c"></a>Anyway. Listening to their music still makes me feel better. I miss them terribly. Carissa shot their drummer&rsquo;s wedding and we&rsquo;re still friends with them{<a href="#foot_d" class="foot">4</a>} (sadly they&rsquo;re in Fort Worth which might as well be California). We never knew any of the other band members although I think we both had a crush on Stephen Duncan.</p>

<p class="date">August 03, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript"><a name="foot_a">1</a> Obviously I feel them still. I guess I mean to be immersed in them in such a way as to be more fully engulfed in the moment and reality of current joy as opposed to allowing everything to be tainted by past loss. {<a href="#a" class="foot">back</a>}<br>
<br>
<a name="foot_b">2</a> It is my personal opinion that one should choose &ldquo;all time&rdquo; rankings based on one&rsquo;s own experience as well as allow the rankings to be as flexible as a moment&rsquo;s inspiration. Otherwise everyone&rsquo;s all time band would just be The Beatles and there would be nothing else interesting to talk about. {<a href="#b" class="foot">back</a>}<br>
<br>
<a name="foot_c">3</a> Here is <a href="http://www.cdbaby.com/cd/chemistryset2">Blue Monsters</a>. Good luck finding their debut. If you contact me I will probably hook you up, though. {<a href="#b" class="foot">back</a>}<br>
<br>
<a name="foot_d">4</a> See <a href="https://twitter.com/jawsgirly">jawsgirly</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/jawshoeuh">jawshoeuh</a> {<a href="#c" class="foot">back</a>}</p>




<script type="text/javascript">  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/ChemSet/01%20New%20Hope%20PA.mp3,http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/ChemSet/05%20Love%20(Dance%20on%20the%20one%20that%20brought%20you).mp3,http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/ChemSet/08%20Pilot%20kiss%20my%20karma.mp3,http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/ChemSet/09%20T-rex%20devours%20the%20glitteratti.mp3",  
        titles: "New Hope PA,Love (Dance on the one that brought you),Pilot kiss my karma,T-rex devours the glitteratti",  
        artists: "The Chemistry Set"});
  });
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Get Over Yourself</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/03/get-over-yourself.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/03/get-over-yourself.html</id>
    <updated>2011-08-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Tom Conlon - Wake Me Some days I feel like I need a shirt that says: "I lost my daughter....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_1"><a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/11%20Wake%20Me.mp3">Tom Conlon - Wake Me</a></span></span></p>


<p>Some days I feel like I need a shirt that says: &ldquo;I lost my daughter. Get over yourself.&rdquo;</p>

<hr>


<p>Today was a bad day. It&rsquo;s a bad month to have a bad month if you know what I mean. The constant effing heat (30-some days over 100 degrees and no end in sight) combined with a ridiculous workload mean very little riding or time for sanity resets (of which riding was my primary).</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still having to deal with the cemetery because Margot&rsquo;s headstone is still not done. My handler there is very nice but emails have failed to transfer for whatever reasons and it takes me weeks to return normal phone calls yet alone these. The font I originally chose (Helvetica) was too big to fit even though we chose no additional text. Today I just went by there because I was nearby and knew that was going to be the quickest way to keep this god damned process moving forward. They had at least given me two options that were the closest and would fit. I picked something-gothic.</p>

<p>It was a quick stop but I still found myself wrecked afterward&mdash;and headed to work. This song by my friend Tom Conlon left me sobbing as I drove down <a href="http://tinyurl.com/3rnm3sb">I75</a>. Don&rsquo;t get me wrong, it is probably my favorite song of all time. But the longing it conveys is so much more intense now. That this current life is but a dream that leads to the reality of the next should be some comfort to me* &hellip;Her wait for me is like a day. My wait is my lifetime.</p>

<p>A lifetime of longing. The emotions all came to the front. It happens in the car so much more frequently than anywhere else.</p>

<hr>


<p>Then on the way home from work I stopped by Whole Foods for Necessary Supplies (for Frito-pie and <a href="http://www.deschutesbrewery.com/brew/inversion-ipa">sanity</a>) and for whatever reason it was filled with beautiful 1-2 year old girls. One right at the entrance who was obviously as full of wonder and joy at life as Margot was. Another played with the offerings in the open chiller in the first isle. Your boys aren&rsquo;t much trouble, your newborns even I can handle. But your 1 year old girls punch me in the chest, penetrate my ribcage and squeeze my heart until it bruises.</p>

<p class="date">July 27, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">* maaan I have an entire post about this subject and a man I met about a month ago who was like a prophet to me. So far it has been too much to try and process in written words.

<script type="text/javascript">  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/11%20Wake%20Me.mp3",  
        titles: "Wake Me",  
        artists: "Tom Conlon"});
  });
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
