<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>danielsjourney</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml" />
  <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2011-02-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>loss</subtitle>

  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">What Now?</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/24/what-now.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/24/what-now.html</id>
    <updated>2011-02-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>There are many obvious questions in my situation, most of which cycle through my mind like a ferris wheel, each...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='I keep banging my head against the bottom of this question but nothing ever comes popping out of the top. Photo by Bob Prosser http://www.flickr.com/photos/44986108@N00/5032931614/' src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4129/5032931614_a60572eaf6_z.jpg' />
<p>There are many obvious questions in my situation, most of which cycle through my mind like a ferris wheel, each taking their turn stopped in the loading and unloading area. <em>Why?</em> is one <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/09/05/why.html'>I&#8217;ve mentioned before</a>; I have to some extent decided that question is best escorted out of the park by security. <em>What now?</em> however, that one has made a couple trips around now. I wonder if when that one has left the ride if maybe the ride won&#8217;t stop going around for a while. That would be nice.</p>

<p>On one hand, so many things haven&#8217;t changed. My personality hasn&#8217;t changed that much&#8211;at least not that I can tell. I&#8217;m not more patient or kind or understanding. I&#8217;m not significantly less vain. I&#8217;m not more or less secure.</p>

<p>Some things have changed for the worse. There are now a thousand triggers that might make something in my brain misfire. I care less about what other people think. I drop the f-bomb with more frequency and drink more than I used to&#8230;and I was pretty bad on both counts already.</p>

<p>One thing that <em>might</em> have changed for the better is, in the words Jim Uhls added to <em>Fight Club</em>, the ability to let that which does not matter truly slide.</p>

<p>So what now? There is never any way but forward. Life is shit and life is sweet. We all know that. You just don&#8217;t know how sweet yours is.*</p>

<p><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/33602849@N00/63732753/'><img src='http://farm1.static.flickr.com/29/63732753_ac69ceb2d2.jpg' alt='Question mark bomb image by niznoz' /></a></p>
<p class='date'>February 24, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>*Ha ha. No. You really don't.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">When in Doubt, Ride Hard</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/20/ride.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/20/ride.html</id>
    <updated>2011-02-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Today I rode for the 5th day in a row. It probably would have been 10 days except for last...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='http://www.flickr.com/photos/silverfingers/2462014101/in/faves-dealingwith/ Photo by Hans Hamburger' src='http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2384/2462014101_8fed19efb6.jpg' />
<p>Today I rode for the 5th day in a row. It probably would have been 10 days except for last Monday and Tuesday off due to two separate TMI ailments. And I must have really &#8220;misunderestimated&#8221; the previous four days because today kicked my ass in the best way possible.</p>

<p>Sunday mornings I&#8217;ve acquired the habit of riding with the group out of <a href='http://ocbicycleco.com/'>Oak Cliff Bicycle Company</a>, probably the only non-pretentious shop or group ride in town. But it&#8217;s <em>hilly</em> and pretty <em>fast</em> and is a great way to take the legs to their limit especially if, like I did today, you&#8217;ve left yourself with not-really-enough left in your legs for such a ride.</p>

<p>So I&#8217;ve had the odd pleasure of existing for the rest of my day in an odd haze and <a href='http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=5102364950'>as Phil Liggett would say</a> &#8220;legs [that] have turned to rubber&#8221;.</p>
<hr />
<p>I&#8217;ve wanted a couple of times to re-post about <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/24/fast-boy.html'>Fast Boy</a>. His blog and our occasional email correspondence have been a great encouragement to me. Although our pain is very different it is similar in its mere existence. He travels through his with an aplomb that is well summed up with this excerpt from <a href='http://www.fastboycycles.com/teachingcancertocry/?p=601'>his latest post</a>. It is also such an eloquent description of the dichotomy that is the pain-addled life:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>I hate this pattern of bringing you ever more pitiful news. I sometimes hesitate to write at all, and yet the point is to document this bloody process.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>Meanwhile, strangely, I find that I am ever more aware of just how much I love my life. My mind is going at warp speed with ideas.. I&#8217;m excited about getting back to building bikes, but also about lots of other things. I love making these food videos! I&#8217;ve got some music video work coming up that&#8217;s awfully exciting. There are things that I want to write, pieces of hardware that I want to design. Places I want to go.. and yet I&#8217;m falling asleep writing this entry. I&#8217;m beat. I&#8217;m tired. I hurt. It is unbelievably frustrating.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>Tonight I will make fish cakes.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr /><p class='date'>February 20, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Winter's Over?</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/19/winter.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/19/winter.html</id>
    <updated>2011-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Six months and six days. That&#8217;s how long it&#8217;s been. The six month mark passed without event, in fact even...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='http://www.flickr.com/photos/movito/5361359983/ photo by Fredrik Matheson, who I wish I knew in real life.' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5086/5361359983_6cba68a10c.jpg' />
<p>Six months and six days. That&#8217;s how long it&#8217;s been. The six month mark passed without event, in fact even the 14th was pretty good, we even had a <a href='https://www.facebook.com/pages/Wheeler-Sparks/334053513499'>rock star dinner guest</a>. Tuesday it all fell apart. Wednesday was back to just ok. And so it goes. Now it&#8217;s already Saturday in a WTF kind of speed.</p>

<p>The temperatures have risen to the 80&#8217;s and even though ride preparation takes a few fewer seconds and there&#8217;s less nose blowing during rides*, it feels far, far too soon. Winters are a quiet kind of sad and still. In a way that was helpful. My soul&#8217;s not renewing, so why should the Earth? Anyway, seems all it means is bugs and sweat and wind.</p>

<p>I want to give some kind of meaningful update or information, but everything I&#8217;ve already said still holds true. <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/09/02/in-order-to-remember-we-must-first-forget.html'>Being reminded of her, or the event, or the loss&#8230;any reminders still must be avoided</a>, the pain is still so debilitating. <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/09/29/motivation-mood.html'>Motivation is still elusive</a>. <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/26/dislikes.html'>Your shit is still really fucking petty</a> and I still really don&#8217;t want to see your babies.</p>

<p>It still seems like I&#8217;m just beating off depression and pain and (honest) sadness and resentment like it&#8217;s my full time job. I just want my daughter back. I just want to be a daddy again. I just want my life back.</p>
<p class='date'>February 19, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>* There are also a lot more people out riding around the lake, which is so annoying.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Super Bowl</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/07/super-bowl.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/07/super-bowl.html</id>
    <updated>2011-02-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I wonder where I fit in the scheme of things. Especially while I am out riding my bike&#8230;which I do...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by Arnoooo http://www.flickr.com/photos/studiobeeldruis/2636723848/' src='http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3258/2636723848_4b3c9474e0.jpg' />
<blockquote>
<p>I wonder where I fit in the scheme of things. Especially while I am out riding my bike&#8230;which I do almost like a religion nowadays. Compelled somehow, but wrapped in a fear and a certainty that this is a fool&#8217;s paradise. I am visited day and night with memories, and no good ones, reenactments of days of pain long passed by.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>There may never be another super bowl for me. But death calls out, and life refuses to hear. <strong>It is all wasted on thirty second commercials, selling things no living man has any need of, only dead men spend their money so stupidly.</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>&#8211; <a href='http://www.alexigrewal.com/index.php/blog/122-super-bowl'>Alexi Grewal</a></p>
<hr />
<blockquote>
<p>Two weeks ago, Grewal took part in Wheat Ridge Cyclery&#8217;s Crooked Roubaix, his first competitive event since his retirement. Despite riding a mountain bike, flat pedals and hiking boots, Grewal finished the 90-mile gran fondo-style high-altitude event on dirt and paved roads in the leading group, crossing the line in fourth place out of a field of some 125 starters.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>&#8211; <a href='http://velonews.competitor.com/2010/09/news/inside-cycling-with-john-wilcockson-alexi-grewal-is-deadly-serious-about-comeback_142905'>Alexi Grewal comeback</a></p>
<hr />
<p>I had a long post composed in my mind about how last night&#8217;s spectacle made me lose all hope for humanity, as <a href='http://www.google.com/search?q=groupon+super+bowl+commercial' title='and that was only one example of many'>the commercials proved we  no longer have any compassion for our fellow man</a> and the players (and I assume fans) credited God for their good plays. We believe He has an opinion on the matter of sports performance but not, apparently, on human suffering. I also have planned a long post about cycling and the dark cloud that currently looms over its greatest spectacles. I still might write the latter. In the meantime, I am happy to turn this post about the Super Bowl into a post about cycling.</p>
<hr />
<blockquote>
<p>Maybe this whole doping issue is here to turn us from our own selfishness to see that we have not as yet realized that the bicycle and bicycle racing has a purpose and meaning we have yet to even think about or care to understand. I think we are missing the real reality of what we have in the bicycle and in the racing of it.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>&#8211; <a href='http://velonews.competitor.com/2008/04/news/an-essay-by-1984-olympic-gold-medalist-alexi-grewal_74053'>Alexi Grewal</a> (again)</p>
<p class='date'>February 07, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">A Black Wave is Comin'</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/06/a-black-wave-is-comin.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/06/a-black-wave-is-comin.html</id>
    <updated>2011-02-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='212' width='499'><param name='allowfullscreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><param name='movie' value='http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=11287967&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=0&amp;show_byline=0&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1&amp;autoplay=0&amp;loop=0' /><embed src='http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=11287967&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=0&amp;show_byline=0&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1&amp;autoplay=0&amp;loop=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='212' width='499' /></object></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Snow</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/04/snow.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/04/snow.html</id>
    <updated>2011-02-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Most of you are living it as well, but after four snow days in a row, having gotten out once...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Carissa' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5259/5417115901_accbb186d9.jpg' alt='Carissa' />
<p>Most of you are living it as well, but after four snow days in a row, having gotten out once since Monday (and Monday I went on a mountain bike ride in regular shorts and jersey) and then only to get <a href='http://twitpic.com/3w60vp'>my tire fixed</a> and re-stock on milk and beer&#8230;well, I&#8217;m over it. I am normally a fan of colder weather but the bike being a rare refuge of late, Texans in general&#8211;and specifically civically&#8211;unprepared for such conditions and 7-year-olds being particularly prone to the more annoying strains of cabin fever have all taken their toll.</p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5060/5417115985_4ae612d9bd.jpg' alt='The fire' /></p>

<p>Last night when the snow started to fall about midnight I kind of resigned to it all. And today our good friend and neighbor Brix had another one of his famous impromptu front porch fetes. Standing by a fire with a beer and a cigar as big flakes continued to fall throughout the afternoon, it wasn&#8217;t so bad. The sun even came out. For about 15 minutes.</p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5220/5417116055_905384a83b.jpg' alt='Penn' /></p>

<p>Ringo, of course, <strong>loves</strong> it. He&#8217;s the Kenneth Parcell of our family.</p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5012/5417312822_ac8679dc22.jpg' alt='Ringo' /></p>

<p><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/sets/72157625852615671/'>Carissa&#8217;s pictures are here</a> in case you haven&#8217;t seen them already.</p>
<p class='date'>February 04, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>I miss her so much. I couldn't stop thinking about how much she would have loved the snow. How much better all this time stuck inside would have been, stuck inside with her.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">...</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/30/trudge.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/30/trudge.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>&#8230;could tell you about how my depression has been getting worse. How I have been considering chemical interventions for it....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object data='http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=2640512438/size=venti/bgcol=FFFFFF/linkcol=4285BB//' type='text/html' height='100' width='400'> </object></p>
<p>&#8230;could tell you about how my depression has been getting worse. How I have been considering chemical interventions for it. How I remembered how the last time I required anti-depressants it was quite a few months after an event I had to pretty much eradicate from my memory. How I&#8217;m riding my bicycle a whole lot these days trying to beat it off with naturally enhanced endorphins and serotonin and norepinephrine or whatever making yourself hurt on a bicycle does that makes you forget everything and occasionally overly verbose about not much in particular.</p>

<p>&#8230;could tell you about how my day job has come to an end and I&#8217;m trying to figure out what to do next. How I&#8217;m working on a new project that has blown past all attempts to deadline it. How I&#8217;m scared shitless to pursue that thing full time because I&#8217;m afraid it will be an abject failure. How I don&#8217;t know if I even want to work right now except that funds are down after the medical bills and the property taxes and the etc.</p>

<p>&#8230;could tell you about how I don&#8217;t know where that property tax bill went. How I don&#8217;t remember seeing it cross my desk. How hard it is to do normal shit these days.</p>

<p>&#8230;could tell you about how this morning on my drive to a morning group ride my trunk lid came loose and I had to pull over into a parking lot of an empty little office building on the I-30 service road just east of Grand. The same god damn parking lot that I pulled over into the day we were told she was probably not going to make it, and I couldn&#8217;t drive any more because I was losing my shit. And this morning I had to pull into that same parking lot because of my god damn trunk lid, and when I came to a stop instead of balling and balling and begging God and begging God I just cursed at him. I cursed at him like Cee Lo Green except without melody and with a lot more anger and bitterness.</p>

<p>&#8230;could tell you about how two people total have downloaded my last record in the 6 days since I released it and how that&#8217;s about 0.3% of my Twitter followers alone. And one of those people is my Mom, who isn&#8217;t on Twitter anyway.</p>

<p>&#8230;could tell you about what a fine cook my wife is and about the homemade veggie red curry she made tonight and the friends we had over and whose company we enjoyed.</p>

<p>&#8230;could tell you about the mean strangers on the internet who probably thought I wouldn&#8217;t read their comments about me and about this blog and about how <em>stupid</em> it was that I had <a href='http://www.ftrain.com/wwic.html'>not consulted</a> them about how best to grieve. <em>&#8220;What Daniel needs to do is&#8230;&#8221;</em></p>

<p>&#8230;could tell you about all the failed attempts my brain has made at creating some semblance of a tautology for this thing. How none of my experience or faith or culture has provided any tools for dealing with it. How they have only provided frameworks that crumble under its weight, pain for their attempts at grace, crumbling ruins for their attempts at meaning.</p>

<p>&#8230;but I don&#8217;t really feel like it.</p>
<p class='date'>January 30, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Reamericana</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/24/reamericana.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/24/reamericana.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>In 2003 I lived in Bosnia for a few months and while there recorded a little four-song EP, the Americana...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object data='http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3895428586/size=grande3/bgcol=FFFFFF/linkcol=4285BB//' type='text/html' height='410' width='300'> </object></p>
<p>In 2003 I lived in Bosnia for a few months and while there recorded a little four-song EP, the <em>Americana EP</em>. I was really proud of it, it was my first time working with a producer and it was my first project since 1997. I&#8217;ll have to &#8220;re-print&#8221; the epic story of the Bosnian disc reproduction <em>mofiasco</em> on here soon for those who haven&#8217;t already heard it.</p>

<p>After the first <em><a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/album/happy-sounding-sad-songs'>Happy Sounding Sad Songs</a></em> sessions I wasn&#8217;t quite happy with the collection. There were a few songs on it that sounded like they belonged more with the previous <em>Americana EP</em> than with the rest of their companions on <em>HSSS</em>. I tabled those three, recorded two new ones <em>(<a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/track/i-dont-know-what-to-do-about-that' title='I Don&apos;t Know What to do About That'>IDKWTDAT</a> &amp; <a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/track/clich]'>Clich&#233;</a>)</em>, and that was that.</p>

<p>I had it in my mind to re-work <em>Americana</em> since then. The original EP only used sampled drums and on a couple of the songs they sounded, well, sampled. I wanted real drums on those, combine them with the 3 stragglers from <em>HSSS</em>, ignore the fact that someone without a career has no place releasing a B-sides compilation, and whammo: new record.</p>

<p>Well it took a while to get around to re-working those old tracks. I had to find a studio that could import them. Then we discovered my producer back in Sarajevo had made a mistake with the backups, and I was missing most of one of the songs. We worked on the other three, adding new guitars and drums and some keys. We mixed more professionally. I mashed-up a little ending for <em>Closed</em> that harkens forward to the (now-past) remake of <a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/track/american-dream-town'><em>Dream Town</em> on <em>HSSS</em></a>. I ended up throwing out one more song.</p>

<p>Anyway, everything was ready to go last summer. Then some stuff happened.</p>

<p>Anyway, here it is.</p>

<p>Album notes:</p>

<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>American Dream Town</strong><br /><em>A song about secret societies, plastic surgery and other curious aspects of the American Dream.</em><br />Daniel Miller: acoustic guitar, vocals<br />Elvis Srsan: synth bass, hammond, vocals<br />Tom Bridwell: drums<br />Chris Holt: electric guitar</p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong>Numb Us</strong><br /><em>We all have our drugs, our little helpers.</em><br />Daniel Miller: acoustic guitar, drums, vocals<br />Salim Nourallah: bass, vocals<br />Chris Holt: electric guitar</p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong>Black Eye&#8217;d Kind of Love</strong><br /><em>I&#8217;ve always been pleased about how many details of the story I was able to tell in this song with such a relative economy of words. As for the story, I made it up.</em><br />Daniel Miller: acoustic guitar, drums, vocals<br />Salim Nourallah: bass, vocals<br />Chris Holt: electric guitar</p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong>Prayin&#8217; for You</strong><br /><em>&#8220;No one can keep you down when your heart is already on the ground.&#8221;</em><br />Daniel Miller: guitars, drums, vocals<br />Salim Nourallah: bass<br />Michele Pittenger: vocals</p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong>Closed for the Year</strong><br /><em>A song about an imaginary place where capitalism has no effect. It is kind of the bookend to American Dream Town.</em><br />Daniel Miller: acoustic guitar, vocals<br />Elvis Srsan: synth bass<br />Tom Bridwell: drums<br />Paul Williams: hammond<br />Jesse Donoghue: electric guitar</p>
</li>
</ol>

<p>Original sessions for <em>American Dream Town</em> and <em>Closed for the Year</em> produced by Elvis Srsan at Mandarina Studios in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina in 2003. Electric guitar for <em>Closed for the Year</em> recorded in Jesse Donoghue&#8217;s living room in Delray Beach, Florida some time before 2003.</p>

<p><em>Numb Us</em>, <em>Black Eye&#8217;d Kind of Love</em> and <em>Prayin&#8217; for You</em> produced and recorded by Salim Nourallah and mixed by Rip Rowan at Pleasantry Lane studios, Dallas, Texas in 2006 and 2007.</p>

<p>Additional recording for <em>American Dream Town</em> and <em>Closed for the Year</em> by Tom Bridwell and mixed by Paul Williams at Tomcast Studios, Dallas, Texas in 2010.</p>

<p>All tracks mastered by Carl Saff in 2010.</p>

<p>Cover art by Cathey Miller, from the original piece &#8220;Bring It&#8221;<br />Title font: Raleway by Matt McInerney<br />Cover design by Daniel Miller</p>
<p class='date'>January 24, 2011</p><script type='text/javascript'>
  djdc.connected = function() {
    $("#content_container object").css({"padding": "5px"});
  };
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">All You Lucky People</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/23/all-you-lucky-people.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/23/all-you-lucky-people.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Adam Again - All You Lucky People I&#8217;m after itAnd you&#8217;ll knowAnd I keep lookin&#8217; at all you lucky people...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_1'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/13%20All%20You%20Lucky%20People.mp3'>Adam Again - All You Lucky People</a></span></span></p>
<p>I&#8217;m after it<br />And you&#8217;ll know<br />And I keep lookin&#8217; at all you lucky people coming around<br />Say hello</p>
<p class='date'>January 23, 2011</p><script type='text/javascript'>  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/13%20All%20You%20Lucky%20People.mp3",  
        titles: "All You Lucky People",  
        artists: "Adam Again"});
  });
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Laughing Heart</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/21/the-laughing-heart.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/21/the-laughing-heart.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Your life is your lifedon&#8217;t let it be clubbed into dank submission.be on the watch.there are ways out.there is a...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Illustration by aeneastudio http://www.flickr.com/photos/90282319@N00/4253530070/' src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4040/4253530070_fb31ffee15.jpg' />
<p>Your life is your life<br />don&#8217;t let it be clubbed into dank submission.<br />be on the watch.<br />there are ways out.<br />there is a light somewhere.<br />it may not be much light but<br />it beats the darkness.<br />be on the watch.<br />the gods will offer you chances.<br />know them.<br />take them.<br />you can&#8217;t beat death but<br />you can beat death in life, sometimes.<br />and the more often you learn to do it,<br />the more light there will be.<br />your life is your life.<br />know it while you have it.<br />you are marvelous<br />the gods wait to delight<br />in you.</p>

<p>&#8211; Charles Bukowski</p>
<p class='date'>January 21, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Maranatha</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/20/maranatha.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/20/maranatha.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>&#8220;People said all kinds of things&#8230;I just gave up giving people quick answers.&#8221; January 20, 2011Warning For Overly Sensitive People:...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='340' width='560'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/oHEUrppPfIA?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/oHEUrppPfIA?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='340' width='560' /></object></p>
<p>&#8220;People said all kinds of things&#8230;I just gave up giving people quick answers.&#8221;</p>
<p class='date'>January 20, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>Warning For Overly Sensitive People: The song sung at the end of this video has a NSFW lyric, right at the 5:30 mark.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">I Once was Found</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/17/in-the-name.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/17/in-the-name.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='340' width='560'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/F9VuY4SglEA?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0#t=50s' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/F9VuY4SglEA?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0#t=50s' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='340' width='560' /></object></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Pendulum</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/11/pendulum.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/11/pendulum.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Saturday night the news of the day was still being processed and Carissa and I had a date which included...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by fliegender http://www.flickr.com/photos/fliegender/166781144/' src='http://farm1.static.flickr.com/62/166781144_3105e46712.jpg' />
<p>Saturday night the news of the day was still being processed and Carissa and I had a date which included experiencing a set of music that did amazing things the likes of which I had not seen in a long time. It seemed as if maybe God was still with us.</p>

<p>Sunday the Texas weather changed, snow fell from the sky. And story after story of the shooting was published. Some of these stories have been about conservative rhetoric, others about gun laws. While the former subject is merely a frustrating annoyance, the latter can really tear me apart. It is clear to me that we as a society have lost our right to bear arms. I&#8217;ve heard all the arguments to the contrary and they are all absurd.</p>

<p>It seems like I shouldn&#8217;t have to explain that I am more sensitive to the subject of death. But it does seem like I need to explain that these objects, that our country&#8217;s founders protected as life-sustaining and revolutionary, have become fetish objects. And if you fetishize a gun, you fetishize death. You mock life. You deny loss.</p>

<p>But I did not start this post to say that.</p>

<p>Yesterday I found out about some even more disturbing news (even though it happened over a week ago). It&#8217;s so disturbing that I&#8217;m not going to share a link. Part of the reason it was so was because it was so true. So honest. Part of what I read was this:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Maybe a God who operates by those rules does exist. If so, fuck Him.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>If there is a God I hope he is with the person who wrote that, showing him justice and comfort.</p>

<p>Saturday night&#8217;s God feels very far away.</p>

<p>I guess I&#8217;m hoping getting this out might make a call for better weather.</p>
<p class='date'>January 11, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Turn</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/09/corner.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/09/corner.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>There&#8217;s a corner being turned. The temperature is dropping. Various projects are progressing apace. My wife said it well: My...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Not exactly what I&apos;m describing in this post, but I really like this photo Carissa took at the velodrome in Frisco http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/1423220549/' src='http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1377/1423220549_7dfd4e89e7_o.jpg' />
<p>There&#8217;s a corner being turned. The temperature is dropping. Various projects are progressing apace. <a href='http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2011/01/new-years.html'>My wife said it well</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>My goals for 2011 are to take everyone by the hand and march us all left, right, left, right, forward, quickly, eyes open for opportunity and minds open for peace. I wish for everyone personal growth in relationships and careers and health and blessings on all people. May you all be filled with real strength and love.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Carissa is an amazingly strong person for whom I am very grateful. I could not navigate these waters without her. I&#8217;m also attracted to her each day more than the last. I don&#8217;t have a lot of relationship advice to give, but I think that&#8217;s the way this thing called love is supposed to work.</p>
<hr />
<blockquote>
<p>&#8230;when people are truly sinking&#8230;they have no idea what mix of character, connections and dumb luck will be enough to pull through</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In reading <em><a href='http://nyti.ms/hBgUlt'>On Road to Recovery, Past Adversity Provides a Map</a></em> I thought about all the difficult times we&#8217;ve both had prior to being together. In this, the most difficult search for meaning, it might be thought that those past hardships were to prepare us for this. Or it could just be, as she put it:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&#8230;this is the era where everyone around me has had enough time to create something important. Celebrations are more meaningful and loss is more profound because in either direction there is such investment.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In any case, to consider all this random and meaningless, while valid, is a path to madness.</p>
<hr />
<p>I recently started riding my bike a bit more. I got sick of my gut hanging over my belt. Counting calories has once again become a habit. Riding is the only way to keep those calories in the negative enough to really make a difference. I need to drink less too. I&#8217;m trying.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.rapha.cc/the-rapha-festive-500'>Rapha has provided some motivation</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Riding hard at Christmas is not a paradox. As you stuff your belly with food and soak yourself with booze, the roads may seem empty. But they aren&#8217;t. This year, riders across the globe will be squeezing themselves like oversized elves into tights and overshoes and heading out to go the distance, leaving the turbo trainer in the garage.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>My goal was to do half of the Rapha 500. I got to maybe 200k instead. But I went on the longest ride I&#8217;d done since the 90&#8217;s. I rode more days than I had in any given week since the 90&#8217;s. I&#8217;m noticeably faster now than I was two weeks before Christmas. I haven&#8217;t lost any weight. But when I&#8217;m on my bicycle my mind clears and fills with good ideas and sometimes, even, a little hope. I still miss good opportunities to ride, but I&#8217;m getting better about not letting those pass me by.</p>

<p>Guiding a well built bicycle through a turn at speed is one of the most enjoyable things a man can do. If practiced, there becomes a sequence trained into the body that makes it feel as if it has joined with the machine beneath it, one entity with one mind. There is a cadence to the movements: the shifting of weight on the saddle and then on the pedals, the eyes&#8217; line moves further ahead, then the body initiates the turn and the bicycle obeys.</p>

<p>It is starting to feel like the first beats of that cadence.</p>
<p class='date'>January 09, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>While I have not splurged for any Rapha clothing, they do help <a href='http://www.velodramatic.com/archives/6266'>perpetuate an aesthetic</a> that accentuates all the things I've loved about cycling. It is, after all, one of the most beautiful sports in the world. It should be no surprise that so many designers are drawn to it.<br /><br /><object height='270' width='480'><param name='allowfullscreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><param name='movie' value='http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=15197531&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=0&amp;show_byline=0&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1&amp;autoplay=0&amp;loop=0' /><embed src='http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=15197531&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=0&amp;show_byline=0&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1&amp;autoplay=0&amp;loop=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='270' width='480' /></object></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Frankie...</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/08/frankie.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/08/frankie.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I hope at this point anyone in Dallas reading this blog knows about what happened in our community this week....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by Danny Fulgencio for the Dallas Observer http://blogs.dallasobserver.com/dc9/2011/01/last_night_the_frankie_45_memo.php' src='http://blogs.dallasobserver.com/dc9/frankiefrankdanny.jpg' />
<p>I hope at this point anyone in Dallas reading this blog knows about <a href='http://www.dallasobserver.com/2011-01-06/music/remembering-frankie-45/'>what happened in our community</a> this week. If you don&#8217;t, go read that fitting tribute by Pete Freedman, as well as <a href='http://frontrow.dmagazine.com/2011/01/bill-holston-frankie-45-left-it-on-the-stage/'>this one by our friend Bill Holston</a>. I only knew Frankie and only know Frank from seeing them at the Kettle gallery and Dada. Obviously I now feel connected to Frank. I don&#8217;t know what else to say about this, or how to possibly reach out to him. The place he now inhabits, and will be, where I still am, it is indescribable and unknowable and unique for each person within it.</p>
<p><object height='295' width='480'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/MGWA2Y9v0pM?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/MGWA2Y9v0pM?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='295' width='480' /></object></p><p class='date' style='clear:all'>January 08, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
