<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>danielsjourney</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml" />
  <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2011-06-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>loss</subtitle>

  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Panda Bear</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/07/T_T.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/07/T_T.html</id>
    <updated>2011-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>It's weird the things that will set me off. This picture breaks my fucking heart. June 07, 2011 Lately I've...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4001/4394761412_24b6877a8d.jpg" width="500" height="337" alt="13A by yukilife http://www.flickr.com/photos/yukilife/4394761412/" title="13A by yukilife http://www.flickr.com/photos/yukilife/4394761412/"></p>

<p>It's weird the things that will set me off. This picture breaks</p>

<p style="text-align:center">my fucking</p>




<p style="text-align:right">heart.</p>




<p class="date">June 07, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">Lately I've been busy enough to forget about things for large chunks of my day. Then something will trigger a thought or a memory and the wave of emotions, the front load washer spin cycle kicks into high gear and it'll even throw in some guilt about having forgotten. Just for good measure. I'm having to just plow through; and I wonder what it's doing to me.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Raffiniert ist der Herrgott, aber boshaft ist er nicht</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/06/still.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/06/still.html</id>
    <updated>2011-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>One of the main problems has been how completely unsatisfactory any attempts to create meaningful narrative around this situation are....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/sports.png" title="http://xkcd.com/904/ 'Also, all financial analysis. And, more directly, D&D.' the as always brilliant xkcd"></p>

<p>One of the main problems has been how completely unsatisfactory any attempts to create meaningful narrative around this situation are. Storytelling is one of the main activities of human beings, it's how we construct meaning and make sense of our lives. (I could write more about this and reference a lot of material but I barely have time to publish this short post; and that is a big rabbit hole--I might end up making less sense than if I just leave it at the previous sentence.)</p>

<p>So when the bad days arrive, like <a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/22/lately.html">I mentioned</a>, like this last Saturday and a couple days in-between, this is what my brain immediately tries to do. It cycles through a lot of different thoughts and emotions very quickly but it typically ends up trying to construct some meaningful narrative to deal with all those thoughts and emotions. And it fails. It ends up simply sad, angry, lonely and frustrated that there is nothing to explain why it has to feel that way, why the best thing that ever happened to me was taken from me, why such a beautiful life ended so soon.</p>

<p>I saw <a href="http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein#1920s">an Einstein quote</a> yesterday: "Subtle is the Lord, but malicious He is not." I like that it was followed (at some point) with: "I have second thoughts. Maybe God is malicious."*</p>

<p class="date">June 6, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">* According to wikipedia, "as quoted in Einstein in America (1985) by Jamie Sayen, indicating that God leads people to believe they understand things that they actually are far from understanding"</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Something From Nothing</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/30/this-looks-a-bit-like-an-elephant.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/30/this-looks-a-bit-like-an-elephant.html</id>
    <updated>2011-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>About a year ago I told Hal this film needed to be made, and that was before the Banksy business....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><span class="media"><iframe frameborder="0" height="410px" src="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1605226499/something-from-nothing/widget/video.html" width="480px"></iframe></span></p>

<p>About a year ago I told Hal this film needed to be made, and that was before the <a href="http://blog.vandalog.com/2011/03/before-banksy-that-elephant-tank-was-a-mans-home/">Banksy</a> <a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/did-banksys-latest-work-bring-misery-to-a-homeless-man-2246336.html">business</a>. This is an important project and you should go support it as you are able.</p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="380px" src="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1605226499/something-from-nothing/widget/card.html" width="220px"></iframe>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">YAPAB (Yet Another Post About Bicycling)</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/26/yapab.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/26/yapab.html</id>
    <updated>2011-05-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>If you think about it, bicycling is an absurd activity in which to engage. There are many reasons: TL;DR: Bicycling...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/24290169?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=ffffff" width="499" height="281" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>


<p>If you think about it, bicycling is an absurd activity in which to engage. There are many reasons:</p>

<p style="font-style:italic; font-size: .9em; text-align: right"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Too_long;_didn't_read">TL;DR</a>: Bicycling is a beautiful activity and sport despite all the counts against it, and as such is a great metaphor for humanity's place within life's rich pageant.</p>


<p>Time: between maintaining a bicycle, shopping for new equipment, preparing for a ride (kit, contacts, collecting of necessities), actually riding (which as you become more proficient, requires more time), cleaning up after a ride and washing kit...absurd amounts of time are spent. It's a full time thing, really.</p>

<p>Danger: not only are there the dangers of simply riding down the road--wet, oily turns, railroad tracks, cracks in the pavement, debris--there are vehicles, and most notably their drivers! Not only are most of them in a <em>huge rush to get to their important life destination</em>, they are also <em>texting important things</em> while doing so, frequently paying no attention whatsoever to the road or other persons on it, assuming whatever they hit won't be killed because of course it will also be enclosed in steel and glass. Because <em>who would ride a bicycle on the road with these idiots?</em></p>

<p>There's more! Dogs, one of which I encountered today. The thing with dogs is, if they bark, they probably won't bite. It's the ones who don't make a sound you have to worry about. Today I was riding along and I heard* the sound of dog claws coming in <em>rather frequent</em> contact with asphalt. I looked back to see that the <em>biggest German Shepard</em> you have ever seen was almost within striking distance of me. Somehow I found some speed and outran him. He added a nice sprint interval to what was going to be an otherwise mid-tempo ride.</p>

<p>Then there's racing, which if you're crazy enough to train for and do, increases your chance of unfortunate contact with the pavement exponentially.</p>

<p>Cost: self explanatory. Bikes and the things they require are almost as bad as boats and Ferraris.</p>

<p>Pain: it's not just the legs and lungs. Back and butt are the real problems. One must nurture and nurse a very specific area of one's anatomy that comes in contact with that infernal device known as a saddle. As for the back, as it ages it complains ever more incessantly about the unnatural position a bicyclist subjects it to for long periods of time.</p>

<p>Despite all of this and more, we still not only continue to bicycle, but <em>actually enjoy</em> it! Even on days when I've ridden plenty, like today, or even days when I couldn't ride more even if I tried, I still feel jealousy and compulsion when I see riders go by my house**. I guess there's some magic ratio when the traffic isn't trying to kill you, and the road surface isn't trying to break your bike, and the wind isn't trying to slow you to a crawl, and the heat isn't trying to cause salty sweat to pour into your eyes and weigh down your clothes, and the glass isn't trying to force you into roadside maintenance delay...when the tempo is just right and the pedals turn with ease and the sweat actually evaporates off your body...those moments somehow fuel the fire and keep us out there day after day.</p>

<hr>


<p>There's a Calvin and Hobbes cartoon that says this much better in panels instead of paragraphs...short of finding it, scanning it and violating ridiculous copyrights by posting it here, I recommend you read a lot of <a href="http://www.bicycling.com/news/featured-stories/stroke-fate">Bill Strickland</a>, specifically that one that describes many of the aesthetic wonders of cycling (once again) better than I can.</p>

<hr>


<p>I've <a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/12/dope.html">mentioned before</a> the current doping crisis in cycling, and the history that will need to be re-written because of the doping crisis in cycling. I don't want to harp on it much more, but if you missed <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2011/05/20/60minutes/main20064858.shtml?tag=contentMain;cbsCarousel">Tyler Hamilton on 60 Minutes last weekend</a> I suggest you check it out. If you don't realize it is still a present issue, <a href="http://bicycling.com/blogs/thisjustin/2011/05/26/contador-defence-tries-to-delay-cas-hearing/">think again</a>. And finally if you don't think we should be worried about past offenders, I suggest you consider <a href="http://bicycling.com/blogs/boulderreport/2011/05/26/failure/">this</a>.</p>

<p class="date">May 26, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">* If I was one of you earbud-sporting jokers out there, my calves would have been doggie treats!<br><br>** We live on a popular hill loop near <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&source=s_q&hl=en&geocode=&q=white+rock+lake,+dallas&aq=&sll=32.833515,-96.72226&sspn=0.047382,0.086346&gl=us&ie=UTF8&hq=&hnear=White+Rock+Lake&ll=32.828034,-96.725349&spn=0.047385,0.086346&z=14">White Rock Lake</a>.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Fear, Flatulence, Fingers, Fabulous</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/25/fear-flatulence-fingers-fabulous.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/25/fear-flatulence-fingers-fabulous.html</id>
    <updated>2011-05-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Last night hail and tornados fell upon our city, distracting Penn from his homework and generally striking fear into the...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/bathroom_huddle.jpg" title="Bathroom Huddle"></p>

<p>Last night hail and tornados fell upon our city, distracting Penn from his homework and generally striking fear into the populace of our metroplex. As <a href="http://twitpic.com/52522m">the weather man</a> continued to pronounce the imminent destruction of our homes and businesses, Penn expressed multiple times, <em>"I'm scared!"</em> My only response was, "I am too! We all are!" I have a whole post about fear coming up.</p>

<p>When the time came, we closed all the shudders and doors and got into the bathroom located in the very middle of our house. You could barely hear the storm from in there. Then the power goes out. And it gets hot quick.</p>

<p>Then Penn goes, "Wait, I hear something!" We all get quiet. And then he lets rip a loud one! He and I laugh loud. Mom not so much. But I was pleased at how well I've trained him.</p>

<p><object width="560" height="349"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/5crL6uPIuIs?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/5crL6uPIuIs?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="560" height="349" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></p>


<p>Took this video shortly before we retreated to the bathroom. It was <em>non-stop</em> lightning. If you watch the whole clip, you'll see the <em>huge</em> strike that made me stop filming and all of us run back inside!</p>

<hr>


<p>This morning we went for our second baby appointment and another sonogram. They had to measure the baby's neck or something so to get the baby to get into a position where they could get their measurement the technician had Carissa move around. She moved to her right side: nothing. She moved to her left side and our baby did a little 80's dance. It was certainly a fantastic way to start my day, seeing that.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2257/5759151616_af1745a9ef.jpg" alt="Sonogram picture" /></p>

<p>Also there was the image above, where you can see her/his fingers. Which is awesome/amazing.</p>

<hr>


<p>Tonight I went to a talk by <a href="http://garyvaynerchuk.com/">Gary Vaynerchuk</a> who is an amazingly inspiring speaker. During the Q&amp;A he always asked how the question-asker was doing and the question-asker always reciprocated the question. His answer was either <em>tremendous</em> or <em>fabulous</em>. It's part of his thing. He's like a ball of infectious energy which I appreciated and enjoyed. Still, it made me think about that question, one we all ask. <em>"How are you?"</em> A question I have an entire blog post about as well.</p>

<p class="date">May 25, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Lately</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/22/lately.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/22/lately.html</id>
    <updated>2011-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>We've been having a few hard days. You wouldn't know it from the outside, but inside our hearts and minds...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://mlkshk.com/r/2LWH" title="Eggs http://mlkshk.com/p/2LWH"></p>

<p>We've been having a few hard days. You wouldn't know it from the outside, but inside our hearts and minds it's been inexplicably harder the last couple days. My bad day was Friday--which happened to be the day of my first client meeting for the <a href="http://extrasauce.com">new job</a>...bad day for a bad day, although hopefully no one noticed and the meeting did go swimmingly, although that had little to nothing to do with me. Carissa's was yesterday, when I should have coerced her into coming to <a href="http://gowalla.com/checkins/37114225">paint the new office</a> but instead she was left alone home with her thoughts.</p>

<hr>


<p>It's sort of like this: everything is going really well. <em>Really</em> well. Except for that one thing. And that one thing colors all the other really good things with <em>if only, if only, if only</em>.</p>

<hr>


<p>It's sort of like this: I still think this with frequency: <em>Why? Why me? Why her? Why us?</em> The most comforting logic as of late has been that these things have no logic, no reason, no prejudice. I imagine it is the sort of thing a young man of old would experience on the battlefield. There are life lessons most people never learn anymore. There are a few still who are forced to learn them. This is a wisdom I could have done without. There are lessons we learn because of our own moral decrepitude--I have had many of those. These other lessons of which I speak, they are thrust upon us most unwillingly. It is almost like we are not allowed to live as the rest of you live. We are forced to wrestle with the angel. But our story will not be written in any holy books. Our story is barely written in your memories.</p>

<hr>


<p>I rode the Sunday morning ride as usual this morning. I'm not sure I've missed a Sunday this year except when I was out of town one weekend. This morning was particularly humid, however. So much time spent getting sweat out of eyes. <a href="http://kotori.bostonbiker.org/2008/11/22/reflection-on-the-meanings-of-kits/">Kit</a> soaked in seat weighs heavy on the frame. Not to mention the difficulty it creates in the unmentionables. No matter how you prepare the Area in Question, if sweat cannot escape it, discomfort is soon to follow.</p>

<p>The Sunday morning ride, as usual, clocked in at about 50 miles.</p>

<p>So of course I followed that up with a commute by bicycle to my new office to continue (however briefly) the painting effort.</p>

<hr>


<p>After an hour or two I joined the rest of my family for a <a href="http://apeepatthecoops.blogspot.com/">chicken coop tour</a>. Apparently this is quite foreign to most city dwellers, however we have been considering having chickens for a little while now. And there are enough people already doing it in East Dallas alone as well as enough interest in the practice to justify what appeared to be a very successful and popular event! Almost every stop had not just a fantastic coop but also a flourishing garden. Obviously I already live in a house with <a href="http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/search/label/food">amazing food</a>. But we're always on the proverbial hunt for something that can make our table even tastier.</p>

<hr>


<p>So many thoughts in between all of these, but I have not the time nor the inclination to collect them. I'm most frequently reduced to a shrug and frown and slapping of hands onto the plow. Then, later, a toast, a laugh, a story.</p>

<p class="date">May 22, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Jonathan Harris: Today</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/10/today.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/10/today.html</id>
    <updated>2011-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>

</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><object width="640" height="510"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/AH7YxbuZQs8?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;hd=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/AH7YxbuZQs8?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;hd=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="510" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The New Black</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/04/how-to-mourn.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/04/how-to-mourn.html</id>
    <updated>2011-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>

</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><object width="560" height="349"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/vgwhRiGFxn0?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;hd=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/vgwhRiGFxn0?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;hd=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="560" height="349" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Baby</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/28/baby.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/28/baby.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Obviously we are thrilled to announce that Carissa is pregnant. I had hoped that this announcement, whenever it came, might...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5225/5661852854_2b85931e1b_z.jpg" alt="7 weeks 5 days sonogram" title="http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5661852854/ 7 weeks 5 days sonogram"></p>

<p>Obviously we are thrilled to announce that Carissa is pregnant.</p>

<p>I had hoped that this announcement, whenever it came, might be the final post of this blog. I'm realizing that is probably not the case. There are still some things I'm going to have to figure out about this experience and this blog has been a half decent place to work out some of those things. (That said, clearly I won't be posting here past December, at the latest.)</p>

<p>I'm hoping Lucy's* development, arrival and life is the most beautiful and amazing thing ever experienced by mankind. It will be. It has to be. She has a perfect big sister to make proud.</p>

<p class="date">April 28, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">* &ldquo;<a href="http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2011/04/baby-miller.html">Think girl thoughts</a>.&rdquo;</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Fathers do you want...</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/26/fathers.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/26/fathers.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>


  djdc.connected = function() {
    $("img.callout").css("max-width","640px");
  };


</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5190/5658108216_01d21a540e_z.jpg" title="Photo by niznoz http://www.flickr.com/photos/niznoz/5658108216"></p>

<script type="text/javascript">
  djdc.connected = function() {
    $("img.callout").css("max-width","640px");
  };
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Iesus Nazarenus, Rex Iudaeorum</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/24/easter.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/24/easter.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I've always been more interested in the death of Jesus than his resurrection. The resurrection feels like a cop out....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/download.jpeg" title="# http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/04/18/us-france-art-idUSTRE73H4JR20110418"></p>

<p>I've always been more interested in the death of Jesus than his resurrection. The resurrection feels like a cop out. Like the authors and architects of my religion had to make it conform to the standards of mythology and epic narrative.</p>

<p>There are stories of believers who did not immediately learn of the resurrection. They remained faithful for years to the Christ who had died on a cross, before learning that he had afterwards walked through walls and floated up into the sky. Part of me wants to be part of a secret sect who was never brought the News. We would believe because of the man who lived, not the man who lived again. Those of us who died--our elderly and our children--would join Him, wherever he was. Not because he had floated into the sky, but because he had gone before us, and stayed there.</p>

<p>Because that some messiah was raised from the dead but then allowed my perfect daughter to go before me is absurd, and I refuse to pretend otherwise. I do not lose hope that there is some explanation, mind you. I would simply point out that your social network proclamations of "He is risen!" ring a little flat this season.</p>

<p>Some zealous believers <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/04/18/us-france-art-idUSTRE73H4JR20110418">damaged an image of Christ on the cross</a> this week because they thought it defaming. They struck his image in the face. Here He was in his most blatantly symbolic--molded in cheap plastic by those who claim to honor him, then surrounded by our human waste--and they erased his face. In their attempts to keep Him separate--holy and resurrected--they removed him from us, and left us only with our waste.</p>

<p>They enforce the voice that says this is punishment for historic acts. They remove the hope of rescue from this mire, that this life is not as it seems, that time and its suffering are just a constraint she has been saved from.</p>

<p>There are some who will find the above paragraphs telling of a lost or misguided faith (&ldquo;<a href="http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=1%20Corinthians%2015:14-18&amp;version=NASB">1 Corinthians 15</a>!" I hear you flipping to), perhaps even compelled to intervene (with a Facebook comment--LOL!) or pray.</p>

<p>Here's a great <a href="http://thoughtcatalog.com/2011/easter-jesus-was-way-cool/">post about Easter</a> that references <a href="http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Mark+8%3A22-24&amp;version=NASB">Mark 8</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>...This passage has always stuck with me. I don't believe that Jesus walked on water or multiplied loaves and fishes. ...But that strange statement by the blind man at the end--"I see men like trees, walking around." It's strange. It's beautiful. And it sounds real. It doesn't sound fake. It sounds like something that a blind man, upon seeing the world for the first time, might actually say. Groping for something to compare the sight of fellow human beings to, he might say that they remind him of trees; landlocked trees that he has touched and felt before--trees that are suddenly uprooted and are moving around.</p>

<p>It's an eerie passage...[it] does seem oddly convincing--in a way that is different from so much of the Bible, which so often does not seem oddly convincing. And so, did a bunch of people actually see Jesus restore sight to a blind man? ...Well?  ...Did they?</p></blockquote>

<p>I've always been more convinced by curious disbelief than by firm, rational beliefs.</p>

<p class="date">April 24, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript"><a href="http://www.kesterbrewin.com/2011/04/19/piss-christ-sanitising-death-and-torture/">Here is another good analysis of the Piss Christ vandalism by my friend Kester</a>.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Music is a world within itself with a language we all understand</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/23/music.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/23/music.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>My friends from Albuquerque, Lousy Robot, were in town last night and I rather enjoyed their set of music at...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5064/5645792898_2cd64f2237_z.jpg" title="Dandee Fleming and Joey Gonzales of Lousy Robot, photo by Kate Mackley http://www.flickr.com/photos/katemackley/5645792898/in/photostream"></p>

<p>My friends from Albuquerque, <a href="http://music.lousyrobot.com/"><em>Lousy Robot</em></a>, were in town last night and I rather enjoyed their set of music at the Double Wide. I had a lot of profound thoughts during the show but I must have washed them all away with IPA. Simply put: music is awesome.</p>

<p>Dandee (pictured) really enjoys playing and it shows when he is on stage. The world could do for a few more musicians like Dandee and a few more bands like Lousy Robot.</p>

<p class="date">April 23, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">&amp;ldquo;Busy day&amp;hellip;but there&amp;rsquo;s always time for the paper.&amp;rdquo;</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/20/busy.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/20/busy.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Things have been busy and will continue to be so. There is more good news to come. There is work...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/tumblr_ljyjrpJZIz1qzcq51o1_500.gif" title="&ldquo;Busy day in Manhattan&hellip;but there&rsquo;s always time for the paper.&rdquo; via From Me To You http://fromme-toyou.tumblr.com/post/4778641278/busy-day-in-manhattan-but-theres-always-time-for"></p>

<p>Things have been <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/withextrasauce/status/60026226236080128">busy</a> and will continue to be so. There is more good news to come. There is work to be done. It still comes and goes in waves. There are still a couple things I wrestle with and perhaps will make observations about on this blog but for the most part this is wrapping itself up and I am trying to strategize a move back to--and re-inclusion of the archives of--my regular blog.</p>

<p>Here are some pics of recent life:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5631350506/" title="Soccer Picnic by carissabyers, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5024/5631350506_f18bfaed10.jpg" width="500" height="334" alt="Soccer Picnic"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5609519035/" title="Lakewood Spring Carival by carissabyers, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5224/5609519035_2888310e75_z.jpg" alt="Lakewood Spring Carival"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5610098872/" title="Lakewood Spring Carival by carissabyers, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5145/5610098872_a1a00a86bc.jpg" width="500" height="334" alt="Lakewood Spring Carival"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5600708590/" title="Deep Ellum Arts Festival by carissabyers, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5064/5600708590_0ed44e0c80.jpg" width="500" height="334" alt="Deep Ellum Arts Festival"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5607442933/" title="Goalie Penn by carissabyers, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5106/5607442933_015ee04684.jpg" width="500" height="334" alt="Goalie Penn"></a></p>

<p class="date">April 20, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">There is so much going on in this video it kind of freaks me out</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/15/so-much.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/15/so-much.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>

</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><object width="640" height="390"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/3i-zYdOPG2k?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0&amp;hd=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/3i-zYdOPG2k?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0&amp;hd=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="640" height="390"></embed></object></p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Perhaps because it is the most beautiful sport, it is the most trouble-ridden</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/12/dope.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/12/dope.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I mentioned a while ago that I might write a long post about the doping issue in professional cycling. At...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/18/23072082_0571604453.jpg" title="http://www.flickr.com/photos/slabbers/23072082/ Photo by Bastiaan Slabbers"></p>

<p>I <a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/07/super-bowl.html">mentioned a while ago</a> that I might write a long post about the doping issue in professional cycling. At the time I was catching up on all the information available, specifically about Lance Armstrong and in light of the <a href="http://nyvelocity.com/content/interviews/2011/landiskimmage">very long interview of Floyd Landis</a> I spent quite a few days reading and analyzing. If you're really interested in this subject, I suggest you read it.</p>

<p>In the meantime, Bicycling magazine's Bill Strickland has <a href="https://www.readability.com/articles/hfwviezu">published a really well done piece in their latest issue</a> which says everything I wanted to say but with more writing talent, insight and experience than I have.</p>

<p class="date">April 12, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
