<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>danielsjourney</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml" />
  <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2011-01-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>loss</subtitle>

  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Laughing Heart</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/21/the-laughing-heart.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/21/the-laughing-heart.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Your life is your lifedon&#8217;t let it be clubbed into dank submission.be on the watch.there are ways out.there is a...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Illustration by aeneastudio http://www.flickr.com/photos/90282319@N00/4253530070/' src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4040/4253530070_fb31ffee15.jpg' />
<p>Your life is your life<br />don&#8217;t let it be clubbed into dank submission.<br />be on the watch.<br />there are ways out.<br />there is a light somewhere.<br />it may not be much light but<br />it beats the darkness.<br />be on the watch.<br />the gods will offer you chances.<br />know them.<br />take them.<br />you can&#8217;t beat death but<br />you can beat death in life, sometimes.<br />and the more often you learn to do it,<br />the more light there will be.<br />your life is your life.<br />know it while you have it.<br />you are marvelous<br />the gods wait to delight<br />in you.</p>

<p>&#8211; Charles Bukowski</p>
<p class='date'>January 21, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Maranatha</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/20/maranatha.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/20/maranatha.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>&#8220;People said all kinds of things&#8230;I just gave up giving people quick answers.&#8221; January 20, 2011Warning For Overly Sensitive People:...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='340' width='560'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/oHEUrppPfIA?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/oHEUrppPfIA?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='340' width='560' /></object></p>
<p>&#8220;People said all kinds of things&#8230;I just gave up giving people quick answers.&#8221;</p>
<p class='date'>January 20, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>Warning For Overly Sensitive People: The song sung at the end of this video has a NSFW lyric, right at the 5:30 mark.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">I Once was Found</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/17/in-the-name.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/17/in-the-name.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='340' width='560'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/F9VuY4SglEA?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0#t=50s' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/F9VuY4SglEA?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0#t=50s' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='340' width='560' /></object></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Pendulum</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/11/pendulum.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/11/pendulum.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Saturday night the news of the day was still being processed and Carissa and I had a date which included...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by fliegender http://www.flickr.com/photos/fliegender/166781144/' src='http://farm1.static.flickr.com/62/166781144_3105e46712.jpg' />
<p>Saturday night the news of the day was still being processed and Carissa and I had a date which included experiencing a set of music that did amazing things the likes of which I had not seen in a long time. It seemed as if maybe God was still with us.</p>

<p>Sunday the Texas weather changed, snow fell from the sky. And story after story of the shooting was published. Some of these stories have been about conservative rhetoric, others about gun laws. While the former subject is merely a frustrating annoyance, the latter can really tear me apart. It is clear to me that we as a society have lost our right to bear arms. I&#8217;ve heard all the arguments to the contrary and they are all absurd.</p>

<p>It seems like I shouldn&#8217;t have to explain that I am more sensitive to the subject of death. But it does seem like I need to explain that these objects, that our country&#8217;s founders protected as life-sustaining and revolutionary, have become fetish objects. And if you fetishize a gun, you fetishize death. You mock life. You deny loss.</p>

<p>But I did not start this post to say that.</p>

<p>Yesterday I found out about some even more disturbing news (even though it happened over a week ago). It&#8217;s so disturbing that I&#8217;m not going to share a link. Part of the reason it was so was because it was so true. So honest. Part of what I read was this:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Maybe a God who operates by those rules does exist. If so, fuck Him.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>If there is a God I hope he is with the person who wrote that, showing him justice and comfort.</p>

<p>Saturday night&#8217;s God feels very far away.</p>

<p>I guess I&#8217;m hoping getting this out might make a call for better weather.</p>
<p class='date'>January 11, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Turn</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/09/corner.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/09/corner.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>There&#8217;s a corner being turned. The temperature is dropping. Various projects are progressing apace. My wife said it well: My...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Not exactly what I&apos;m describing in this post, but I really like this photo Carissa took at the velodrome in Frisco http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/1423220549/' src='http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1377/1423220549_7dfd4e89e7_o.jpg' />
<p>There&#8217;s a corner being turned. The temperature is dropping. Various projects are progressing apace. <a href='http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2011/01/new-years.html'>My wife said it well</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>My goals for 2011 are to take everyone by the hand and march us all left, right, left, right, forward, quickly, eyes open for opportunity and minds open for peace. I wish for everyone personal growth in relationships and careers and health and blessings on all people. May you all be filled with real strength and love.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Carissa is an amazingly strong person for whom I am very grateful. I could not navigate these waters without her. I&#8217;m also attracted to her each day more than the last. I don&#8217;t have a lot of relationship advice to give, but I think that&#8217;s the way this thing called love is supposed to work.</p>
<hr />
<blockquote>
<p>&#8230;when people are truly sinking&#8230;they have no idea what mix of character, connections and dumb luck will be enough to pull through</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In reading <em><a href='http://nyti.ms/hBgUlt'>On Road to Recovery, Past Adversity Provides a Map</a></em> I thought about all the difficult times we&#8217;ve both had prior to being together. In this, the most difficult search for meaning, it might be thought that those past hardships were to prepare us for this. Or it could just be, as she put it:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&#8230;this is the era where everyone around me has had enough time to create something important. Celebrations are more meaningful and loss is more profound because in either direction there is such investment.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In any case, to consider all this random and meaningless, while valid, is a path to madness.</p>
<hr />
<p>I recently started riding my bike a bit more. I got sick of my gut hanging over my belt. Counting calories has once again become a habit. Riding is the only way to keep those calories in the negative enough to really make a difference. I need to drink less too. I&#8217;m trying.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.rapha.cc/the-rapha-festive-500'>Rapha has provided some motivation</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Riding hard at Christmas is not a paradox. As you stuff your belly with food and soak yourself with booze, the roads may seem empty. But they aren&#8217;t. This year, riders across the globe will be squeezing themselves like oversized elves into tights and overshoes and heading out to go the distance, leaving the turbo trainer in the garage.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>My goal was to do half of the Rapha 500. I got to maybe 200k instead. But I went on the longest ride I&#8217;d done since the 90&#8217;s. I rode more days than I had in any given week since the 90&#8217;s. I&#8217;m noticeably faster now than I was two weeks before Christmas. I haven&#8217;t lost any weight. But when I&#8217;m on my bicycle my mind clears and fills with good ideas and sometimes, even, a little hope. I still miss good opportunities to ride, but I&#8217;m getting better about not letting those pass me by.</p>

<p>Guiding a well built bicycle through a turn at speed is one of the most enjoyable things a man can do. If practiced, there becomes a sequence trained into the body that makes it feel as if it has joined with the machine beneath it, one entity with one mind. There is a cadence to the movements: the shifting of weight on the saddle and then on the pedals, the eyes&#8217; line moves further ahead, then the body initiates the turn and the bicycle obeys.</p>

<p>It is starting to feel like the first beats of that cadence.</p>
<p class='date'>January 09, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>While I have not splurged for any Rapha clothing, they do help <a href='http://www.velodramatic.com/archives/6266'>perpetuate an aesthetic</a> that accentuates all the things I've loved about cycling. It is, after all, one of the most beautiful sports in the world. It should be no surprise that so many designers are drawn to it.<br /><br /><object height='270' width='480'><param name='allowfullscreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><param name='movie' value='http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=15197531&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=0&amp;show_byline=0&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1&amp;autoplay=0&amp;loop=0' /><embed src='http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=15197531&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=0&amp;show_byline=0&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1&amp;autoplay=0&amp;loop=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='270' width='480' /></object></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Frankie...</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/08/frankie.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/08/frankie.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I hope at this point anyone in Dallas reading this blog knows about what happened in our community this week....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by Danny Fulgencio for the Dallas Observer http://blogs.dallasobserver.com/dc9/2011/01/last_night_the_frankie_45_memo.php' src='http://blogs.dallasobserver.com/dc9/frankiefrankdanny.jpg' />
<p>I hope at this point anyone in Dallas reading this blog knows about <a href='http://www.dallasobserver.com/2011-01-06/music/remembering-frankie-45/'>what happened in our community</a> this week. If you don&#8217;t, go read that fitting tribute by Pete Freedman, as well as <a href='http://frontrow.dmagazine.com/2011/01/bill-holston-frankie-45-left-it-on-the-stage/'>this one by our friend Bill Holston</a>. I only knew Frankie and only know Frank from seeing them at the Kettle gallery and Dada. Obviously I now feel connected to Frank. I don&#8217;t know what else to say about this, or how to possibly reach out to him. The place he now inhabits, and will be, where I still am, it is indescribable and unknowable and unique for each person within it.</p>
<p><object height='295' width='480'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/MGWA2Y9v0pM?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/MGWA2Y9v0pM?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='295' width='480' /></object></p><p class='date' style='clear:all'>January 08, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Tweetage Wasteland: You Can't Turn Off The Machine</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/05/the-machine.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/05/the-machine.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Last December I paid Dave Pell a compliment on Twitter and he replied &#8220;Learning a lot from your blog.&#8221; I...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='385' width='480'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/u7ziwuIpnVY?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/u7ziwuIpnVY?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='385' width='480' /></object></p>
<p>Last December <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/dealingwith/status/14823407203913728'>I paid Dave Pell a compliment on Twitter</a> and he replied &#8220;<a href='http://twitter.com/#!/davepell/status/14852545004437504'>Learning a lot from your blog</a>.&#8221; I thought, &#8220;Uh oh, which blog?&#8221; and asked him as much in a direct message. Twitter gave way to email and he asked if he could use material from my post <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/29/connected.html'>&#8220;The Infinitely Connected Triggers of Her Memory and the Dumb Machines of the Technopathocracy.&#8221;</a> Dave starts his piece:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>I think about a lot of things before I share online. But here&#8217;s one thing I never think about:</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>The unthinkable.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Dave is an amazing writer already featured on NPR (among others), and <a href='http://tweetagewasteland.com/2011/01/you-cant-turn-off-the-machine/'>the things he wrote around the context of my post were both sensitive and thought provoking</a>.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Daniel can&#8217;t escape his own digital trail. Yet he returns to the internet to add to it. He is using the machine to express his frustration that the machine won&#8217;t leave him alone. The same technology that haunts him also provides a way to mourn and remember.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>&#8230;The acts of communication, sharing and remembering online are similar to their counterparts in our offline lives, but they&#8217;re not the same.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>&#8230;We haven&#8217;t had a chance to reflect on the role this technology is playing in our lives.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This is all a subject matter I&#8217;ve been interested in for a long time. In my original post I use the term <em>technopathology</em>, a term I first encountered in the Peter Lamborn Wilson (aka Hakim Bey) video I included in <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/28/isolation.html'>this post</a> (he coined the term). I&#8217;ve been a long-time fan of Wilson&#8217;s writings (ask anyone who&#8217;s been around when I start referencing his essay on <a href='http://books.google.com/books?id=FlKN__HHPTMC&amp;lpg=PP1&amp;ots=L760-c6-yS&amp;dq=hakim%20bey%20immediatism&amp;pg=PA7#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false'>Immediatism</a>) but I&#8217;m not as radical in my rejection of technologies as he. As Dave says, this is the world we live in&#8211;and I read that a little more literally as a technologist who makes his living (and spends most of his time, besides) in front of just such a machine. But to think about this system as &#8220;the rule of sick machines&#8221; is helpful when trying to diagnose these illnesses we&#8217;ve developed due to our unblinking acceptance of various technologies into our lives.</p>

<p>I wrote about this topic years ago for Movement magazine in the UK:</p>
<blockquote style='font-style:normal'>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m not really so lapsarian. Like Doctorow and Sterling, I believe more in a singularity than an apocalypse.<br /><br />&ldquo;...technology allows a boolean-packet level quantification of not new behaviors, but ways-of-being that predate history. A simple way to explore what the web was really teaching us was to imagine a world born with that knowledge but devoid of the cognition-obliterating information overload that the tools engender. What kind of slow death constraints would bring focus to the real breakthroughs of modern life? A web without servers? Markets without cash or stocks? A regression, sure, but not a dark ages. An enlightened regression.&rdquo;</blockquote>
<p>From 2008&#8217;s <em><a href='http://danielsjourney.com/files/Movement_130_20-21.pdf'>The Antipocalypse: Documentation</a></em>, the last of the three-part <em>Antipocalypse</em> series. If you have an interest in clicking through, you might start with <a href='http://www.danielsjourney.com/files/Daniel%20Miller%20-%20The%20Antipocalypse.pdf'>Part 1</a> and <a href='http://www.danielsjourney.com/files/JohnnyCitizen_Antipoc1_1.pdf'>Part 1.1</a>. So nerdy with my numbering.</p>
<p class='date'>January 05, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>Incidentally, stupid technical bullshit has eaten my day today: Carissa is adjusting to her new Mac and reminding me how much Finder sucks and how keyboard-inaccessible Mac dialogs are. I accidentally re-created <a href='http://danielsjourney.com'>danielsjourney.com</a> as an empty website, not a huge loss these days---I had it recreated in a few minutes--but what a bonehead move. Even Markdown is giving me trouble with some quotes in this post and I had to hand-encode them. It&rsquo;s like the machine knows I&rsquo;m talking shit about it and is being passive-aggressive in return.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Dreams</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/04/dreams.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/04/dreams.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>It took a while for her to show up in my dreams, but apparently it&#8217;s started. Last night I had...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='G.O. Kimmell, gentleman, scholar, patriarch. 1913-2008. http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/5324515434/' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5243/5324515434_0b05fe1a59.jpg' />
<p>It took a while for her to show up in my dreams, but apparently it&#8217;s started. Last night I had a dream that we were having a party and she was there, and I was <strong>so</strong> happy and just held her and nuzzled her and she giggled that amazing giggle and was soft and perfect and beautiful and happy like always. I kept saying, &#8220;She&#8217;s back! She&#8217;s back!&#8221; in between big facefulls of her stomach and back and thighs.</p>

<p>I had to hand her off to Carissa and I was moving towards the door when my grandfather walked in. My confusion turned to comfort and he just sauntered in like he&#8217;d been there a hundred times. I said to whoever was standing next to me at the time, &#8220;There are dead people at my party and it&#8217;s making me happy.&#8221;</p>

<p>The dream didn&#8217;t really bother me when I first woke up, but its effects seem to be lingering. I&#8217;m not sure if writing this post is going to help or not. I&#8217;m trying to take it as a comfort. I probably just need to go ride my bike and then get focused on something else.</p>
<p class='date'>January 04, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">I love how xkcd can wrap a profound observation about meaning in a penis joke</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/03/pen15.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/03/pen15.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Also, if you have not seen Randall&#8217;s talk at Google, you should. djdc.connected = function() { $("img.callout").css({"max-width": "none", "padding": "5px"});...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='xkcd http://xkcd.com/842/' src='http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/mark.png' />
<p>Also, if you have not seen <a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zJOS0sV2a24'>Randall&#8217;s talk at Google</a>, you should.</p>
<script type='text/javascript'>
  djdc.connected = function() {
    $("img.callout").css({"max-width": "none",
                          "padding": "5px"});
  };
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Out with the old, in with the really old</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/01/out-with-the-old.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/01/out-with-the-old.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Happy Sounding Sad Songs is a record I released in 2007 under the name Johnny Citizen, a non de guerre...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object data='http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2217487435/size=grande3/bgcol=FFFFFF/linkcol=4285BB//' type='text/html' height='410' width='300'> </object></p>
<p><em><a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/album/happy-sounding-sad-songs'>Happy Sounding Sad Songs</a></em> is a record I released in 2007 under the name <em>Johnny Citizen</em>, a <em>non de guerre</em> I&#8217;d first ascribed to a fictional character in 2001. I&#8217;ve been meaning to put it on the web for free download for a while, and it just worked out that today is that day. Later this month I&#8217;m releasing a re-worked and re-arranged re-issue of my <em>Americana EP</em> as well.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve long wanted to explain some of the material on <em>HSSS</em>. I didn&#8217;t go into a lot of detail, but here is what I wrote about each track as well as my best guess about the year the song was written:</p>

<ul>
<li>Don&#8217;t Tell Me (2001): A break up song for someone you can&#8217;t break up with&#8211;an emotionally unavailable God. The extended ending has lyrics from the song that inspired this one, <em>Dig</em> by Adam Again:</li>
</ul>
<p><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_1'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/07%20Dig.mp3'>Adam Again - Dig</a></span></span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Painful Tired (2001): An ode to sleep deprivation.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>High Tonight (2003): Sometimes when a relationship is about to crash and burn, you just want to have one night where you forget about the giant piles of resentment and hurt and just enjoy each other&#8217;s company one last time before you go your separate ways. Incidentally, using &#8220;get high&#8221; as a metaphor is probably the best way for a metaphor to be mistakenly literally interpreted. The ending was originally an interpolation of Over the Rhine&#8217;s <em>Long Lost Brother</em>:</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_2'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20Long%20Lost%20Brother.mp3'>Over the Rhine - Long Lost Brother</a></span></span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Humanity&#8217;s Playbill (2003): The first verse speaks to various things in &#8220;our world&#8221;: A lover who can&#8217;t keep her promises but also can&#8217;t admit to not keeping them. &#8220;At the local megaplex by fools and drones&#8221; is a segue and is specifically about &#8220;The Passion of the Christ&#8221;, a movie that was receiving a lot of attention at the time. The next verse continues airing grievances against both modern faith and modern ideals: &#8220;We are like the birds&#8221; is a sideways reference to the &#8220;consider the ravens&#8221; parable. The streets of heaven as &#8220;fool&#8217;s gold&#8221; is mostly an inditement of those motivated not by love but by reward. The rest of the song is sung specifically at Jesus, with the &#8220;shouting over the din&#8221; unintentionally pairing with the line &#8220;I can&#8217;t hear unless you shout above the noise&#8221; from <em><a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/track/dont-tell-me'>Don&#8217;t Tell Me</a></em>.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>I Don&#8217;t Know What to do About That (2007): One of my favorite songs musically, and the newest song on the record, but the lyrics are strictly historical. Made by another to feel really poorly about myself, this was the song that came out. I like that the title line, at the time sung in desperation, is now a shoulder-shrug.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>I Radio Heaven: I cover a lot of Over the Rhine songs, but this was my favorite. We had fun with it. Here&#8217;s the original, for those who have never heard it:</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_3'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/05%20I%20Radio%20Heaven.mp3'>Over the Rhine - I Radio Heaven</a></span></span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sucker for Love (2003): This was the first song we recorded for the record. &#8220;Someone&#8230;to shove&#8221; is, of course, a reference to <a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OrrE5bCA5lg'>the classic Soul Asylum song</a>.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>Clich&#233; (2007): Ever been driven to madness by a love you shouldn&#8217;t have entertained in the first place? Ever keep pursuing it despite every person around you and every shred of rationality left in your brain telling you not to? Yeah, I have too.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>Beautiful and Tragic (2003): A song I wrote about Bosnia before I&#8217;d even moved there. The spoken word track is actually Polish. We didn&#8217;t know any Bosnians to call at the time. The lyrics reference U2&#8217;s <em>The Best of 1990-2000</em>, a record where the <a href='http://member.u2.com/discography/index/album/albumId/4076/tagName/Other'>Passengers</a> track <em><a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miss_Sarajevo'>Miss Sarajevo</a></em> comes just before <em>Stay</em>. &#8220;My wheels are spinning but I&#8217;m upside down&#8221; is a lyric off the latter:</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_4'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/Stay.mp3'>U2 - Stay (Faraway, So Close)</a></span></span></p>
<ul>
<li>American Dream Town (2002): A re-recording of a previously-released tune. A song about secret societies, plastic surgery and other interesting aspects of the American dream. Jason Roberts of <a href='http://www.happybullets.com/'>The Happy Bullets</a> wrote the ending, which I have always been chuffed about.</li>
</ul>
<p class='date'>January 01, 2011</p><script type='text/javascript'>  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/07%20Dig.mp3",  
        titles: "Dig",  
        artists: "Adam Again"});
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_2", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20Long%20Lost%20Brother.mp3",  
        titles: "Long Lost Brother",  
        artists: "Over the Rhine"});
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_3", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/05%20I%20Radio%20Heaven.mp3",  
        titles: "I Radio Heaven",  
        artists: "Over the Rhine"});
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_4", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/Stay.mp3",  
        titles: "Stay (Faraway, So Close)",  
        artists: "U2"});
  });
  djdc.connected = function() {
    $("#content_container object").css({"padding": "5px"});
  };
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Hi Beautiful</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/30/hi-beautiful.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/30/hi-beautiful.html</id>
    <updated>2010-12-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>You&#8217;ve likely seen it already, but Carissa posted this yesterday: &#8220;I was looking for a document and ran across an...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;ve likely seen it already, but <a href='carissabyers.blogspot.com'>Carissa</a> posted <a href='http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2010/12/hi-beautiful-book-for-margot.html'>this</a> yesterday: &#8220;I was looking for a document and ran across an old text. It was the book I was making for Margot, similar to the book I made for Penn. I can&#8217;t remember if I ever posted it. I hadn&#8217;t finished the pages yet. It is such an accurate description of us.&#8221;</p>

<blockquote>
<p>I spend my days holding her close with ideas that maybe I could put her back in. Keep her safe. Maybe if I rock her long enough I can encourage some sort of osmosis. Absorb her. And of course I am. Just not literally. I imagine a bubble around her. Dreams and love and ideas are spun like sugar around us.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>I spend my days kissing each roll beneath her chin, the back of her neck, the top of her head where the swirls of black hair spin out around and around and into a peak at the top. I run my lips across the corner of her mouth, across the hill of her cheek and down the bottom of her earlobe. I blow into her soft wrinkled bellybutton and kiss the backs of her fleshy thighs. Her hands and feet find their way into my mouth like magic. She is the softest thing that has ever existed.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>She burrows into my breast to nurse and heaves a sigh of contentment when we&#8217;re all settled in to one another. Her eyes close and her lashes are made from the delicate feathers of baby birds. I am swollen with longing. I pray to Father Time to keep us this way forever. Or at least a little while longer.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>When she cries in the arms of someone else I am pulled like a magnet. I am biologically wired to retrieve and protect but I don&#8217;t. I wait. Smile. Gently take her when she&#8217;s handed over and I coo and assure that it&#8217;s okay out there in the world. That I&#8217;ll always be here to come back to. Always. Always.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>When she cries in her Daddy&#8217;s cradle I wait longer. I whisper to her that her Daddy has never loved anyone more in the whole wide world and there are no arms better or safer for her to cry in.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>Her Daddy stands tall and roars at the world with brawn and willpower promising excruciating elements to any who might harm his precious baby. Just as easily he turns and nuzzles her with such gentleness, golden whiskers and bright blue eyes. &#8220;Hi, Beautiful.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>I spend my days holding her close and teaching her independence. Hoping I come upon some magical formula that can balance the two through the tornadoes of growing up. Hoping that someday she will be a woman, my daughter and my friend and we can sit back in our dreams and love and ideas, spun like sugar around us.</p>
</blockquote>
<p class='date'>December 30, 2010</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Gathering Gloom in the Stable Room</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/21/the-gathering-gloom.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/21/the-gathering-gloom.html</id>
    <updated>2010-12-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Last Sunday we had the privilege of attending The Dallas Family Band&#8217;s &#8220;christmas/carol-singing/merrymaking festivities&#8221; at Murray Street Coffee. There was...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by Kelsey Foster http://kelseyfoster.net' src='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/MG_9765.jpg' />
<p>Last Sunday we had the privilege of attending <a href='http://dallasfamilyband.com/'>The Dallas Family Band</a>&#8217;s &#8220;christmas/carol-singing/merrymaking festivities&#8221; at <a href='http://murraystreetcoffee.com/'>Murray Street Coffee</a>. There was also plentiful, tasty food provided by the attendees.</p>

<p>The Dallas Family Band is doing something very authentic and beautiful here, and it is an honor to know some of them, and experience their music. Sunday was no exception.</p>

<p>On Monday, <a href='http://thebeatensea.com/'>The Beaten Sea</a> released a Christmas single, <a href='http://purchase.thebeatensea.com/track/the-gathering-gloom-in-the-stable-room'>The Gathering Gloom in the Stable Room</a>, a song that somehow completely ignores decades of crap Christmas music and harkens to the classic Christmas hymns that had both real meaning and musical substance.</p>

<p>The Dallas Observer <a href='http://blogs.dallasobserver.com/dc9/2010/12/bonus_mp3_the_beaten_sea_--_th.php'>commented</a>:</p>
<blockquote>...a Christmas-themed tune penned by co-frontman Jamie Wilson called "The Gathering Gloom in the Stable Room" and featuring Wilson, his co-leader Benj Pocta and backing vocalist Ashley Myrick (known now to many around town under her own performance moniker, Lalagray) each taking turns on lead vocals. The song also features backing efforts from drummer Daniel Hall, Spooky Folk violinist Petra Kelly and Fox &amp; The Bird player Wheeler Sparks.<br /><br />It's a classic-sounding tune, filled with spiritual lyricism and the same kind of authenticity heard throughout the rest of the band's catalog...[and] the first recorded in the band's new home studios in Deep Ellum...</blockquote>
<p><a href='http://purchase.thebeatensea.com/track/the-gathering-gloom-in-the-stable-room'>Go pick it up</a>.</p>
<p class='date'>December 21, 2010</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Refugees</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/13/the-refugees.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/13/the-refugees.html</id>
    <updated>2010-12-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Andrew Solomon - The Refugees Last week was a pretty bad week emotionally/spiritually. I&#8217;m not really sure why, it could...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_1'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20Andrew%20Solomon_%20The%20Refugees.mp3'>Andrew Solomon - The Refugees</a></span></span></p>
<p>Last week was a pretty bad week emotionally/spiritually. I&#8217;m not really sure why, it could have been the pendulum swinging back from my <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/08/boulder.html'>good time in Boulder</a> or the general <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear,_uncertainty_and_doubt'>FUD</a> both worldwide and locally. It might be the onset of the Christmas season and the fact that all good things are stained with this loss.</p>

<p>Saturday I had reason to drive to Fort Worth and on the way there and back I listened to <a href='http://www.themoth.org/'>The Moth</a> podcast of stories told at their various storytelling events. I was headed back when this one came up, a story told almost a decade ago by <a href='http://www.google.com/search?q=Andrew+Solomon'>Andrew Solomon</a>. I should warn you, what it describes is horrible and should only be heard at the right moment. Fortify yourself. But it is also a story of incredible strength and hope. I was somewhere in the <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mid-Cities'>Mid-Cities</a> when he finished and the whole thing washed over me at once&#8211;both an intense sadness and a weight-lifting, as if my own burden of sadness, pain and injustice briefly ascended to join with all those who also knew of it and more.</p>
<p class='date'>December 13, 2010</p><script type='text/javascript'>  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20Andrew%20Solomon_%20The%20Refugees.mp3",  
        titles: "The Refugees",  
        artists: "Andrew Solomon"});
  });
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Guests</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/10/the-guests.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/10/the-guests.html</id>
    <updated>2010-12-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='385' width='640'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/l48aOXWKx4E?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/l48aOXWKx4E?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='385' width='640' /></object></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">&amp;#9829; Boulder</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/08/boulder.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/08/boulder.html</id>
    <updated>2010-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Had the opportunity to visit Boulder, CO, for the first time last week and I immediately fell in love. From...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='# http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/tags/boulder/' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5289/5247302520_f49f2017e8.jpg' />
<p>Had the opportunity to visit Boulder, CO, for the first time last week and I immediately fell in love. From the <a href='http://www.illegalpetes.com/'>tacos</a> to the somehow always <a href='http://atlaspurveyors.com/'>excellent</a> <a href='http://tridentcafe.com/'>espresso</a> to the <a href='http://www.happynoodlehouse.com/TheBitterBar/tabid/464/Default.aspx'>fancy drinks</a> to the mountains. Mostly the mountains. Since moving away from Tucson at the end of 1997 I&#8217;ve only been in the (real) mountains a couple of times, and I&#8217;d forgotten how good they are for my soul.</p>

<p>Now I have a huge city crush on Boulder and am trying to figure out how to move there so I can go up into those mountains whenever I need sanity, peace or comfort.</p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5003/5247319516_f04fc7b527.jpg' alt='yes please' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5123/5245393700_ccf4cc7b59.jpg' alt='mountain lakes are fun' /></p>
<p class='date'>December 08, 2010</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
