<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>danielsjourney</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml" />
  <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2011-04-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>loss</subtitle>

  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Mofiasco</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/10/mofiasco.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/10/mofiasco.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I said in January that I should re-post this story. Took a while. I read a really amazing blog post...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='http://www.flickr.com/photos/nigel321/2254589407/ photo by Nigel Swales' src='http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2355/2254589407_4160be1ea0.jpg' />
<p>I <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/24/reamericana.html'>said in January</a> that I should re-post this story. Took a while. I read a really amazing blog post today and its narrative involved the Bosnian crisis, so it inspired me to finally re-post this. I&#8217;ll share that blog post tomorrow.</p>

<p>I should set the scene: August 2003. I&#8217;ve been in Bosnia since the beginning of April. I have recorded an EP, my first project since a CD I hastily put together my last semester in college in 1997. I have a band comprised of three Balkan misfits I already have a great affection for. My drummer, Elvis, also produced the EP. I have a &#8220;CD release&#8221; gig at the longest-established rock club in Sarajevo (it existed&#8211;in some form&#8211;during the siege). I&#8217;m leaving in the days following the gig for the Slovakian mountains&#8211;a vacation with my wife&#8217;s family&#8211;and the Greenbelt festival in the UK, where I have a gig. This is the day of the gig:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>So we have an ok rehearsal yesterday afternoon, I&#8217;m sure there will be some fuck ups tonight at the gig, but we&#8217;ll plow through them and in general rock, as long as there is a good crowd with some energy. I will definitely have NO voice after the gig. Just as well.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>After we were done, around 7:30, the guys took me to pick up the CD&#8217;s. I immediately got a bad feeling when I was no longer dealing with the guy I had been dealing with all along, but was picking up the CD&#8217;s from these two gangster-looking guys working out of their low-rider Benz. I got back in our car with the CD&#8217;s and immediately Elvis goes, &#8220;Were they mofia or what?&#8221; I said, &#8221;I&#8217;m never doing business with that guy again.&#8221; But I got my CD&#8217;s, they didn&#8217;t look half bad, so that was that. I thought.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>I got home and first thing stuck one in the CD player. I was never concerned about the music reproduction because, after all, this is now digital to digital reproduction, exactly like when you or I burn a CD on our computer: an exact copy, and you don&#8217;t have to be a techie to burn a CD on a computer, right? I was checking the disk more for skips or improper tracking (the pirated CD&#8217;s here are almost never tracked correctly, meaning &#8220;track 1&#8221; is the first song plus a split second of song 2&#8211;a major pain in the ass when you have your CD player on &#8220;random&#8221;)&#8230;&#8230;but I popped it in and immediately, within a second, could tell something was horribly wrong&#8230;</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>You&#8217;re thinking: &#8220;The CD contained Bosnian turbo-folk music!&#8221; NO! That, my friend, would have been great&#8211;at least some hilarity to go along with my shock, disappointment and confusion.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>The sound quality was simply horrible. It sounded like an analog recording reproduced 100 times (you know, like a tape of a tape of a tape &#8230; + 98 more times). My heart immediately sunk to the ground floor (we live on the 4th). I tried another one in disbelief&#8230;how could they fuck this up? &#8230;but it was exactly the same shitty quality. I had one of my 2 masters sitting right there, so I confirmed that it was fine; it was. I thought maybe the master I gave them was fucked up somehow, so I ran and grabbed it from the other room; it was fine too. I tried yet another CD off a different spindle and it was the same. I was fucked.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>I called M in hysterics, I didn&#8217;t even know where she was or if she was going to help me. It was almost 9pm on a Tuesday and I was alone in a city that loves to hate me, up against some mobsters who had just ripped me off.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>Now that was mostly just fucked right up the ass. Excuse my colorful metaphor. But this being the last minute and all, there was no fixing this problem in time.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>M was out somewhere, and she offered to help me out and asked if I wanted her friends to come with. I said, yeah, that might be good. I called the guy I got the CD&#8217;s from, told him the problem, and we decided to meet right away to talk about it. M came and picked me up and we went to where those friends were hanging out. One friend in particular is this older guy with tons of connections all over the city. He first called the guy I was dealing with&#8230;then things got a little out of control&#8230;</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>I just wanted some emotional backup, but I got a touch more than that&#8230;M&#8217;s friend called the kind of guys* everyone is afraid of, apparently. Already long story short, the 4 of us went up the restaurant with the CD&#8217;s, I explained to Jr. Gangster Kid the problem, he just shrugged his shoulders and said, &#8220;What do you want?&#8221; I said a refund, there was some hooing and hawing&#8230;and then, and this I did not see at all, only heard about it&#8211;those guys everyone is afraid of&#8211;showed up, they had just pulled their car into the parking lot, and within a few seconds I was getting my money back.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>I bought the CD sleeves from somebody else, so I now have 280 CD sleeves and no CD&#8217;s. Today I&#8217;m burning copies of the disk to take to GB, to at least give away to people. Funny thing is, I could&#8217;ve probly burnt the 280 in 2 days with my two burners&#8230;even with my shit software I could&#8217;ve done a better, faster job by myself, with just some CD labels, than this guy did. When I get back in September, I&#8217;ll start looking at companies in the States who do CD printing, and it will be the end of the year before I see any CD&#8217;s that way, but at least I know they&#8217;ll be OK.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>&#8230;the end&#8230;how things changed after that. I was actually back in the States in September, never to return to Bosnia again&#8230;</p>
<p class='date'>April 10, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>* They were known as the <em>gray eminence</em>, which I had never heard of at the time and thought sounded a bit funny but it turns out is a <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%89minence_grise'>real thing</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">...guess he was sleep golfing?</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/08/sleep-golfing.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/08/sleep-golfing.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I&#8217;ve had a couple of dreams lately about passing out on golf courses. Last night&#8217;s was really involved. I was...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='349' width='560'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/nr1XgsjL6HQ?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/nr1XgsjL6HQ?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='349' width='560' /></object></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve had a couple of dreams lately about passing out on golf courses. Last night&#8217;s was really involved. I was having to pay for my clothes having been dry cleaned while I was asleep. The bill was <span style='font-family: Georgia, serif'>$</span>170 and there were clothes in the bag that weren&#8217;t mine. While they were adjusting the bill and telling me it wasn&#8217;t going to make that much of a difference&#8211;there was some serious subtext from the staff that I was really being charged for spending the night at the golf course&#8211;I finally had the realization: if my clothes had been dry cleaned and lay now in front of me on the counter, what clothes was I wearing now and how did I get into them? At that point I think the dissonance was too much for the Dream Plot Generator and I woke up. It was a few minutes later that I remembered the Donnie Darko scene.</p>

<p>There&#8217;s a lot to unpack and not much of it is too mysterious, really. I&#8217;m just curious: why golf courses?</p>
<p class='date'>April 08, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>The beginning of this scene&mdash;when the jet engine falls through the house&mdash;always seems to me to be overacted by Maggie Gyllenhaal. Sure, the sky is falling&mdash;literally&mdash;but would that really reduce a 19 year old woman to cowering and tears? (The next sentence will make NO sense if you haven't seen the movie.) The only way my brain has been able to interpret that performance is that she had some precognition of the other/real timeline, and her reaction in this scene ties to the final scene when the plot's main timeline ends and you're returned to this point. I've thought about that final scene a lot lately.</p><p class='postscript'>Life's been pretty ok lately, actually. I want to share but none of the good things are shareable...yet. I thought my experience would make all other life stressors&mdash;good and bad&mdash;easier to navigate. It hasn't, really&mdash;those things are just as stressful as ever, it's just that they're relatively not a big deal. Monsters are smaller. Recovery is faster.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">(Anything but) Existential Indifference</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/02/existential-indifference.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/02/existential-indifference.html</id>
    <updated>2011-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I somewhat recently discovered Oliver Burkeman and have found his columns rather good. This week&#8217;s is no exception: &#8230;Garcin is...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='http://www.flickr.com/photos/92661859@N00/2311071031/ I like Mike Bitzenhofer&apos;s approach to existentialism: &apos;Eggistentialism&apos;' src='http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3129/2311071031_d977ff5c1c.jpg' />
<p>I somewhat recently discovered <a href='http://twitter.com/oliverburkeman'>Oliver Burkeman</a> and have found his columns rather good. This week&#8217;s is no exception:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&#8230;Garcin is having an existential crisis, as people tend to do in Sartre. (These days, he could just pick up a copy of <a href='http://www.purposedrivenlife.com/en-US/Home/home.htm'>The Purpose-Driven Life</a> and be done with it.) He&#8217;s facing the Big Question: how to deal with life&#8217;s apparent meaninglessness? Of course, many other philosophers, not to mention self-help gurus, would argue that life isn&#8217;t meaningless&#8211;that meaning&#8217;s to be found in family, or work, or spirituality. But intriguing new research suggests that, for a sizeable chunk of the population, a different answer to the Big Question may be more pertinent: who cares?</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href='https://www.readability.com/articles/00qcgokg'>&#8230;read the rest</a>.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve long been interested in meaning formation as a primary motivator of human behavior and a majority stakeholder in any person&#8217;s happiness (I&#8217;m a big fan of <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man&apos;s_Search_for_Meaning'>Frankl</a>). As I&#8217;ve tried to parse the recent events of my life, this is often the lens I use. I&#8217;m often confused by others who appear to have this existential indifference that Burkeman refers to. On one hand, I want to be able to move through life with more aplomb. On the other hand, it sure seems like a lot of us here sharing this planet just don&#8217;t care.</p>

<p>Of course existential crisis is not required to do important work. I have a friend who spends a lot of time thinking about how to work better and does excellent work partly due to that intention (he&#8217;s also just a hard worker). About a year age were discussing his strategies for maintaining focus and doing meaningful work&#8211;I was just starting work on <a href='http://todoblin.com'>Todoblin</a> and particularly interested (as I always am, really) in <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grok'>groking</a> how people work. I asked him, &#8220;Don&#8217;t you ever have moments of existential crisis?&#8221; He just kind of gave me a look that said something like, &#8220;You speak of this &#8216;existential crisis&#8217; like it&#8217;s something that actually happens to people.&#8221;</p>
<p class='date'>April 02, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">...lonely is healing if you make it</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/29/how-to-be-alone.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/29/how-to-be-alone.html</id>
    <updated>2011-03-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I feel like I&#8217;ve posted this already, I think because I&#8217;ve tweeted it twice now. It was good to be...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='390' width='640'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/k7X7sZzSXYs?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/k7X7sZzSXYs?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='390' width='640' /></object></p>
<p>I feel like I&#8217;ve posted this already, I think because I&#8217;ve tweeted it twice now. It was good to be reminded of it again today.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">&amp;ldquo;Real men go on&amp;rdquo;</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/24/real-men-go-on.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/24/real-men-go-on.html</id>
    <updated>2011-03-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>&#8230;real men tough it out in life, they get up and go on living despite setbacks&#8230;it takes maturity to deal...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by Rob Brewer http://www.flickr.com/photos/rbrwr/271634009/' src='http://farm1.static.flickr.com/82/271634009_6a2d67a360.jpg' />
<blockquote>
<p>&#8230;real men tough it out in life, they get up and go on living despite setbacks&#8230;<span>it takes</span> maturity to deal with the blows&#8230;</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href='http://blogs.dallasobserver.com/dc9/2011/03/bill_holstons_take_on_last_nig.php'>Bill Holston, paraphrasing Frank Campagna at Adam Carter&#8217;s memorial</a>.</p>
<p class='date'>March 24, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Michigan</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/23/michigan.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/23/michigan.html</id>
    <updated>2011-03-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>
Carissa posted pictures and a blog post about our trip to Michigan&#8230;
















March 23, 2011</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='# http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5550534620/in/faves-dealingwith/' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5296/5550534620_abe31267a7_z.jpg' />
<p>Carissa posted <a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/sets/72157626201223847/'>pictures</a> and a <a href='http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2011/03/michigan-2011.html'>blog post</a> about our trip to Michigan&#8230;</p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5263/5550536544_0c61bfae54_z.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5057/5549954813_11f8e24032.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5305/5550543436_d2522abfbb_z.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5179/5550545742_f859d2a244.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5022/5549968663_a83df64e9f.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5258/5550551220_738436bff4.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5030/5550553918_1aa9826f72_z.jpg' alt='' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5023/5549973637_6a55628cb1_z.jpg' alt='' /></p>
<p class='date'>March 23, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Determinedistic</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/22/determined.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/22/determined.html</id>
    <updated>2011-03-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Kings of Convenience - Scars on Land I&#8217;ve said before that there are certain questions that are now &#8220;best escorted...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_1'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/13%20Scars%20On%20Land.mp3'>Kings of Convenience - Scars on Land</a></span></span></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve said before that there are certain questions that are now &#8220;<a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/24/what-now.html'>best escorted out of the park by security</a>&#8221; &#8230;and maybe you noticed that was the first of a trilogy: &#8220;What now?&#8221; &#8220;<a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/28/I-can-not-go-on.html'>I&#8217;ll go on.</a>&#8221; &#8220;<a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/07/bikes.html'>Not because [I want] to but because [I have] to.</a>&#8221;</p>

<p>The problem with the deeper questions surrounding our loss and our lives is that they are the questions that have existed for all time and our answers&#8211;or lack thereof&#8211;are the same as well. The search for meaning evolves into a search to be more human, to connect to&#8211;not a Truth&#8211;but the truth of what it means to here with others.</p>

<p>So today I was reading some posts by my friend Kester Brewin and he wrote <a href='http://www.kesterbrewin.com/2011/03/15/free-will-determinism-heaven-hell/'>something that made a tiny bit of sense</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&#8230;we cannot prove if heaven and hell exist, but it&#8217;s a natural response to want the world to be fair, to be sorted out and judged at some point so that justice is done. A deterministic universe it might be&#8211;just chemicals and electrons&#8211;but this is not a world that we find &#8220;human&#8221; precisely because it makes a nonsense of ideas of love&#8211;and hate too.</p>
</blockquote>
<p class='date'>March 22, 2011</p><p class='postscript'><blockquote style='font-style:italic'>The weight of lead<br />
On floors of sand<br />
The idea reduced again<br />
To outcome<br />
<br />
No chain stays unbroken<br />
All aims get forgotten</blockquote></p><script type='text/javascript'>  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/13%20Scars%20On%20Land.mp3",  
        titles: "Scars on Land",  
        artists: "Kings of Convenience"});
  });
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Week That Was</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/21/the-week-that-was.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/21/the-week-that-was.html</id>
    <updated>2011-03-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>The last week in Michigan was awesome for so many reasons. The weather was perfect. I enjoyed being out in...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='photo by Carissa http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5541721448/in/set-72157626178939455/' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5091/5541721448_53e1c9a0f8.jpg' />
<p>The last week in Michigan was awesome for so many reasons. The weather was perfect. I enjoyed being out in the country. It reminded me very much of where I grew up in Pennsylvania. I enjoyed getting to know Carissa&#8217;s family more, including meeting relatives I&#8217;d never met before and seeing <a href='http://twitpic.com/4a2oe0'>where</a> Carissa&#8217;s brother and stepfather make their pizza ovens as well as <a href='http://maps.google.com/maps?q=buchanan+mi'>where</a> they are going to have their restaurant. We had <a href='http://twitpic.com/49wt4n'>fresh roasted</a> coffee every morning, either <a href='http://twitpic.com/49x0c7'>pour-over</a> or via their new industrial <a href='http://twitpic.com/4aou8e'>espresso machine</a>. We had <a href='http://twitpic.com/4a5fwr'>home-made pizza</a> one evening, made with home-made cheese, home-made dough, washed down with locally brewed <a href='http://twitpic.com/4a50w3'>10% IPA</a> (that might have made me a little bit belligerent&#8230;oops). We went to awesome stores and to the dunes by Lake Michigan. We ate homemade <a href='http://twitpic.com/4a395a'>crepes</a> for lunch&#8230;twice. After relatively painless drives/flights back we all quickly fell asleep Friday night. Penn slept for over 12 hours that night.</p>
<hr />
<p>Saturday was a day at the velodrome for me. At the <a href='http://superdrome.com/'>Superdrome</a> here in Texas you are required to take the developmental class, which is about 4 hours long. After that you are free to ride on the track during open track times or race (assuming you also obtain a racing license). I took a track developmental class in Pennsylvania&#8230;in 1994. Last time I rode on a track was (I think) 1996.</p>

<p>The beginning of the class was a little mind-numbing but an expected and necessary evil to get onto the track. The Superdrome is <a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/1423220549/in/set-72157602121750885/'>steeper</a> than anything I&#8217;d ridden before and did take some getting used to. But once open track was declared and I could take a couple laps at speed, I started to get hooked again. There is just nothing like the feel of the g-forces when really hammering through a turn on a velodrome. Especially one with turns that steep.</p>

<p>After the open track session we practiced <a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jCPfxsbp8Ig&amp;feature=related' title='Not at ALL as awesome as this one, but damn it is so beautiful to watch and gives you the idea'>pacelining</a> for 20 laps. Then we finished the day with a 10 lap <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scratch_race' title='&quot;A scratch race is a cycling race in which all contestants start from scratch (on equal terms)&quot;'>scratch</a>* race, which I won! Back in 1994 I won the developmental class race, too, and I was hooked. I feel the same things now, just with the more weathered enthusiasm and caution of age.</p>

<p>Sunday, possibly inspired by Saturday&#8217;s tiny success, I rode to the morning ride in Oak Cliff, then lobbied for a longer route than normal. The combination allowed me to break the 50 mile mark for the first time in 15 or so years.</p>
<hr />
<p>While we were in Michigan I just couldn&#8217;t stop thinking about Margot. How much she would have loved it there and loved meeting her extended family and hanging out with them. There are so many things that are continuously covered with the smell of loss. Things I wanted her to experience, things I wanted to experience with her. Things that while enjoyable, were made alive in an unfathomable way for me with her there, and are now made dark with her absence.</p>

<p>When I ride I am traveling back in time. I am in a place she never inhabited. A place she couldn&#8217;t inhabit. I think that&#8217;s why I like it so much.</p>
<p class='date'>March 21, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>* I always thought it was a race <em>to</em> the scratch, or the line &ldquo;scratched&rdquo; across the track to indicate the finish line. Sounds more poetic to me.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">&amp;ldquo;quote&amp;hellip;unquote&amp;rdquo;</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/10/quotes.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/10/quotes.html</id>
    <updated>2011-03-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Alfred North Whitehead: An enormous part of our mature experience cannot not be expressed in words. In formal logic, a...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='# http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/5517585612/' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5011/5517585612_4fe37f046d.jpg' />
<p>Alfred North Whitehead:</p>
<hr style='clear: left; margin-top: 1.5em; border: 0px; background: transparent;' />
<blockquote>
<p>An enormous part of our mature experience cannot not be expressed in words.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr style='margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 1.15em' />
<blockquote>
<p>In formal logic, a contradiction is the signal of defeat, but in the evolution of real knowledge it marks the first step in progress toward a victory.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr style='margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 1.15em' />
<blockquote>
<p>Knowledge shrinks as wisdom grows.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr style='margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 1.15em' />
<blockquote>
<p>The deepest definition of youth is life as yet untouched by tragedy.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr style='margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 1.15em' />
<blockquote>
<p>The art of progress is to preserve order amid change and to preserve change amid order.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr style='margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 1.15em' />
<blockquote>
<p>There are no whole truths: all truths are half-truths. It is trying to treat them as whole truths that plays to the devil.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr style='margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 1.15em' />
<blockquote>
<p>We think in generalities, but we live in detail.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr style='margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 1.15em' />
<blockquote>
<p>I have suffered a great deal from writers who have quoted this or that sentence of mine either out of its context or in juxtaposition to some incongruous matter which quite distorted my meaning, or destroyed it altogether.</p>
</blockquote>
<p class='date'>March 10, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>I was searching for the Whitehead quote &ldquo;It is the business of the future to be dangerous&rdquo; about a year ago because of the DJ Spooky song <em>Synchronic Disjecta</em>.</p><p class='media'><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_1'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/02%20Synchronic%20Disjecta.mp3'>DJ Spooky - Synchronic Disjecta</a></span></span></p><script type='text/javascript'>  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/02%20Synchronic%20Disjecta.mp3",  
        titles: "Synchronic Disjecta",  
        artists: "DJ Spooky"});
  });
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Aw hell, let's keep talking about bikes</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/07/bikes.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/07/bikes.html</id>
    <updated>2011-03-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Yesterday I rode a brisk 47 miles, not the 60 mile Saturday morning training rides of 1995 Tucson, but something....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='from this post http://www.lagazzettadellabici.com/2011/03/photographs-from-archives.html' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5299/5509891000_48d275bf98.jpg' />
<p>Yesterday I rode a brisk 47 miles, not the 60 mile Saturday morning training rides of 1995 Tucson, but something. Today the only time my legs forgot their pain was when I was on the bike again. That&#8217;s one of the best things about bicycling.</p>
<hr />
<p>I&#8217;m not sure where I&#8217;m going with this blog. It&#8217;s feeling increasingly useless. I&#8217;m going to remove the link to it from my homepage because I&#8217;m getting a lot of emails from recruiters. Recruiters are hilariously coy and always require the wrong information. A friend asked the best question, &#8220;Are you ready?&#8221; I replied, &#8220;Work is good.&#8221; He echoed, &#8220;Work is good!&#8221; and sort of half threw his hands in the air. This is the best we do. If we were farmers we would be planting. If we were hunters we would be hunting. Not because we wanted to but because we had to.</p>

<p>What we do is make software. And software is best made by humans who understand each other (and by extension understand the people who use their software). Unless they&#8217;re miraculously made up of such humans, organizations make shitty software. Just an observation.</p>
<hr />
<p>Penn is sitting next to me doing his homework and just declared: &#8220;Don&#8217;t give me an idea! Give me a snack!&#8221; It was completely random. Before that he said, &#8220;Don&#8217;t think of bad things. Think of <strong>pancakes</strong>!&#8221;</p>
<hr />
<p>Back to bikes. I must confess. I spent the afternoon looking at porn. Bike porn.</p>

<p>The image to the left is from <a href='http://www.lagazzettadellabici.com/2011/03/photographs-from-archives.html'>this post</a>, which is full of pictures from pre-1990 era cycling. The era that I studied while riding and then racing in junior high and high school. I have a collection of cycling hats from that era; I&#8217;m not really sure how I got into hat collecting&#8230;they&#8217;re cheaper and take up less space than jerseys or bikes. I am pretty sure at one point I had a GiS cap. I might have worn it until it was too worn to wear or keep. But when I saw that GiS logo on that rider&#8217;s kit, I could smell my introduction to cycling. It is weird how the olfactory sense is the one most connected to memory, isn&#8217;t it? I could literally smell some combination of things I haven&#8217;t smelled in two decades, and in that brief memory was all the magic that was bike racing.</p>

<p>What probably happened was that moment released some happy chemicals in my brain and so I spent the rest of the afternoon trying to recreate that experience. In vain, of course&#8230;</p>

<p><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/sashae/2626635126/in/faves-dealingwith/'><img src='http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3097/2626635126_b860cdabfe_z.jpg' alt='GiS kit' /></a></p>

<p>But I did find this GiS jersey on Flickr. There&#8217;s also this <a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/sashae/2626636076/in/faves-dealingwith/'>Ariostea jersey</a>! And it turns out <a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/sashae/'>that Flickr account is some kind of magical gold mine for awesome retro (or otherwise) gear</a>&#8230;</p>

<p><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/sashae/2289870697/in/faves-dealingwith/'><img src='http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2293/2289870697_f2d663f178.jpg' alt='OMG Yamaguchi' /></a></p>

<p><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/pedalturista/2500148658/in/faves-dealingwith/'><img src='http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2207/2500148658_491c7fc0e7.jpg' alt='pink Nagasawa!' /></a></p>

<p><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/sashae/4689592172/in/faves-dealingwith/'><img src='http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1300/4689592172_8619f2d3f9.jpg' alt='Spectrum!' /></a></p>

<p>What you have to understand about a <a href='http://www.spectrum-cycles.com/'>Tom Kellogg</a> bicycle is it was a bike that&#8211;at least while I was in the Leigh Valley in mid-90&#8217;s&#8211;made an immediate statement about the quality of the rider who pedaled it. I was in Tucson in the same time frame and there it was a <a href='http://gilmourbicycles.us/'>Gilmour</a> that communicated the same thing.</p>

<p>Hilariously, I&#8217;ve had <a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/5440032097/'>the same bike for so long now that <em>it</em> gets retro points</a>. It is in fact so old I have to do some research to figure out its lineage.</p>

<p>Another funny thing is that I get the most cred, these days, for being able to do a <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Track_stand'>track stand</a>, which I learned over time while navigating the many traffic lights of Tucson, not at the track where I raced for a few years. As with most things in life, the hardest part of learning how to track stand is starting to learn how to track stand. After some initial mastery of it, it becomes ridiculously simple.</p>

<p>Back to jerseys for a moment. This one really makes me all fuzzy with nostalgia:</p>

<p><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/sashae/4230909099/in/faves-dealingwith/'><img src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4069/4230909099_fb0435d561.jpg' alt='Toshiba jersey' /></a></p>

<p>Maybe now that I&#8217;m an adult I&#8217;ll start collecting frames instead of caps. Spectrums and Gilmours and LeMonds and Sachs and my old Klein. Oh and a <a href='http://fastboycycles.com/'>Fast Boy</a>, of course. I&#8217;ll get one of these to actually ride:</p>

<p><a href='http://prollyisnotprobably.com/2011/02/2011_nahbs_recon_kirk_framewor.php'><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5053/5479836041_52a85770b4_z.jpg' alt='Dave Kirk Terraplane' /></a></p>

<p>(<a href='http://redkiteprayer.com/?p=1772'>Here&#8217;s why</a>.) I have more to show and tell about bicycling and bicycle racing but this post is long enough already. Here are some more images just for fun:</p>

<p><a href='http://prollyisnotprobably.com/2011/03/recent_roll_god_is_in_the_deta.php'><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5211/5496071714_733aa65ce8.jpg' alt='Priorities' /></a></p>

<p><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/manyjourneys/5200068405/in/faves-dealingwith/'><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5129/5200068405_30ba3a29d2_z.jpg' alt='Oh shit!' /></a></p>

<p>The former above is for after the latter. Yikes! And I leave you with this <a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/actu24/3386649913/in/faves-dealingwith/'>link to a picture of Eddy Merckx signing a poster in a butcher shop, which I love for some reason</a>.</p>
<p class='date'>March 07, 2011</p><p class='postscript' />]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">You must go on, I can't go on, I'll go on.</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/28/I-can-not-go-on.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/28/I-can-not-go-on.html</id>
    <updated>2011-02-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I said I might have gained &#8220;the ability to let that which does not matter truly slide&#8221; but I&#8217;m not...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='photo by yours truly http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/5487718406/' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5018/5487718406_8dcbb88dfe.jpg' />
<p>I said I might have gained &#8220;the ability to let that which does not matter truly slide&#8221; but I&#8217;m not so sure that is the case. Little things and big things alike will derail me for hours if not days. I guess big things should all be small things now simply by sake of comparison, or by the way my stress and pain scale has been radically recalibrated. Maybe that will be the case in time, but right now I still just feel like my skin is raw. Every little bump or brush up against something causes my pain sensors to overload, preventing my brain to think about anything else and having me reaching for the medicine cabinet.</p>

<p>In terms of determining what is and is not important, that sensor feels like it&#8217;s been reset. I&#8217;ve lost the person that was the most important, that made anything else meaningful. The person that made all the time and pain prior to her arrival worth it. With her gone, it&#8217;s hard to consider anything worth doing or meaningful. She was my grace, and now my grace is gone.</p>
<p class='date'>February 28, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>The title quote is Samuel Beckett, via John Ralston, whose <a href='http://johnralston.bandcamp.com/'>new record you should purchase</a>, posthaste.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">What Now?</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/24/what-now.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/24/what-now.html</id>
    <updated>2011-02-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>There are many obvious questions in my situation, most of which cycle through my mind like a ferris wheel, each...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='I keep banging my head against the bottom of this question but nothing ever comes popping out of the top. Photo by Bob Prosser http://www.flickr.com/photos/44986108@N00/5032931614/' src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4129/5032931614_a60572eaf6_z.jpg' />
<p>There are many obvious questions in my situation, most of which cycle through my mind like a ferris wheel, each taking their turn stopped in the loading and unloading area. <em>Why?</em> is one <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/09/05/why.html'>I&#8217;ve mentioned before</a>; I have to some extent decided that question is best escorted out of the park by security. <em>What now?</em> however, that one has made a couple trips around now. I wonder if when that one has left the ride if maybe the ride won&#8217;t stop going around for a while. That would be nice.</p>

<p>On one hand, so many things haven&#8217;t changed. My personality hasn&#8217;t changed that much&#8211;at least not that I can tell. I&#8217;m not more patient or kind or understanding. I&#8217;m not significantly less vain. I&#8217;m not more or less secure.</p>

<p>Some things have changed for the worse. There are now a thousand triggers that might make something in my brain misfire. I care less about what other people think. I drop the f-bomb with more frequency and drink more than I used to&#8230;and I was pretty bad on both counts already.</p>

<p>One thing that <em>might</em> have changed for the better is, in the words Jim Uhls added to <em>Fight Club</em>, the ability to let that which does not matter truly slide.</p>

<p>So what now? There is never any way but forward. Life is shit and life is sweet. We all know that. You just don&#8217;t know how sweet yours is.*</p>

<p><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/33602849@N00/63732753/'><img src='http://farm1.static.flickr.com/29/63732753_ac69ceb2d2.jpg' alt='Question mark bomb image by niznoz' /></a></p>
<p class='date'>February 24, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>*Ha ha. No. You really don't.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">When in Doubt, Ride Hard</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/20/ride.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/20/ride.html</id>
    <updated>2011-02-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Today I rode for the 5th day in a row. It probably would have been 10 days except for last...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='http://www.flickr.com/photos/silverfingers/2462014101/in/faves-dealingwith/ Photo by Hans Hamburger' src='http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2384/2462014101_8fed19efb6.jpg' />
<p>Today I rode for the 5th day in a row. It probably would have been 10 days except for last Monday and Tuesday off due to two separate TMI ailments. And I must have really &#8220;misunderestimated&#8221; the previous four days because today kicked my ass in the best way possible.</p>

<p>Sunday mornings I&#8217;ve acquired the habit of riding with the group out of <a href='http://ocbicycleco.com/'>Oak Cliff Bicycle Company</a>, probably the only non-pretentious shop or group ride in town. But it&#8217;s <em>hilly</em> and pretty <em>fast</em> and is a great way to take the legs to their limit especially if, like I did today, you&#8217;ve left yourself with not-really-enough left in your legs for such a ride.</p>

<p>So I&#8217;ve had the odd pleasure of existing for the rest of my day in an odd haze and <a href='http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=5102364950'>as Phil Liggett would say</a> &#8220;legs [that] have turned to rubber&#8221;.</p>
<hr />
<p>I&#8217;ve wanted a couple of times to re-post about <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/24/fast-boy.html'>Fast Boy</a>. His blog and our occasional email correspondence have been a great encouragement to me. Although our pain is very different it is similar in its mere existence. He travels through his with an aplomb that is well summed up with this excerpt from <a href='http://www.fastboycycles.com/teachingcancertocry/?p=601'>his latest post</a>. It is also such an eloquent description of the dichotomy that is the pain-addled life:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>I hate this pattern of bringing you ever more pitiful news. I sometimes hesitate to write at all, and yet the point is to document this bloody process.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>Meanwhile, strangely, I find that I am ever more aware of just how much I love my life. My mind is going at warp speed with ideas.. I&#8217;m excited about getting back to building bikes, but also about lots of other things. I love making these food videos! I&#8217;ve got some music video work coming up that&#8217;s awfully exciting. There are things that I want to write, pieces of hardware that I want to design. Places I want to go.. and yet I&#8217;m falling asleep writing this entry. I&#8217;m beat. I&#8217;m tired. I hurt. It is unbelievably frustrating.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>Tonight I will make fish cakes.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr /><p class='date'>February 20, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Winter's Over?</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/19/winter.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/19/winter.html</id>
    <updated>2011-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Six months and six days. That&#8217;s how long it&#8217;s been. The six month mark passed without event, in fact even...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='http://www.flickr.com/photos/movito/5361359983/ photo by Fredrik Matheson, who I wish I knew in real life.' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5086/5361359983_6cba68a10c.jpg' />
<p>Six months and six days. That&#8217;s how long it&#8217;s been. The six month mark passed without event, in fact even the 14th was pretty good, we even had a <a href='https://www.facebook.com/pages/Wheeler-Sparks/334053513499'>rock star dinner guest</a>. Tuesday it all fell apart. Wednesday was back to just ok. And so it goes. Now it&#8217;s already Saturday in a WTF kind of speed.</p>

<p>The temperatures have risen to the 80&#8217;s and even though ride preparation takes a few fewer seconds and there&#8217;s less nose blowing during rides*, it feels far, far too soon. Winters are a quiet kind of sad and still. In a way that was helpful. My soul&#8217;s not renewing, so why should the Earth? Anyway, seems all it means is bugs and sweat and wind.</p>

<p>I want to give some kind of meaningful update or information, but everything I&#8217;ve already said still holds true. <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/09/02/in-order-to-remember-we-must-first-forget.html'>Being reminded of her, or the event, or the loss&#8230;any reminders still must be avoided</a>, the pain is still so debilitating. <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/09/29/motivation-mood.html'>Motivation is still elusive</a>. <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/26/dislikes.html'>Your shit is still really fucking petty</a> and I still really don&#8217;t want to see your babies.</p>

<p>It still seems like I&#8217;m just beating off depression and pain and (honest) sadness and resentment like it&#8217;s my full time job. I just want my daughter back. I just want to be a daddy again. I just want my life back.</p>
<p class='date'>February 19, 2011</p><p class='postscript'>* There are also a lot more people out riding around the lake, which is so annoying.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Super Bowl</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/07/super-bowl.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/07/super-bowl.html</id>
    <updated>2011-02-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I wonder where I fit in the scheme of things. Especially while I am out riding my bike&#8230;which I do...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by Arnoooo http://www.flickr.com/photos/studiobeeldruis/2636723848/' src='http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3258/2636723848_4b3c9474e0.jpg' />
<blockquote>
<p>I wonder where I fit in the scheme of things. Especially while I am out riding my bike&#8230;which I do almost like a religion nowadays. Compelled somehow, but wrapped in a fear and a certainty that this is a fool&#8217;s paradise. I am visited day and night with memories, and no good ones, reenactments of days of pain long passed by.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>There may never be another super bowl for me. But death calls out, and life refuses to hear. <strong>It is all wasted on thirty second commercials, selling things no living man has any need of, only dead men spend their money so stupidly.</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>&#8211; <a href='http://www.alexigrewal.com/index.php/blog/122-super-bowl'>Alexi Grewal</a></p>
<hr />
<blockquote>
<p>Two weeks ago, Grewal took part in Wheat Ridge Cyclery&#8217;s Crooked Roubaix, his first competitive event since his retirement. Despite riding a mountain bike, flat pedals and hiking boots, Grewal finished the 90-mile gran fondo-style high-altitude event on dirt and paved roads in the leading group, crossing the line in fourth place out of a field of some 125 starters.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>&#8211; <a href='http://velonews.competitor.com/2010/09/news/inside-cycling-with-john-wilcockson-alexi-grewal-is-deadly-serious-about-comeback_142905'>Alexi Grewal comeback</a></p>
<hr />
<p>I had a long post composed in my mind about how last night&#8217;s spectacle made me lose all hope for humanity, as <a href='http://www.google.com/search?q=groupon+super+bowl+commercial' title='and that was only one example of many'>the commercials proved we  no longer have any compassion for our fellow man</a> and the players (and I assume fans) credited God for their good plays. We believe He has an opinion on the matter of sports performance but not, apparently, on human suffering. I also have planned a long post about cycling and the dark cloud that currently looms over its greatest spectacles. I still might write the latter. In the meantime, I am happy to turn this post about the Super Bowl into a post about cycling.</p>
<hr />
<blockquote>
<p>Maybe this whole doping issue is here to turn us from our own selfishness to see that we have not as yet realized that the bicycle and bicycle racing has a purpose and meaning we have yet to even think about or care to understand. I think we are missing the real reality of what we have in the bicycle and in the racing of it.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>&#8211; <a href='http://velonews.competitor.com/2008/04/news/an-essay-by-1984-olympic-gold-medalist-alexi-grewal_74053'>Alexi Grewal</a> (again)</p>
<p class='date'>February 07, 2011</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
