<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>danielsjourney</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml" />
  <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2011-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>loss</subtitle>

  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Out with the old, in with the really old</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/01/out-with-the-old.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/01/out-with-the-old.html</id>
    <updated>2011-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Happy Sounding Sad Songs is a record I released in 2007 under the name Johnny Citizen, a non de guerre...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object data='http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2217487435/size=grande3/bgcol=FFFFFF/linkcol=4285BB//' type='text/html' height='410' width='300'> </object></p>
<p><em><a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/album/happy-sounding-sad-songs'>Happy Sounding Sad Songs</a></em> is a record I released in 2007 under the name <em>Johnny Citizen</em>, a <em>non de guerre</em> I&#8217;d first ascribed to a fictional character in 2001. I&#8217;ve been meaning to put it on the web for free download for a while, and it just worked out that today is that day. Later this month I&#8217;m releasing a re-worked and re-arranged re-issue of my <em>Americana EP</em> as well.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve long wanted to explain some of the material on <em>HSSS</em>. I didn&#8217;t go into a lot of detail, but here is what I wrote about each track as well as my best guess about the year the song was written:</p>

<ul>
<li>Don&#8217;t Tell Me (2001): A break up song for someone you can&#8217;t break up with&#8211;an emotionally unavailable God. The extended ending has lyrics from the song that inspired this one, <em>Dig</em> by Adam Again:</li>
</ul>
<p><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_1'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/07%20Dig.mp3'>Adam Again - Dig</a></span></span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Painful Tired (2001): An ode to sleep deprivation.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>High Tonight (2003): Sometimes when a relationship is about to crash and burn, you just want to have one night where you forget about the giant piles of resentment and hurt and just enjoy each other&#8217;s company one last time before you go your separate ways. Incidentally, using &#8220;get high&#8221; as a metaphor is probably the best way for a metaphor to be mistakenly literally interpreted. The ending was originally an interpolation of Over the Rhine&#8217;s <em>Long Lost Brother</em>:</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_2'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20Long%20Lost%20Brother.mp3'>Over the Rhine - Long Lost Brother</a></span></span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Humanity&#8217;s Playbill (2003): The first verse speaks to various things in &#8220;our world&#8221;: A lover who can&#8217;t keep her promises but also can&#8217;t admit to not keeping them. &#8220;At the local megaplex by fools and drones&#8221; is a segue and is specifically about &#8220;The Passion of the Christ&#8221;, a movie that was receiving a lot of attention at the time. The next verse continues airing grievances against both modern faith and modern ideals: &#8220;We are like the birds&#8221; is a sideways reference to the &#8220;consider the ravens&#8221; parable. The streets of heaven as &#8220;fool&#8217;s gold&#8221; is mostly an inditement of those motivated not by love but by reward. The rest of the song is sung specifically at Jesus, with the &#8220;shouting over the din&#8221; unintentionally pairing with the line &#8220;I can&#8217;t hear unless you shout above the noise&#8221; from <em><a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/track/dont-tell-me'>Don&#8217;t Tell Me</a></em>.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>I Don&#8217;t Know What to do About That (2007): One of my favorite songs musically, and the newest song on the record, but the lyrics are strictly historical. Made by another to feel really poorly about myself, this was the song that came out. I like that the title line, at the time sung in desperation, is now a shoulder-shrug.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>I Radio Heaven: I cover a lot of Over the Rhine songs, but this was my favorite. We had fun with it. Here&#8217;s the original, for those who have never heard it:</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_3'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/05%20I%20Radio%20Heaven.mp3'>Over the Rhine - I Radio Heaven</a></span></span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sucker for Love (2003): This was the first song we recorded for the record. &#8220;Someone&#8230;to shove&#8221; is, of course, a reference to <a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OrrE5bCA5lg'>the classic Soul Asylum song</a>.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>Clich&#233; (2007): Ever been driven to madness by a love you shouldn&#8217;t have entertained in the first place? Ever keep pursuing it despite every person around you and every shred of rationality left in your brain telling you not to? Yeah, I have too.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>Beautiful and Tragic (2003): A song I wrote about Bosnia before I&#8217;d even moved there. The spoken word track is actually Polish. We didn&#8217;t know any Bosnians to call at the time. The lyrics reference U2&#8217;s <em>The Best of 1990-2000</em>, a record where the <a href='http://member.u2.com/discography/index/album/albumId/4076/tagName/Other'>Passengers</a> track <em><a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miss_Sarajevo'>Miss Sarajevo</a></em> comes just before <em>Stay</em>. &#8220;My wheels are spinning but I&#8217;m upside down&#8221; is a lyric off the latter:</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_4'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/Stay.mp3'>U2 - Stay (Faraway, So Close)</a></span></span></p>
<ul>
<li>American Dream Town (2002): A re-recording of a previously-released tune. A song about secret societies, plastic surgery and other interesting aspects of the American dream. Jason Roberts of <a href='http://www.happybullets.com/'>The Happy Bullets</a> wrote the ending, which I have always been chuffed about.</li>
</ul>
<p class='date'>January 01, 2011</p><script type='text/javascript'>  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/07%20Dig.mp3",  
        titles: "Dig",  
        artists: "Adam Again"});
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_2", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20Long%20Lost%20Brother.mp3",  
        titles: "Long Lost Brother",  
        artists: "Over the Rhine"});
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_3", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/05%20I%20Radio%20Heaven.mp3",  
        titles: "I Radio Heaven",  
        artists: "Over the Rhine"});
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_4", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/Stay.mp3",  
        titles: "Stay (Faraway, So Close)",  
        artists: "U2"});
  });
  djdc.connected = function() {
    $("#content_container object").css({"padding": "5px"});
  };
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Hi Beautiful</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/30/hi-beautiful.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/30/hi-beautiful.html</id>
    <updated>2010-12-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>You&#8217;ve likely seen it already, but Carissa posted this yesterday: &#8220;I was looking for a document and ran across an...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;ve likely seen it already, but <a href='carissabyers.blogspot.com'>Carissa</a> posted <a href='http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2010/12/hi-beautiful-book-for-margot.html'>this</a> yesterday: &#8220;I was looking for a document and ran across an old text. It was the book I was making for Margot, similar to the book I made for Penn. I can&#8217;t remember if I ever posted it. I hadn&#8217;t finished the pages yet. It is such an accurate description of us.&#8221;</p>

<blockquote>
<p>I spend my days holding her close with ideas that maybe I could put her back in. Keep her safe. Maybe if I rock her long enough I can encourage some sort of osmosis. Absorb her. And of course I am. Just not literally. I imagine a bubble around her. Dreams and love and ideas are spun like sugar around us.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>I spend my days kissing each roll beneath her chin, the back of her neck, the top of her head where the swirls of black hair spin out around and around and into a peak at the top. I run my lips across the corner of her mouth, across the hill of her cheek and down the bottom of her earlobe. I blow into her soft wrinkled bellybutton and kiss the backs of her fleshy thighs. Her hands and feet find their way into my mouth like magic. She is the softest thing that has ever existed.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>She burrows into my breast to nurse and heaves a sigh of contentment when we&#8217;re all settled in to one another. Her eyes close and her lashes are made from the delicate feathers of baby birds. I am swollen with longing. I pray to Father Time to keep us this way forever. Or at least a little while longer.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>When she cries in the arms of someone else I am pulled like a magnet. I am biologically wired to retrieve and protect but I don&#8217;t. I wait. Smile. Gently take her when she&#8217;s handed over and I coo and assure that it&#8217;s okay out there in the world. That I&#8217;ll always be here to come back to. Always. Always.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>When she cries in her Daddy&#8217;s cradle I wait longer. I whisper to her that her Daddy has never loved anyone more in the whole wide world and there are no arms better or safer for her to cry in.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>Her Daddy stands tall and roars at the world with brawn and willpower promising excruciating elements to any who might harm his precious baby. Just as easily he turns and nuzzles her with such gentleness, golden whiskers and bright blue eyes. &#8220;Hi, Beautiful.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>I spend my days holding her close and teaching her independence. Hoping I come upon some magical formula that can balance the two through the tornadoes of growing up. Hoping that someday she will be a woman, my daughter and my friend and we can sit back in our dreams and love and ideas, spun like sugar around us.</p>
</blockquote>
<p class='date'>December 30, 2010</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Gathering Gloom in the Stable Room</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/21/the-gathering-gloom.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/21/the-gathering-gloom.html</id>
    <updated>2010-12-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Last Sunday we had the privilege of attending The Dallas Family Band&#8217;s &#8220;christmas/carol-singing/merrymaking festivities&#8221; at Murray Street Coffee. There was...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by Kelsey Foster http://kelseyfoster.net' src='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/MG_9765.jpg' />
<p>Last Sunday we had the privilege of attending <a href='http://dallasfamilyband.com/'>The Dallas Family Band</a>&#8217;s &#8220;christmas/carol-singing/merrymaking festivities&#8221; at <a href='http://murraystreetcoffee.com/'>Murray Street Coffee</a>. There was also plentiful, tasty food provided by the attendees.</p>

<p>The Dallas Family Band is doing something very authentic and beautiful here, and it is an honor to know some of them, and experience their music. Sunday was no exception.</p>

<p>On Monday, <a href='http://thebeatensea.com/'>The Beaten Sea</a> released a Christmas single, <a href='http://purchase.thebeatensea.com/track/the-gathering-gloom-in-the-stable-room'>The Gathering Gloom in the Stable Room</a>, a song that somehow completely ignores decades of crap Christmas music and harkens to the classic Christmas hymns that had both real meaning and musical substance.</p>

<p>The Dallas Observer <a href='http://blogs.dallasobserver.com/dc9/2010/12/bonus_mp3_the_beaten_sea_--_th.php'>commented</a>:</p>
<blockquote>...a Christmas-themed tune penned by co-frontman Jamie Wilson called "The Gathering Gloom in the Stable Room" and featuring Wilson, his co-leader Benj Pocta and backing vocalist Ashley Myrick (known now to many around town under her own performance moniker, Lalagray) each taking turns on lead vocals. The song also features backing efforts from drummer Daniel Hall, Spooky Folk violinist Petra Kelly and Fox &amp; The Bird player Wheeler Sparks.<br /><br />It's a classic-sounding tune, filled with spiritual lyricism and the same kind of authenticity heard throughout the rest of the band's catalog...[and] the first recorded in the band's new home studios in Deep Ellum...</blockquote>
<p><a href='http://purchase.thebeatensea.com/track/the-gathering-gloom-in-the-stable-room'>Go pick it up</a>.</p>
<p class='date'>December 21, 2010</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Refugees</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/13/the-refugees.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/13/the-refugees.html</id>
    <updated>2010-12-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Andrew Solomon - The Refugees Last week was a pretty bad week emotionally/spiritually. I&#8217;m not really sure why, it could...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_1'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20Andrew%20Solomon_%20The%20Refugees.mp3'>Andrew Solomon - The Refugees</a></span></span></p>
<p>Last week was a pretty bad week emotionally/spiritually. I&#8217;m not really sure why, it could have been the pendulum swinging back from my <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/08/boulder.html'>good time in Boulder</a> or the general <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear,_uncertainty_and_doubt'>FUD</a> both worldwide and locally. It might be the onset of the Christmas season and the fact that all good things are stained with this loss.</p>

<p>Saturday I had reason to drive to Fort Worth and on the way there and back I listened to <a href='http://www.themoth.org/'>The Moth</a> podcast of stories told at their various storytelling events. I was headed back when this one came up, a story told almost a decade ago by <a href='http://www.google.com/search?q=Andrew+Solomon'>Andrew Solomon</a>. I should warn you, what it describes is horrible and should only be heard at the right moment. Fortify yourself. But it is also a story of incredible strength and hope. I was somewhere in the <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mid-Cities'>Mid-Cities</a> when he finished and the whole thing washed over me at once&#8211;both an intense sadness and a weight-lifting, as if my own burden of sadness, pain and injustice briefly ascended to join with all those who also knew of it and more.</p>
<p class='date'>December 13, 2010</p><script type='text/javascript'>  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20Andrew%20Solomon_%20The%20Refugees.mp3",  
        titles: "The Refugees",  
        artists: "Andrew Solomon"});
  });
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Guests</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/10/the-guests.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/10/the-guests.html</id>
    <updated>2010-12-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='385' width='640'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/l48aOXWKx4E?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/l48aOXWKx4E?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='385' width='640' /></object></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">&amp;#9829; Boulder</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/08/boulder.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/08/boulder.html</id>
    <updated>2010-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Had the opportunity to visit Boulder, CO, for the first time last week and I immediately fell in love. From...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='# http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/tags/boulder/' src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5289/5247302520_f49f2017e8.jpg' />
<p>Had the opportunity to visit Boulder, CO, for the first time last week and I immediately fell in love. From the <a href='http://www.illegalpetes.com/'>tacos</a> to the somehow always <a href='http://atlaspurveyors.com/'>excellent</a> <a href='http://tridentcafe.com/'>espresso</a> to the <a href='http://www.happynoodlehouse.com/TheBitterBar/tabid/464/Default.aspx'>fancy drinks</a> to the mountains. Mostly the mountains. Since moving away from Tucson at the end of 1997 I&#8217;ve only been in the (real) mountains a couple of times, and I&#8217;d forgotten how good they are for my soul.</p>

<p>Now I have a huge city crush on Boulder and am trying to figure out how to move there so I can go up into those mountains whenever I need sanity, peace or comfort.</p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5003/5247319516_f04fc7b527.jpg' alt='yes please' /></p>

<p><img src='http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5123/5245393700_ccf4cc7b59.jpg' alt='mountain lakes are fun' /></p>
<p class='date'>December 08, 2010</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">The Infinitely Connected Triggers of Her Memory and the Dumb Machines of the Technopathocracy</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/29/connected.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/29/connected.html</id>
    <updated>2010-11-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Someday I want to be able to sit and look at her pictures, even watch the videos, and remember how...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Pattern image from Patrick Hoesly http://www.flickr.com/photos/zooboing/4580408068/' src='/images/puzzle.png' />
<p>Someday I want to be able to sit and look at her pictures, even watch the videos, and remember how great it was when she was here. For now, accidentally seeing a thumbnail image in a directory on my computer or on my phone or on Flickr or on Facebook is enough to spawn an hours-long cycle of anxiety and depression. But it&#8217;s not just the obvious things like pictures. Everything is connected to her. Each part of the house, each note of every song, an extremely large array of words that are spoken every day. Even a train of thought about something completely unrelated might get close enough to be drawn off the tracks by the cosmic magnet of her absence.</p>

<p>The <a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i3HyRtdu1o0'>technopathocracy</a> contributes more than just as a container for images that I might stumble upon. It actually goes out of its way to confront me with my pain. Facebook wants to show me &#8220;memories&#8221; in the sidebar. <a href='http://mint.com'>Mint</a> tracks a college fund that&#8211;until I worked up the energy to change it&#8211;bared her name. My mother, the angel, worked on all the medical bills and insurance paperwork while she and my father were in town last week; but now Mint sends alerts to my phone informing me that I have &#8220;High Spending&#8221; in &#8220;Doctor&#8221; &amp; &#8220;Health&#8221;. Old sound recordings still on my iPhone and synced to iTunes sit there waiting to be stumbled upon.</p>

<p>As discourteous as people can be, the machines are worse, they are just too dumb to understand. In a previous age the machines didn&#8217;t talk. Now they chatter on like children unaware of their words.</p>
<script type='text/javascript' charset='utf-8'>
    djdc.connected = function() {
      $("body").css("background","url('/images/puzzle.png')");
      $(".callout").css("opacity",".4").hover(function(){
        $(this).css("opacity","1");
      }, function(){
        $(this).css("opacity",".4");
      });
    };
</script><p class='date'>November 29, 2010</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Things That I Strongly Dislike More Now Than I Used To</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/26/dislikes.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/26/dislikes.html</id>
    <updated>2010-11-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>I thought maybe this experience was going to make me a better person in many respects, but in particular my...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by Nguyen-Anh Le http://www.flickr.com/photos/36751871@N00/446217012/' src='http://farm1.static.flickr.com/229/446217012_1d28cf9705.jpg' />
<p>I thought maybe this experience was going to make me a better person in many respects, but in particular my intolerance for certain things. Not so. In no particular order:</p>

<ul>
<li>People who leave voicemail. Not <em>everyone</em> who leave voicemails, but for example I was on a flight the other day and the guy next to me left the longest voicemail in the history of voicemails. It was so long I had to send Carissa a text message informing her of my bewilderment at his ability to monologue into a voice recording device. <em>However</em>, on the return flight of the same trip, another douchebag next to me, who must have become aware of the new Voicemail Message Length world record, proceeded to leave a voicemail <em>no shorter than</em> 10 minutes long! It was seriously unbelievable, and I had to continually challenge reality as he continued on and on. It was very much like the business douchebag on the plane in <a href='http://vod.fxnetworks.com/watch/louie/221105606001'>this Louie episode</a>, except much longer and as a message not a conversation.</li>

<li>Related: People who have jobs that mostly involve writing emails and still hunt-and-peck type.</li>

<li>People who use Twitter hashtags <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/search/%23stabmyself'>#stabmyself</a> and <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/search/%23FML'>#FML</a>. <a href='http://collecta.com/s/STFU'>STFU</a> and <a href='http://collecta.com/s/GTFOI'>GTFOI</a>.</li>

<li>Related: Drama Kings and Queens. Having struggled my way into a B in Evolutionary Psychology 15 years ago, I&#8217;m well aware that our lizard brain controls us for the majority of our day and our days are the most boring of all history. No tigers chasing us through the jungle, no rival tribes to compete with over food and quality mates, so we have to make our own drama to replace the lack of actual, life-threatening drama. The continued erosion of any real meaning in our lives has caused that drama to revolve around increasingly asinine subject matter.</li>

<li>Your driving. Protip: hang up the fucking phone.</li>

<li>Your causes. Are just more bad replacements for that tiger chasing you. If you enact real change in this world it isn&#8217;t going to be via your goddamn Facebook account.</li>

<li>Your children. Honestly. They are annoying and ugly (except when they&#8217;re perfect and beautiful but really it doesn&#8217;t matter) and worst of all (and I don&#8217;t mean this in the maniacal way it will sound) <em>still alive</em>.</li>

<li>The neighbor&#8217;s dog. He seriously will. not. stop. barking.</li>

<li>Opinions other than my own.</li>
</ul>
<p class='date'>November 26, 2010</p><p class='postscript'>Started this post a long time ago, but lately have spent enough time in the anger stage to finish it. I feel a little bit like I might punch Jesus if he walked up to me right now.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Give Thanks</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/25/give-thanks.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/25/give-thanks.html</id>
    <updated>2010-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Chris Holt - The Wind Has Left My Sail All youwhose whole familygathers around the tablegive thanks All youwho kiss...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_1'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/07%20The%20Wind%20Has%20Left%20My%20Sail%20mp3.mp3'>Chris Holt - The Wind Has Left My Sail</a></span></span></p>
<p>All you<br />whose whole family<br />gathers around the table<br />give thanks</p>

<p>All you<br />who kiss your sons<br />and daughters this day<br />give thanks</p>

<p>All you<br />burdened only by things<br />of this world, room and board<br />give thanks</p>

<p>All you<br />sent to sea by things<br />less than this, get over yourself<br />give thanks</p>

<p>All you<br />for whom death is an idea<br />who can argue for its machines&#8217; perpetuation<br />give thanks</p>

<p>All you<br />who can eat<br />or laugh<br />or sleep<br />or reason<br />or type<br />or speak<br />or listen<br />or breathe<br />or work<br />or think<br />without pain<br />give thanks</p>
<p class='date'>November 25, 2010</p><script type='text/javascript'>  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/07%20The%20Wind%20Has%20Left%20My%20Sail%20mp3.mp3",  
        titles: "The Wind Has Left My Sail",  
        artists: "Chris Holt"});
  });
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Thank You Chris</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/21/chris.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/21/chris.html</id>
    <updated>2010-11-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>The reason the Memorial record happened now instead of next year or never is because of Chris Holt. We planned...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Photo by Kate Mackley http://www.flickr.com/photos/katemackley/5078499695/in/photostream/' src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4130/5195708177_ab4bb4384c_o.jpg' />
<p>The reason <a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/album/memorial'>the Memorial record</a> happened now instead of next year or never is because of Chris Holt. We planned the Memorial service in just a couple of days, during a time that I can barely remember, and Chris was incredibly helpful during that time. His new record <a href='http://chrisholt.bandcamp.com/album/a-cosmic-joke'>A Cosmic Joke</a> wasn&#8217;t quite out yet, but he sent us a couple songs from it as possibilities to play at the memorial and we were just floored by them. He continued to go above and beyond by reworking the lyrics of <a href='http://chrisholt.bandcamp.com/track/always-in-awe'>Always in Awe</a>* and learning a new arrangement of <a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/track/ill-fly-away'>I&#8217;ll Fly Away</a> within about 24 hours.</p>

<p>I later told Chris I had a thought to create a collection of the songs played that night. A couple of weeks later he sent me a message that he had made arrangements with <a href='http://www.salimnourallah.com/'>Salim</a> to go into <a href='http://www.pleasantrylane.com/'>Pleasantry Lane</a> to record his tunes. It took a few weeks to finally get into the studio, during which time I sent messages to Doug, The Beaten Sea and Salim, who all agreed to participate in the project. Doug already had some acoustic recordings of the songs from <a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001Q8GBVM?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=wwwdanielsjou-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B001Q8GBVM'>The Shawl</a>. Salim recorded acoustic versions of his two songs during the sessions with Chris. And Benj from The Beaten Sea came in one night to record his version of <a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/track/adios-au-revoir-auf-wiedersehen'>Adios, Au Revoir, Auf Wiedersehen</a>, which will now forever win as most beautiful sad song of all time.</p>

<p>It even turned out that The Beaten Sea and I use the same mastering engineer, so he already had the original of <a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/track/its-hard-to-resist'>It&#8217;s Hard to Resist</a> that he could master to the same level as the rest of the record. Oh, and he donated his time to the project as well, despite never having met me in real life. The hardest part was deciding on a title, choosing between the four different cover art versions <a href='http://vladimirzimakov.com/'>Vladimir</a> sent (I included two in the download) and listening to the masters when they came back.</p>

<p>The record that means the most to me, I can&#8217;t even listen to.</p>
<p class='date'>November 21, 2010</p><p class='postscript'>* i.e., <a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/track/say-goodbye-always-in-awe'>the version on the Memorial collection</a> is one of a kind, available nowhere else. This is actually true of all the tracks on the record except one, but <span style='font-style:italic'>Always in Awe</span> is the only one with different lyrics than the original.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">&amp;ldquo;Memorial&amp;rdquo;</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/19/memorial.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/19/memorial.html</id>
    <updated>2010-11-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>There is a lot more to say about the why and the how of this record, but for now I&#8217;ll...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='Memorial cover art by Vladimir Zimakov http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/album/memorial' src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4147/5192182683_f4d53e64fb.jpg' />
<p>There is a lot more to say about the why and the how of <a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/album/memorial'>this record</a>, but for now I&#8217;ll just say this: It feels a little crassumer to say but it feels good when you buy this record. I had originally planned to offer the download for free but Bandcamp instituted free download limits since then so the $1 download charge just prevents me from having to worry about those limits. Since deciding to charge for it, my thoughts about the nature of the project changed a little bit and I really felt like I wanted to be able to give back to all the artists that participated in its creation. So when you buy the record, in this really weird way, it means it mattered to you too that these artists would contribute their valuable time and considerable talent towards this artifact of remembrance.</p>

<p><a href='http://danielmiller.bandcamp.com/album/memorial'>More info at the album page</a>.</p>
<p class='date'>November 19, 2010</p><p class='postscript'>I've embedded the player in the footer, in case you haven't clicked through already.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Our Stars No Longer Dance</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/18/our-stars-no-longer-dance.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/18/our-stars-no-longer-dance.html</id>
    <updated>2010-11-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Margot loved to dance. This song helps me believe she&#8217;s still dancing. It&#8217;s about Louis Armstrong. Sing to her for...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='385' width='480'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/4Dr0WgduMRo?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/4Dr0WgduMRo?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='385' width='480' /></object></p>
<p>Margot loved to dance. This song helps me believe she&#8217;s still dancing. It&#8217;s about Louis Armstrong. Sing to her for me, Louis.</p>
<p class='date'>November 18, 2010</p><p class='postscript'>Planning on releasing tomorrow the record of the music played at her memorial.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">This is about how it is these days</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/15/how-it-is-these-days.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/15/how-it-is-these-days.html</id>
    <updated>2010-11-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Thought of a good metaphor the other day: it&#8217;s like somebody walks in every hour on the hour and punches...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='344' width='425'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/aCaHM1d727E?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/aCaHM1d727E?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='344' width='425' /></object></p>
<p>Thought of a good metaphor the other day: it&#8217;s like somebody walks in every hour on the hour and punches you in the stomach. By late afternoon, you get tired of being punched in the stomach every hour and try doing something else. By early evening you decide to self medicate to try and calm the pain in your gut. By late evening the ache is keeping you up, daring you to go lie down and be quiet for a moment, long enough to not think about anything other than it.</p>

<p>This, of course, is an improvement from being constantly punched in the gut.</p>
<p class='date'>November 16, 2010</p><p class='postscript'>Did you know Houdini was killed by someone punching him in the gut? Houdini had claimed to be able to withstand anyone punching him in the stomach, so some douchebag bust into his green room back stage at a show and punched him repeatedly in the stomach while he was laying on a couch. <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_Houdini#Death'>Houdini died of peritonitis from a ruptured appendix</a>, apparently performing either earlier the same day or the day prior.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Waiting</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/13/waiting.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/13/waiting.html</id>
    <updated>2010-11-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>The Mountain Goats - Isaiah 45:23 I more frequently feel like the rest of my life is just a waiting...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_1'><a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/11%20Isaiah%2045_23.mp3'>The Mountain Goats - Isaiah 45:23</a></span></span></p>
<p>I more frequently feel like the rest of my life is just a waiting to be with her again.</p>
<p class='date'>November 13, 2010</p><script type='text/javascript'>  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/11%20Isaiah%2045_23.mp3",  
        titles: "Isaiah 45:23",  
        artists: "The Mountain Goats"});
  });
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Vetus</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/11/veteran.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/11/veteran.html</id>
    <updated>2010-11-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Mothers and fathersof those who won&#8217;t grow oldbecause of other men&#8217;s plansyou have someone to blameyou have someone to blame...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img title='photo by kT LindSAy http://www.flickr.com/photos/ktlindsay/2037459547' src='http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2402/2037459547_326be90f18.jpg' />
<p>Mothers and fathers<br />of those who won&#8217;t grow old<br />because of other men&#8217;s plans<br />you have someone to blame<br />you have someone to blame</p>

<p>Their hearts are so cold<br />they would kill your son<br />with a movement of their pen<br />and still you take their flag<br />and still you take their flag</p>

<p>They write you a letter<br />and shoot into the air<br />and celebrate today those who escaped alive<br />the riots of their murderous machinations</p>
<p class='date'>November 11, 2010</p><p class='postscript'><a href='http://www.warpoetry.co.uk/owen1.html' title='Dulce et Decorum est'>Wilfred Owen</a> does it infinitely better.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
