<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>danielsjourney</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml" />
  <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2011-07-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>loss</subtitle>

  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Vacation</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/07/28/vacation.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/07/28/vacation.html</id>
    <updated>2011-07-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>July 22nd Woke up at 6 and chatted with my brother-in-law Dale. I was up to go on a bike...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6145/5981717009_e24ba39336.jpg" title=""></p>

<p class="no-caps">July 22nd</p>


<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/5981719857/" title="photo by dealingwith, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6013/5981719857_1150fbbd7e.jpg" width="500" height="167" alt="photo"></a></p>

<ul>
<li>Woke up at 6 and chatted with my brother-in-law Dale. I was up to go on a bike ride while it was under 100 degrees and Dale was up to study for his CPA exam. We talked too loud over coffee and my sister Jan came out and scolded Dale.</li>
<li>Went on a 1.5 hour mountain bike ride around the trails on the 40 acre property we're staying on and the dirt roads of the area. Was chased by two different dogs. Rode a number of hills larger than what we call hills in Dallas.</li>
<li>Ran variations on the Marine-standard obstacle course installed on the property with Dale, Penn and my nephews Cade and Cody. Invented a leg-burning timed run that was a big hit.</li>
<li>Went on a 30 minute walk and chatted with my sister Jan.</li>
<li>Played a relatively epic game of hide-and-seek involving a decent amount of running for at least 30 minutes after dinner.</li>
<li>Did not drink.</li>
<li>Still went over my daily calorie allowance.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/5982280666/" title="photo by dealingwith, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6142/5982280666_4039236063.jpg" width="500" height="167" alt="photo"></a></p>

<hr>


<p>July 23rd</p>

<ul>
<li>Woke up at 6:15 and chatted with my brother in law again (this time about Macs). We kept it to a semi-whisper this time.</li>
<li>Rode about about 1 hour 40. The hills here are bigger and more frequent that in Dallas which is nice until you get tired. They're really more like big rollers but throw in a brisk south headwind and I'm feeling it a bit now. Chased by three dogs this time. Actually one of those times it was a pack of 3 or 4 dogs&mdash;fortunately I was traveling north at the time so I was moving pretty fast thanks to the tailwind. Besides the dogs, though, it is really nice to be riding out in the country with better views, cleaner air and fewer cars.</li>
<li>Went swimming in the pond. I had to talk myself into it but once I was in the water I was so glad I had. Fun!</li>
<li>Napped for 2 hours.</li>
</ul>


<p>Today looms. Margot would have been two years old today. When I said my riding is a shelter from her loss I was generalizing. I thought a lot about her on my ride today. After the pack of chasing dogs it was a bit of a relief to have my mind occupied with looking out for the next canine threat.</p>

<p>But God I just miss her so much. And I wish we could eradicate certain words from our vocabulary. And I wish you all were as raw as I am still so that when you said those words you felt that sting of pain. And I wish today would finally have come and gone for one more year. And I wish this family vacation didn't remind me so much of last year's family vacation, when she was there.</p>

<hr>


<p>July 24th</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/5981718835/" title="photo by dealingwith, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6013/5981718835_138e0701d3.jpg" width="500" height="374" alt="photo"></a></p>

<ul>
<li>Rode the mountain bike just around the property so as to avoid dogs. Got chased by neighbor's dogs anyway.</li>
<li>Walked and swam. I think the swimming is working new muscles in my arms and legs. Good thing.</li>
<li>Power napped. I could have done for another couple hours but my extended family came today and since half the point of being in Oklahoma is to see them, obviously I wasn't going to sleep through their visit.</li>
</ul>


<hr>


<p>July 25th</p>

<p>Woke up a little later than usual (a little before 6:30) to the sight of a wet driveway. The temperature was below 80 and while the humidity was high, it was like a miracle. I decided to head out on the wet roads and not wait another minute to see if the sun came out to dry them. In fact I was hopeful that the clouds would remain for the duration of the ride, which they did.</p>

<p>It was--despite being chased by dogs three or four times*--my favorite ride of the year. It reminded me of riding in Pennsylvania when I was a teenager. It's not hard to understand how I became attracted to the sport. I've been riding in the city for so long now that it actually took some time for me to adjust being out on an empty road, all by myself, with no other roads in sight. It's an introvert's perfect activity.</p>

<p>I was tentatively planning on riding about 50-60 miles but after making a wrong turn and diverting from my original route by five miles I improved a loop back and ended up with just a hair over 40.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/5981716365/" title="photo by dealingwith, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6028/5981716365_1af1dcb304.jpg" width="500" height="374" alt="photo"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/5982277200/" title="photo by dealingwith, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6001/5982277200_ab89c7bbfe.jpg" width="500" height="500" alt="photo"></a></p>

<p><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6129/5981695675_dd1907c58d_b.jpg" style="float:right;"></p>

<p class="postscript">* ...and even diverting once when I saw a giant loose German Shepard up the road--the road I diverted onto was the best of the ride. The best chase was a pair of terriers who never go closer than a few feet from me despite the fact I was climbing and going plenty slow for them to catch up. They followed me so far up that road I started to deviously wonder if I could lead them so far away they wouldn't be able to find their way home.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Lucy</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/07/20/lucy.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/07/20/lucy.html</id>
    <updated>2011-07-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Paul Slavens - Lucy As Lucy&rsquo;s presence becomes more real (we had another sonogram yesterday and she&rsquo;s healthy and moved...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_1"><a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/12%20Lucy.mp3">Paul Slavens - Lucy</a></span></span></p>


<p>As Lucy&rsquo;s presence becomes more real (we had another sonogram yesterday and she&rsquo;s healthy and moved a little bit for us while we watched in awe) I am forced to face the coming reality that there will be another beautiful girl in our house at the same time I will still (always) feel the loss of my first child. Even as I contemplated names this morning I thought, &ldquo;&lsquo;Margot Rose Miller&rsquo; was the perfect name. You can&rsquo;t top that.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t want to have any weird expectations on Lucy. But the part of my soul that needs this all to be woven into a mystical, meaningful narrative wants to feel like both Margot and Lucy are special and ordained, each with a place and purpose, things that from my perspective will always be linked.</p>

<p>Margot was already such an important person, not just because she was as beautiful and perfect as a baby can be. Margot was a miracle, she was redemption, she was the fulfillment of a decade&rsquo;s worth of desire&hellip;and that was only in her being. As she grew she became <a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/09/08/glue.html">exceptional</a> in even more, unexpected ways.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5954520607/" title="Lucy is 9 inches tall and the placenta previa is now just &quot;low lying.&quot; excellent news all around! by carissabyers, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6028/5954520607_a8cc8ee16c.jpg" width="500" height="500" alt="Lucy is 9 inches tall and the placenta previa is now just &quot;low lying.&quot; excellent news all around!"></a></p>

<p>Lucy is somehow part of the answer to the question that will never be answered completely.</p>

<blockquote><p>Lucy, tell me the truth, &lsquo;cause I'm in love with you.</p></blockquote>

<p class="date">July 20, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">Obviously the Paul Slavens song was written from the standpoint of a suitor, to a potential lover. But the line above stuck with me. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Alphabet-Girls-Vol-I/dp/B003MRM8RQ/">The record the song comes from is one of my favorite from last year; you should pick it up</a>.</p>




<script type="text/javascript">  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/12%20Lucy.mp3",  
        titles: "Lucy",  
        artists: "Paul Slavens"});
  });
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Dear Fellow Recreational Utilizers of the Trails and Roads Near White Rock Lake, Dallas, Texas</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/07/16/dear-fellow-recreationalists.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/07/16/dear-fellow-recreationalists.html</id>
    <updated>2011-07-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>While it is very hot outside, this does not give you license to ride your bike shirtless. The only males...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/fat-cyclist.jpg" title="fat cyclist"></p>

<p>While it is <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/dealingwith/status/92007355289567233">very hot outside</a>, this does not give you license to ride your bike shirtless. The only males who are allowed to bicycle shirtless are surfers and other drunk <a href="http://media.photobucket.com/image/fat%20shirtless%20bicyclist/nollpost/mrnspace/fat%20guys%20on%20bikes/Florida100.jpg">beachgoers</a>. (Women, in general, are <a href="http://www.flickr.com/search/?q=topless%20bicyclist">excused from this rule</a>, yet almost never break it.) Despite your proximity to water, there are no beaches at White Rock Lake. In fact, Dallas is what we refer to as &ldquo;landlocked&rdquo; in that the nearest beach is a five hour drive by motorcar. This rule applies to all men but even more so to fat men. It also applies to the adiposely-advanced runner. No one wants to see even the smallest of man-boobs bounce. Further, wearing only a heart rate monitor above the waist is evidence of even more severe social impairment and grounds for institutionalization.</p>

<p>Additionally, in cold weather, please never wear a sleeveless jersey and arm warmers. In fact, sleeveless athletic wear should be left to women and weight lifters.</p>

<p>Triathletes and those who bought and installed triathlete handlebar extensions for the road bicycle they dust off once every eight Saturdays: I would wish bad things to happen to you while you are using said handlebars but the likelihood of said bad things happening increases so much when you use said handlebars that I don't really have to wish it at all. The problem is when your absurd and unsafe riding position comes within a certain distance to my own attempts at safe, reasonable bicycling. You're a hazard. If you are really training for a competitive time trial, drive yourself and your fancy bike out to a long, flat, straight piece of road without other cyclists on it and practice there. If you're not training for a competitive time trial, then you are a complete dork.</p>

<p>Runners: while I admit my frustration with your presence and bewilderment at your choice of exercise modalities may be mirrored by your own feelings toward my bicycling, I do somewhat resent the way you can dominate a mixed-use trail like so many ants on a discarded picnic hotdog. I imagine drivers must feel the same way when stuck behind a large group ride out on the street, but at least they have air conditioning and a radio to enjoy while they wait for a moment to pass. Also, there are not 1000 large group rides all over Dallas every weekend morning.</p>

<p>Bicyclists with earbuds: there are very few times when earbuds are acceptable, mostly for reasons of your own safety. However, if you are going to be around even just a small number of other cyclists, they are unacceptable. I know music can motivate you to pedal and allow the time to pass with a bit more ease. However if you cannot hear the music in the act of bicycling, then you are missing an essential piece of the cycling aesthetic that is required to truly excel at its execution.</p>

<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/22444962?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=ffffff" width="499" height="281" frameborder="0" style="margin-bottom:1.5em;"></iframe>


<p>Police officers: if you really cared about safety on the mixed-use trails and roads around White Rock Lake you would institute speed limits and ban earbuds for both runners and cyclists. You would not camp out near stop signs in order to write tickets with as much efficiency and speed as possible. You would also not blow through a stop sign at top speed in order to catch up to and admonish cyclists for rolling through a stop sign at a slow speed.</p>

<p>To those addressed in the above paragraphs, thank you for your consideration of these simple rules. Much like covering your mouth when you cough, not speaking with your mouth full, not staring at strangers, parking between the lines, putting trash in the appropriate receptacles and not talking through a movie or concert, these simple rules can allow us all to coexist in more harmony.</p>

<p class="date">July 16, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">For additional suggestions for bicyclists (not all I agree with) see <a href="http://www.rapha.cc/raphaquette">Rapha-quette</a>.</p>




<script>
$(function() {
  $("#content > p:eq(1), #content > p:eq(2), #content > p:eq(3), #content > p:eq(4), #content > p:eq(5), #content > p:eq(6)").fancyletter({ commonClass: 'drop_cap' });
});
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Coming to Terms</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/07/12/coming-to-terms.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/07/12/coming-to-terms.html</id>
    <updated>2011-07-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Andy Zipf - I Ain't the Kind for Givin' Up You might have noticed a gradually increasing dearth of posts...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_1"><a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20I%20Ain't%20The%20Kind%20For%20Givin'%20Up.mp3">Andy Zipf - I Ain't the Kind for Givin' Up</a></span></span></p>


<p>You might have noticed a gradually increasing dearth of posts around here. I've been busy. <a href="http://extrasauce.com">Work</a> has been (lately, very) busy and, I dare say, enjoyable. I've had the amazing luck to have gone from one amazing team (Collecta&mdash;where I was for the last two years) to yet another. I cannot hide my excitement about the group of people I've found myself surrounded by at Extra Sauce and I must confess a somewhat disturbing affection* for my coworkers. I have a good feeling about this one.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5194/5857563853_37e2bc8085.jpg"></p>

<hr>


<p>I recently had the realization that no day will ever go by that I don't think about Margot. That no day will ever go by without between 10 and 50 things that trigger her memory, or the memory of losing her, or the reality of the loss I now reside in. And in that realization I became ok with it. The thought sounded something like this: &ldquo;&hellip;and that's ok.&rdquo; This is my reality. This is the rest of my life. I'm not sure how this has changed me long term. I'm not even sure if it's a burden or a freedom; maybe it is somehow both. But the simple acceptance of its permanence felt like a step in the right direction.</p>

<hr>


<p><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6012/5932834184_03bc0843fb_m.jpg" style="float: right;"></p>

<p>(Warning: TMI paragraph.) Been riding my ass off. Literally. Each of the last two Sundays I've returned from a 50 mile ride with skin missing from my backside. Not saddle sores (I worked through those earlier this year), but where the sweat&mdash;created in greater quantities in the 90-100&deg; heat and evaporating more slowly in the high humidity&mdash;pools. That is probably the worst part of the summer training. There is also the severe cramping afterwards and the slower recovery time. Still, I thought I was going to give up when it got above 90 and I'm still, somehow, cramming the miles in week after week. It's more important for my sanity than, for example, this blog. It's more important for my sanity than just about anything, which is probably what's keeping me on the bike despite the misery of the Texas summer.</p>

<hr>


<p>I've mentioned before on this blog that I was considering antidepressants and that I'd used them in the past with (limited) success. Well I finally, at the recommendation of my therapist, saw a psychiatrist and started on some antidepressants. They had their expected (and previously experienced) side effects and their desired clinical effects were negligible. I was just about to give up when he recommended an additional drug. Maybe I was desperate. Maybe I was led. Whichever the case, this thing has been amazing. I've never been so focused, motivated or full of energy before. Even my thoughts improved (obviously this is related to focus, but nevertheless). I'm not going to say what this new drug is, but let's just say you've probably seen a commercial for it on TV. Last weekend I said to a friend, &ldquo;I hate being a [drug] commercial!&rdquo;</p>

<hr>


<p><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2696/5860250877_1e9f9ae9b2.jpg"></p>

<p>In case this blog is your <em>only</em> interaction with my life (given my infrequency of posts you should really follow me on <a href="http://twitter.com/dealingwith">Twitter</a>), we found out our new baby is a girl. I had only come to terms with the fact it could be a boy about 10 seconds prior to the sonogram tech telling us it is a girl. <em>Lucy</em>. (Middle name is either <em>Pearl</em> or <em>Rae</em>&hellip;please chime in with your choice.) It's hard to think about Lucy when I still miss Margot so much, and everything baby-related (clothes, products, etc) makes me think of the past, not the future. Still, I can't help but think that there must be something really special about Lucy. Might not be just any ol' angel charged with her wellbeing.</p>

<hr>


<p>The song embedded at the top of this post is by my friend <a href="http://www.andyzipf.com/">Andy Zipf</a>** who has a new record out (<em>I Ain't the Kind for Givin' Up</em> is the opening track) that you can <a href="http://andyzipf.spinshop.com/">download for free right now</a>. I recommend you do. I've been consuming a lot of music lately (and writing none&mdash;a post for another day, perhaps) and so often a song falls into that <em>10 to 50 things a day</em> I mentioned. But sometimes a song just is, or just fits, or just helps. I was happy to discover this to be the first track on a friend's new album. It meant something.</p>

<hr>


<p><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6016/5932834374_939fc61bec.jpg"></p>

<p>Summer. It's alright.</p>

<p class="date">July 12, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">* I don't know if it's age and/or experience but I'm able to feel a combination of appreciation and acceptance for those I've chosen to be close to (in whatever capacity) that I did not have access to before.<br><br>** Say <em>Ziff</em>.</p>




<script type="text/javascript">  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20I%20Ain't%20The%20Kind%20For%20Givin'%20Up.mp3",  
        titles: "I Ain't the Kind for Givin' Up",  
        artists: "Andy Zipf"});
  });
  
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Rebuild</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/07/05/son-lux-etc.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/07/05/son-lux-etc.html</id>
    <updated>2011-07-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Rebuild by Son Lux Sun Lux's new record We Are Rising is a must have. It's blowing my mind more...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<div class="media"><iframe width="400" height="100" style="position: relative; display: block; width: 400px; height: 100px;" src="http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/v=2/track=2868174850/size=venti/bgcol=FFFFFF/linkcol=272727/vis=flowers/" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0"><a href="http://music.sonluxmusic.com/track/rebuild">Rebuild by Son Lux</a></iframe>
</div>


<p>Sun Lux's new record <em>We Are Rising</em> is a must have. It's blowing my mind more with every listen. There are a few songs that cut a little too close to the bone, and those I must skip. But overall it is a record well described by the title. <a href="http://t.co/84FfI4Q">Go get it here</a> or <a href="http://music.sonluxmusic.com/album/we-are-rising">through Bandcamp</a>.</p>

<p class="date">July 05, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript"><a href="http://twitter.com/#!/sonlux/status/86842264919359488">Ryan Lott himself replied to me on Twitter the other day</a>. I must confess I was chuffed. He was even replying to a tweet I sent <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/dealingwith/status/86305338650918912">in reply to a separate conversation</a>. I don't have the heart to tell him I can't listen to <em>Flowers</em> anymore, either.

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Nostalgia</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/14/nostalgia.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/14/nostalgia.html</id>
    <updated>2011-06-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Isn't the deal with nostalgia just that if we can live in the past, then we live before all these...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3551/3540768084_d6971c7b66.jpg" title="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lintmachine/3540768084/ Sweep by lintmachine"></p>

<p>Isn't the deal with nostalgia just that if we can live in the past, then we live before all these difficult and painful things that have happened to us? We live without the memories. We live in a time that was safe. Enjoyable. Innocent.</p>

<p>I think about the people on <em>Hoarders</em> and I wonder if it really doesn't matter what their current state is, as long as those objects they hold onto allow their minds to be somewhere else. Some kind of form of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dissociation">dissociation</a> or retrograde <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fugue_state">fugue state</a>&mdash;instead of the establishment of a new identity, there is an establishment of a prior identity.</p>

<p>Just a thought.</p>

<p>As I get older, and specifically throughout this experience, my desire for&mdash;or at least the elicitation of&mdash;nostalgic feelings has intensified. And they are very specific. The drum sounds in Phil Collin's <em>I Don't Care Anymore</em>. . .</p>

<p><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_1"><a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20I%20Don't%20Care%20Anymore.mp3">Phil Collins - I Don't Care Anymore</a></span></span></p>


<p>Or Live's <em>Pain Lies On The Riverside</em>. . .</p>

<p><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_2"><a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20Pain%20Lies%20On%20The%20Riverside.mp3">Live - Pain Lies on the Riverside</a></span></span></p>


<p>Or the look of the trees and the smell of the air along <a href="http://maps.google.com/?ie=UTF8&amp;hq=&amp;hnear=6906+Pasadena+Ave,+Dallas,+Texas+75214&amp;t=h&amp;ll=32.805289,-96.728257&amp;spn=0.00271,0.005016&amp;z=18">a particular part of trail</a> cooled by the effects of the greenery and nearby water.</p>

<p class="date">June 14, 2011</p>




<script type="text/javascript">  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20I%20Don't%20Care%20Anymore.mp3",  
        titles: "I Don't Care Anymore",  
        artists: "Phil Collins"});
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_2", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20Pain%20Lies%20On%20The%20Riverside.mp3",  
        titles: "Pain Lies on the Riverside",  
        artists: "Live"});
  });
  
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Best of Times, Worst of Times</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/13/best-worst-of-times.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/13/best-worst-of-times.html</id>
    <updated>2011-06-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Anthony Griffith - Best of Times, Worst of Times I should warn you, this story* by Anthony Griffith is intense....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_1"><a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20Anthony%20Griffith_%20Best%20of%20Times%20Worst%20of%20Times.mp3">Anthony Griffith - Best of Times, Worst of Times</a></span></span></p>


<p>I should warn you, this story* by Anthony Griffith is intense. The title does not do it justice; but then no title could. I'm not sure what prompted me to listen to it on my drive home from work today. I'm also not sure how I managed to drive through the tears. But I'm glad I did. It was very cathartic and he put into words so many things I've wished I could put into words here. I found myself shouting over my sobs, "Yes. Yes. Yes."</p>

<p class="date">June 13, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">* <a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/12/13/the-refugees.html">Another</a> from <a href="http://themoth.org/">the Moth</a> <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/podcast/the-moth-podcast/id275699983">podcast</a>.</p>




<script type="text/javascript">  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/01%20Anthony%20Griffith_%20Best%20of%20Times%20Worst%20of%20Times.mp3",  
        titles: "Best of Times, Worst of Times",  
        artists: "Anthony Griffith"});
  });
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Fear, Part 1: The Boogieman</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/08/fear-part-1-the-boogieman.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/08/fear-part-1-the-boogieman.html</id>
    <updated>2011-06-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Travis - The Fear Had the craziest nightmare last night, but it was so interesting to me that when I...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><span class="audioplayer"><span id="audioplayer_1"><a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/The%20Fear.mp3">Travis - The Fear</a></span></span></p>


<p>Had the craziest nightmare last night, but it was so interesting to me that when I woke up from it I didn't have that residual fear and icky feeling one usually has after waking from a nightmare, but was immediately struck by the meaning of it. I wish I had jumped out of bed immediately to capture the details, but unfortunately I have been extra tired this week and could not keep myself from falling back into a much more peaceful sleep.</p>

<p>But I got the gist of it. I was somehow trapped in a dark room. There were others with me in this room, although it wasn't clear later what became of them or what their role was. Also in this room was a very bad man. Some kind of horror movie character I am going to have a hard time describing; I can't think of a real horror movie character analog. He was mostly invisible. He was able to appear and disappear, making eluding him impossible. We were also trapped in this very small room, so even if I could see him the entire time it wouldn't have mattered all that much anyway. He was attacking me, scratching or otherwise able to hurt me without a weapon. The most vivid aspect of this part of the dream was my fear. I was terrified. I was more scared in this situation than I had ever been in my life.</p>

<p>Somehow I got out of the room and I was in another, larger room with a lot of people I knew. I was trying to warn them of this crazy, dangerous, murderous boogieman who was right behind me. Then he was there, attacking me again, and I was screaming, pointing, exclaiming and entreating God, as one does.</p>

<p>And then Carissa was there, gentle, approaching slowly, reaching out to touch me. And as she spoke the words, "Daniel, there's no one there," he disappeared, and I was left with only the symptoms of my panic, catching my breath, grasping reality, Carissa there calming me, helping me understand. The realization that I had gone mad and imagined the entire thing was its own, replacement fear, mixed with dread, for what it meant for me. I had allowed myself to be torn away from reality in a serious way, and would have to be brought back somehow. When the boogieman reappeared I would have to tell myself he wasn't real at just the moment my legs started to automatically run.</p>

<p>As I looked at Carissa, bewildered, I reached to touch the back of my neck and asked, "If he wasn't real, why am I hurt?" and fingered the raw skin under the scrapes. She replied just as gently, "I don't know."</p>

<p class="date">June 08, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">Funny that I had this dream the night when I went to sleep watching <em>The Century of Self</em>, including an audio clip of Anna Freud saying, "Dreams are the royal road to the unconscious."</p>




<script type="text/javascript">  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/The%20Fear.mp3",  
        titles: "The Fear",  
        artists: "Travis"});
  });
</script>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Panda Bear</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/07/T_T.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/07/T_T.html</id>
    <updated>2011-06-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>It's weird the things that will set me off. This picture breaks my fucking heart. June 07, 2011 Lately I've...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4001/4394761412_24b6877a8d.jpg" width="500" height="337" alt="13A by yukilife http://www.flickr.com/photos/yukilife/4394761412/" title="13A by yukilife http://www.flickr.com/photos/yukilife/4394761412/"></p>

<p>It's weird the things that will set me off. This picture breaks</p>

<p style="text-align:center">my fucking</p>




<p style="text-align:right">heart.</p>




<p class="date">June 07, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">Lately I've been busy enough to forget about things for large chunks of my day. Then something will trigger a thought or a memory and the wave of emotions, the front load washer spin cycle kicks into high gear and it'll even throw in some guilt about having forgotten. Just for good measure. I'm having to just plow through; and I wonder what it's doing to me.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Raffiniert ist der Herrgott, aber boshaft ist er nicht</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/06/still.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/06/06/still.html</id>
    <updated>2011-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>One of the main problems has been how completely unsatisfactory any attempts to create meaningful narrative around this situation are....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/sports.png" title="http://xkcd.com/904/ 'Also, all financial analysis. And, more directly, D&D.' the as always brilliant xkcd"></p>

<p>One of the main problems has been how completely unsatisfactory any attempts to create meaningful narrative around this situation are. Storytelling is one of the main activities of human beings, it's how we construct meaning and make sense of our lives. (I could write more about this and reference a lot of material but I barely have time to publish this short post; and that is a big rabbit hole--I might end up making less sense than if I just leave it at the previous sentence.)</p>

<p>So when the bad days arrive, like <a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/22/lately.html">I mentioned</a>, like this last Saturday and a couple days in-between, this is what my brain immediately tries to do. It cycles through a lot of different thoughts and emotions very quickly but it typically ends up trying to construct some meaningful narrative to deal with all those thoughts and emotions. And it fails. It ends up simply sad, angry, lonely and frustrated that there is nothing to explain why it has to feel that way, why the best thing that ever happened to me was taken from me, why such a beautiful life ended so soon.</p>

<p>I saw <a href="http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein#1920s">an Einstein quote</a> yesterday: "Subtle is the Lord, but malicious He is not." I like that it was followed (at some point) with: "I have second thoughts. Maybe God is malicious."*</p>

<p class="date">June 6, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">* According to wikipedia, "as quoted in Einstein in America (1985) by Jamie Sayen, indicating that God leads people to believe they understand things that they actually are far from understanding"</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Something From Nothing</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/30/this-looks-a-bit-like-an-elephant.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/30/this-looks-a-bit-like-an-elephant.html</id>
    <updated>2011-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>About a year ago I told Hal this film needed to be made, and that was before the Banksy business....</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><span class="media"><iframe frameborder="0" height="410px" src="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1605226499/something-from-nothing/widget/video.html" width="480px"></iframe></span></p>

<p>About a year ago I told Hal this film needed to be made, and that was before the <a href="http://blog.vandalog.com/2011/03/before-banksy-that-elephant-tank-was-a-mans-home/">Banksy</a> <a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/did-banksys-latest-work-bring-misery-to-a-homeless-man-2246336.html">business</a>. This is an important project and you should go support it as you are able.</p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="380px" src="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1605226499/something-from-nothing/widget/card.html" width="220px"></iframe>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">YAPAB (Yet Another Post About Bicycling)</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/26/yapab.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/26/yapab.html</id>
    <updated>2011-05-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>If you think about it, bicycling is an absurd activity in which to engage. There are many reasons: TL;DR: Bicycling...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/24290169?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=ffffff" width="499" height="281" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>


<p>If you think about it, bicycling is an absurd activity in which to engage. There are many reasons:</p>

<p style="font-style:italic; font-size: .9em; text-align: right"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Too_long;_didn't_read">TL;DR</a>: Bicycling is a beautiful activity and sport despite all the counts against it, and as such is a great metaphor for humanity's place within life's rich pageant.</p>


<p>Time: between maintaining a bicycle, shopping for new equipment, preparing for a ride (kit, contacts, collecting of necessities), actually riding (which as you become more proficient, requires more time), cleaning up after a ride and washing kit...absurd amounts of time are spent. It's a full time thing, really.</p>

<p>Danger: not only are there the dangers of simply riding down the road--wet, oily turns, railroad tracks, cracks in the pavement, debris--there are vehicles, and most notably their drivers! Not only are most of them in a <em>huge rush to get to their important life destination</em>, they are also <em>texting important things</em> while doing so, frequently paying no attention whatsoever to the road or other persons on it, assuming whatever they hit won't be killed because of course it will also be enclosed in steel and glass. Because <em>who would ride a bicycle on the road with these idiots?</em></p>

<p>There's more! Dogs, one of which I encountered today. The thing with dogs is, if they bark, they probably won't bite. It's the ones who don't make a sound you have to worry about. Today I was riding along and I heard* the sound of dog claws coming in <em>rather frequent</em> contact with asphalt. I looked back to see that the <em>biggest German Shepard</em> you have ever seen was almost within striking distance of me. Somehow I found some speed and outran him. He added a nice sprint interval to what was going to be an otherwise mid-tempo ride.</p>

<p>Then there's racing, which if you're crazy enough to train for and do, increases your chance of unfortunate contact with the pavement exponentially.</p>

<p>Cost: self explanatory. Bikes and the things they require are almost as bad as boats and Ferraris.</p>

<p>Pain: it's not just the legs and lungs. Back and butt are the real problems. One must nurture and nurse a very specific area of one's anatomy that comes in contact with that infernal device known as a saddle. As for the back, as it ages it complains ever more incessantly about the unnatural position a bicyclist subjects it to for long periods of time.</p>

<p>Despite all of this and more, we still not only continue to bicycle, but <em>actually enjoy</em> it! Even on days when I've ridden plenty, like today, or even days when I couldn't ride more even if I tried, I still feel jealousy and compulsion when I see riders go by my house**. I guess there's some magic ratio when the traffic isn't trying to kill you, and the road surface isn't trying to break your bike, and the wind isn't trying to slow you to a crawl, and the heat isn't trying to cause salty sweat to pour into your eyes and weigh down your clothes, and the glass isn't trying to force you into roadside maintenance delay...when the tempo is just right and the pedals turn with ease and the sweat actually evaporates off your body...those moments somehow fuel the fire and keep us out there day after day.</p>

<hr>


<p>There's a Calvin and Hobbes cartoon that says this much better in panels instead of paragraphs...short of finding it, scanning it and violating ridiculous copyrights by posting it here, I recommend you read a lot of <a href="http://www.bicycling.com/news/featured-stories/stroke-fate">Bill Strickland</a>, specifically that one that describes many of the aesthetic wonders of cycling (once again) better than I can.</p>

<hr>


<p>I've <a href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/12/dope.html">mentioned before</a> the current doping crisis in cycling, and the history that will need to be re-written because of the doping crisis in cycling. I don't want to harp on it much more, but if you missed <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2011/05/20/60minutes/main20064858.shtml?tag=contentMain;cbsCarousel">Tyler Hamilton on 60 Minutes last weekend</a> I suggest you check it out. If you don't realize it is still a present issue, <a href="http://bicycling.com/blogs/thisjustin/2011/05/26/contador-defence-tries-to-delay-cas-hearing/">think again</a>. And finally if you don't think we should be worried about past offenders, I suggest you consider <a href="http://bicycling.com/blogs/boulderreport/2011/05/26/failure/">this</a>.</p>

<p class="date">May 26, 2011</p>




<p class="postscript">* If I was one of you earbud-sporting jokers out there, my calves would have been doggie treats!<br><br>** We live on a popular hill loop near <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&source=s_q&hl=en&geocode=&q=white+rock+lake,+dallas&aq=&sll=32.833515,-96.72226&sspn=0.047382,0.086346&gl=us&ie=UTF8&hq=&hnear=White+Rock+Lake&ll=32.828034,-96.725349&spn=0.047385,0.086346&z=14">White Rock Lake</a>.</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Fear, Flatulence, Fingers, Fabulous</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/25/fear-flatulence-fingers-fabulous.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/25/fear-flatulence-fingers-fabulous.html</id>
    <updated>2011-05-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>Last night hail and tornados fell upon our city, distracting Penn from his homework and generally striking fear into the...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/files/bathroom_huddle.jpg" title="Bathroom Huddle"></p>

<p>Last night hail and tornados fell upon our city, distracting Penn from his homework and generally striking fear into the populace of our metroplex. As <a href="http://twitpic.com/52522m">the weather man</a> continued to pronounce the imminent destruction of our homes and businesses, Penn expressed multiple times, <em>"I'm scared!"</em> My only response was, "I am too! We all are!" I have a whole post about fear coming up.</p>

<p>When the time came, we closed all the shudders and doors and got into the bathroom located in the very middle of our house. You could barely hear the storm from in there. Then the power goes out. And it gets hot quick.</p>

<p>Then Penn goes, "Wait, I hear something!" We all get quiet. And then he lets rip a loud one! He and I laugh loud. Mom not so much. But I was pleased at how well I've trained him.</p>

<p><object width="560" height="349"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/5crL6uPIuIs?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/5crL6uPIuIs?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="560" height="349" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></p>


<p>Took this video shortly before we retreated to the bathroom. It was <em>non-stop</em> lightning. If you watch the whole clip, you'll see the <em>huge</em> strike that made me stop filming and all of us run back inside!</p>

<hr>


<p>This morning we went for our second baby appointment and another sonogram. They had to measure the baby's neck or something so to get the baby to get into a position where they could get their measurement the technician had Carissa move around. She moved to her right side: nothing. She moved to her left side and our baby did a little 80's dance. It was certainly a fantastic way to start my day, seeing that.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2257/5759151616_af1745a9ef.jpg" alt="Sonogram picture" /></p>

<p>Also there was the image above, where you can see her/his fingers. Which is awesome/amazing.</p>

<hr>


<p>Tonight I went to a talk by <a href="http://garyvaynerchuk.com/">Gary Vaynerchuk</a> who is an amazingly inspiring speaker. During the Q&amp;A he always asked how the question-asker was doing and the question-asker always reciprocated the question. His answer was either <em>tremendous</em> or <em>fabulous</em>. It's part of his thing. He's like a ball of infectious energy which I appreciated and enjoyed. Still, it made me think about that question, one we all ask. <em>"How are you?"</em> A question I have an entire blog post about as well.</p>

<p class="date">May 25, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Lately</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/22/lately.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/22/lately.html</id>
    <updated>2011-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>We've been having a few hard days. You wouldn't know it from the outside, but inside our hearts and minds...</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://mlkshk.com/r/2LWH" title="Eggs http://mlkshk.com/p/2LWH"></p>

<p>We've been having a few hard days. You wouldn't know it from the outside, but inside our hearts and minds it's been inexplicably harder the last couple days. My bad day was Friday--which happened to be the day of my first client meeting for the <a href="http://extrasauce.com">new job</a>...bad day for a bad day, although hopefully no one noticed and the meeting did go swimmingly, although that had little to nothing to do with me. Carissa's was yesterday, when I should have coerced her into coming to <a href="http://gowalla.com/checkins/37114225">paint the new office</a> but instead she was left alone home with her thoughts.</p>

<hr>


<p>It's sort of like this: everything is going really well. <em>Really</em> well. Except for that one thing. And that one thing colors all the other really good things with <em>if only, if only, if only</em>.</p>

<hr>


<p>It's sort of like this: I still think this with frequency: <em>Why? Why me? Why her? Why us?</em> The most comforting logic as of late has been that these things have no logic, no reason, no prejudice. I imagine it is the sort of thing a young man of old would experience on the battlefield. There are life lessons most people never learn anymore. There are a few still who are forced to learn them. This is a wisdom I could have done without. There are lessons we learn because of our own moral decrepitude--I have had many of those. These other lessons of which I speak, they are thrust upon us most unwillingly. It is almost like we are not allowed to live as the rest of you live. We are forced to wrestle with the angel. But our story will not be written in any holy books. Our story is barely written in your memories.</p>

<hr>


<p>I rode the Sunday morning ride as usual this morning. I'm not sure I've missed a Sunday this year except when I was out of town one weekend. This morning was particularly humid, however. So much time spent getting sweat out of eyes. <a href="http://kotori.bostonbiker.org/2008/11/22/reflection-on-the-meanings-of-kits/">Kit</a> soaked in seat weighs heavy on the frame. Not to mention the difficulty it creates in the unmentionables. No matter how you prepare the Area in Question, if sweat cannot escape it, discomfort is soon to follow.</p>

<p>The Sunday morning ride, as usual, clocked in at about 50 miles.</p>

<p>So of course I followed that up with a commute by bicycle to my new office to continue (however briefly) the painting effort.</p>

<hr>


<p>After an hour or two I joined the rest of my family for a <a href="http://apeepatthecoops.blogspot.com/">chicken coop tour</a>. Apparently this is quite foreign to most city dwellers, however we have been considering having chickens for a little while now. And there are enough people already doing it in East Dallas alone as well as enough interest in the practice to justify what appeared to be a very successful and popular event! Almost every stop had not just a fantastic coop but also a flourishing garden. Obviously I already live in a house with <a href="http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/search/label/food">amazing food</a>. But we're always on the proverbial hunt for something that can make our table even tastier.</p>

<hr>


<p>So many thoughts in between all of these, but I have not the time nor the inclination to collect them. I'm most frequently reduced to a shrug and frown and slapping of hands onto the plow. Then, later, a toast, a laugh, a story.</p>

<p class="date">May 22, 2011</p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html">Jonathan Harris: Today</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/10/today.html' />
    <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/10/today.html</id>
    <updated>2011-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary>

</summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><object width="640" height="510"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/AH7YxbuZQs8?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;hd=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/AH7YxbuZQs8?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;hd=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="510" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></p>

]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
