<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>danielsjourney</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml" />
  <id>http://2010.danielsjourney.com/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2010-11-09 22:56:08 -0600</updated>
  <subtitle>loss</subtitle>

  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Nothing to Write</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/09/nothing-to-write.html' />
    <id>/2010/11/09/nothing-to-write</id>
    <updated>2010-11-09 00:00:00 -0600</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object classid='clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000' data='http://www.flickr.com/apps/video/stewart.swf?v=71377' height='267' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' width='400'> <param name='flashvars' value='intl_lang=en-us&amp;photo_secret=1320021456&amp;photo_id=4150544887' /> <param name='movie' value='http://www.flickr.com/apps/video/stewart.swf?v=71377' /> <param name='bgcolor' value='#000000' /> <param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><embed allowfullscreen='true' bgcolor='#000000' flashvars='intl_lang=en-us&amp;photo_secret=1320021456&amp;photo_id=4150544887' height='267' src='http://www.flickr.com/apps/video/stewart.swf?v=71377' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' width='400' /></object></p>
<p>I want for but have nothing to write<br />My art wing is broken and my past full of shame<br />For those things I had supposed upon us</p>
<p class='date'>November 9, 2010</p><p class='postscript'>I started this poem on October 23rd. I have no idea where I was going with it, so I decided to just post it. Clearly I have nothing to write.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Rosabelle &mdash; answer &mdash; tell &mdash; pray, answer &mdash; look &mdash; tell &mdash; answer, answer &mdash; tell.</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/11/06/more-of-the-same.html' />
    <id>/2010/11/06/more-of-the-same</id>
    <updated>2010-11-06 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img src='http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2651/4236918239_57a2b6a385.jpg' title='Photo by Bethan Phillips http://www.flickr.com/photos/beth19/4236918239/' />
<ul>
<li>I&#8217;m still mostly sad.</li>

<li>I still miss my daughter all the time.</li>

<li>Happy times are still marked by her absence.</li>

<li>Everything would be perfect if she were still here.</li>

<li>I&#8217;m still ready for a fight that won&#8217;t come and wouldn&#8217;t help anything anyway.</li>

<li>I still exist in a world that continues on despite all these things.</li>

<li>I still struggle to resist the urge to just totally drop out.</li>

<li>I still feel really betrayed but I&#8217;m not sure with whom.</li>

<li>I would still do anything to have her back again.</li>
</ul>
<p class='date'>November 06, 2010</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Isolation</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/28/isolation.html' />
    <id>/2010/10/28/isolation</id>
    <updated>2010-10-28 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='340' width='560'><param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/i3HyRtdu1o0?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US' /><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><embed allowfullscreen='true' allowscriptaccess='always' height='340' src='http://www.youtube.com/v/i3HyRtdu1o0?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' width='560' /></object></p>
<p>First, some errata: I realized only after a night&#8217;s sleep that I did not go on anti-depressants 9 months after my divorce (<a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/27/tooth-fairy.html'>as I said</a>) but rather 18 or so. It was after <em>yet another</em> critical experience following my relocation to Texas. It was this double beat-down (as it were) that led to a kind of retreat/regroup that involved, eventually, anti-depressants.</p>

<p>Another thing that occurred to me only after a day&#8217;s passing was in regard to a private conversation I had. I was asked if I felt isolated (within a specific context) and I replied that I did; but I realized today that it&#8217;s not that context&#8211;I feel isolated in this experience. <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/09/29/motivation-mood.html' title='You all have moved on, more or less.'>I subconsciously mention this fact in this post</a>. <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/24/fast-boy.html' title='Ezra and I, we have been forced to exist in a space that not many understand.'>It is also the theme of the Fast Boy post</a>.</p>

<p>The experience of this loss, it is this constant contrast to everything else in life. All the pleasure those around me experience, even their pathetic losses (especially their pathetic losses), even that pleasure I attempt to experience myself, I can&#8217;t help but measure it against this pain. In a time when living in the moment might be more important than ever, I am able only to look backwards and forwards, this spiral of desire and loss, isolation and depression. <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/04/in-the-light-of-prior-suffering.html'>That I previously wrote about suffering is absurd</a>, that I write about this even now is equally so. In the face of the ultimate mystery of our existence, what is there to say, how is one to think, behave, speak? How does one coexist?</p>

<p>Returning to some of the thinkers that have influenced me in the past is being of some help today, hence the video I share here.</p>
<p class='date'>October 28, 2010</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Real Tooth Fairy</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/27/tooth-fairy.html' />
    <id>/2010/10/27/tooth-fairy</id>
    <updated>2010-10-27 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img src='http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1073/5118167425_ae35cce3c8.jpg' title='&apos;tooth fairy&apos; photo illustration click here for credits http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/5118167425/' />
<blockquote>
<p>This morning, Penn sulked slowly down the hallway and plopped on the couch. &#8220;She didn&#8217;t come.&#8221; He looked up at me with the biggest crocodile tears you have ever seen and I couldn&#8217;t bear to lie for that neglectful tooth fairy woman again.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>One of the side effects of the <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/09/17/insomnia.html'>insomnia</a>, which Carissa has been combating by falling asleep cuddled up next to me on the couch while I wait still for sleep to come, is the acceleration of certain veil-liftings like <a href='http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2010/10/lost-tooth-and-tooth-fairy.html'>who the tooth fairy really is</a>.</p>
<p style='text-align:center;font-size:2em;font-weight:bold'>...</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve had a couple of bad days, days where most of real life is ignored, thoughts wander towards darkness and have to be reigned in by distraction, self-medication starts early, and sleep comes late after a handful of pills. At last week&#8217;s appointment my therapist said, &#8220;Are you <em>sure</em> you don&#8217;t want to take something?&#8221;</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve been on anti-depressants before; I have a degree in psychology, I&#8217;ve been self-monitoring my depression for years now. It took 9 months after my divorce (in 2004) for the shock to turn into real depression, and I was on a cocktail of <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antidepressants'>psychoactives</a> for a year.* In 2007 I had another similar crisis and tried a new anti-depressant for about a day before giving up based on those horrible side effects.</p>

<p>Since emerging from that series of bad decisions I&#8217;ve used St John&#8217;s wort with success to combat a pretty regular depression onset. Since August I&#8217;ve been trying to maintain a regular St John&#8217;s regimen. Today I started with double my normal dose, which probably puts me at the recommended daily dose; but I&#8217;m getting the sense that its potency is wearing off. Or what it is trying to fight is getting stronger.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m not as concerned (yet) about a drug decision as I am about what this thing is turning into. There have been cycles of &#8220;It&#8217;s getting better&#8221; that alternate with cycles of &#8220;No, it&#8217;s getting worse.&#8221; <a href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/09/02/in-order-to-remember-we-must-first-forget.html'>The original post of this blog</a> is still just as applicable now as it was then. The amount I miss her every day is unmeasurable, and everything sucks without her.</p>

<p>I need a Tooth Fairy Moment. I need to know what is true, and what this terrain yet holds so I can prepare for it.</p>
<p class='date'>October 27, 2010</p><p class='postscript'>* <a href='/2010/10/28/isolation.html'>correction</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Fast Boy</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/24/fast-boy.html' />
    <id>/2010/10/24/fast-boy</id>
    <updated>2010-10-24 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4149/5038467393_ed3dfabee9.jpg' title='home by fast boy http://www.flickr.com/photos/fastboy/5038467393/in/photostream/' />
<p>The first thing you should know about <a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/fastboy/'>Fast Boy</a> (aka Ezra) is: he makes bikes. <a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/fastboy/collections/72157623961829924/'>Amazingly beautiful bikes</a>. Bikes doubling as works of art or works of art doubling as bikes, I can&#8217;t decide which. This is how I stumbled across his Flickr; I&#8217;ve found there are few bike nerds out there that do not know of his creations.</p>
<a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/fastboy/4606106327/' title='Untitled by fast boy, on Flickr'><img alt='' height='335' src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4024/4606106327_cc17338bb2.jpg' width='500' /></a>
<p><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/fastboy/2678131886/in/set-72157607075926461/'>In 2008 Ezra found out he had cancer</a>. He had chemo, radiation and surgery and fought it off in knightly fashion. Last May, he celebrated <a href='http://www.fastboycycles.com/teachingcancertocry/?p=379'>one year cancer free</a>.</p>

<p>Then, in September, <a href='http://www.fastboycycles.com/teachingcancertocry/?p=383'>it came back</a>. This time, <a href='http://www.fastboycycles.com/teachingcancertocry/?p=385'>the surgery even more severe</a>. More chemo starts soon.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a weird clich&#233; to experience, but this sense of knowing of someone else&#8217;s completely different but equally indescribably horrible experience is comforting. Not in a &#8220;I&#8217;m not alone&#8221; sense, though. I&#8217;m not supposing uniqueness, but people like Ezra and I, we have been forced to exist in a space that not many understand. We will never say <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/search/FML' title='&apos;fuck my life&apos; -- e.g. &apos;Missed the bus FML&apos;'>FML</a>. The fact that our lives are fucked is self evident, every day. But we still must live those days.</p>

<p>And Ezra <em>lives</em>. He <a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/fastboy/5054541856/in/photostream/'>cooks</a>, enjoys the company of friends, takes pictures of his hot wife, plays with his <a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/fastboy/4990523812/'>dog</a> and maintains a will strong enough to say <a href='http://www.fastboycycles.com/teachingcancertocry/'>&#8220;fuck cancer&#8221;</a> in a way no one ever doubts. Even though his body cannot lift it, I know his mind is crafting new beauty from steel.</p>

<p>Fast Boy&#8217;s circumstances are different than mine, but having both been burdened with the terrible fullness of what life can hold, there is a common fight to be had for the good parts. I only know him through his words and his lens, but he inspires me in that fight.</p>
<p class='date'>October 24, 2010</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>I Got Something with Your Name on It</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/23/i-got-something-with-your-name-on-it.html' />
    <id>/2010/10/23/i-got-something-with-your-name-on-it</id>
    <updated>2010-10-23 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4004/4642532960_9d21a5cc51.jpg' title='Photo by Bethan Phillips http://www.flickr.com/photos/beth19/4642532960/' />
<blockquote>
<p>I &#160;got something with your name on it. Stick with me.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>&#8220;Remember before they turned on the carnival? All the folded rides, dead lights. That white kid from the funnel-cake trailer, one used to suck his toe at the pool. One always singing, &#8216;I&#8217;m so full of ideas, and here is the good one.&#8217;</p>

<p>&#8220;Yeah him. You know Troy. He gave it to me. Said you might need it. Had it in his trunk in a Hefty bag, under a roll of orange electric cord and some lumps of bloody butcher paper. He had funnel cakes&#8211;stacked in paper plates and packing tape&#8211;told me forget those, said they wouldn&#8217;t travel well. He was on his way to a bus, a barbecue. Told me if anyone asks, say something like, &#8216;Ain&#8217;t seen him long as I can remember. Wouldn&#8217;t know where he is.&#8217; Say something like that he said.</p>

<p>&#8220;So here it is. If no package accompanies this letter, call me. If it&#8217;s been opened, interrogate mailman. If none of this means anything to you, I don&#8217;t know what to say.</p>

<p>&#8220;Troy said meet him in The Rusty Scupper parking lot at such-and-such a whenever. I pulled up and he&#8217;s already there, sitting on his fender with the trunk open. Had these rubber gloves on to hold the garbage bag. Huge ones, blue, kind for industrial dishes, radioactive food. And he was real anxious, all jumpy on strings. Handed me this stiff thing wrapped in brown paper. It creaked. He wouldn&#8217;t let me put it in my car. &#8216;Not right after I just handed it to you,&#8217; he said. &#8216;Take it inside, they&#8217;ll think it&#8217;s a birthday present.&#8217;</p>

<p>&#8220;I said, &#8216;Who?&#8217;</p>

<p>&#8220;&#8216;Whoever&#8217;s watching,&#8217; he said.&#8221;</p>
<p class='date'>October 23, 2010</p><p class='postscript'>From <span style='font-style:italic'>I Got Something with Your Name on It</span>, part of <a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0802139639?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=wwwdanielsjou-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0802139639' style='font-style:italic'>Gigantic</a> by Marc Nesbitt, the inspiration for an installation I did in 2004 that none of you will get to see again even if you pay me. Well, maybe if you paid me enough I would re-work the installation into something I would be satisfied with now.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>It's a Bitch, Man</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/20/its-a-bitch.html' />
    <id>/2010/10/20/its-a-bitch</id>
    <updated>2010-10-20 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class="media"><object width="640" height="390"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/PgOm8N3ZVw0&hl=en_US&feature=player_embedded&version=3"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/PgOm8N3ZVw0&hl=en_US&feature=player_embedded&version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" allowScriptAccess="always" width="640" height="390"></embed></object></p>

<p style="clear: both;">Keith Michaud is a friend and amazing songwriter from Florida. I recommend you check out <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fgp%2Fentity%2FSummer-Blanket%2FB000APRGF2%3Fie%3DUTF8%26ref_%3Dsr_tc_2_0%26qid%3D1287608344%26sr%3D1-2-ent&tag=wwwdanielsjou-20&linkCode=ur2&camp=1789&creative=390957">his records as <span style="font-style:italic;">Summer Blanket</span></a>.</p>

<p class="date">October 20, 2010</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>My Shit's (Still) F**ked Up</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/17/my-shits-still-fucked-up.html' />
    <id>/2010/10/17/my-shits-still-fucked-up</id>
    <updated>2010-10-17 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><span class='audioplayer'><span id='audioplayer_1'><a href='http://danielsjourney.com/files/01%20My%20Shit&apos;s%20Fucked%20Up.mp3'>Warren Zevon -- My Shit's Fucked Up</a></span></span></p>
<p>I have a strange anxiety with this blog that if I leave a really sad post up too long I&#8217;m putting bad energy out there, and if I leave a happier post up too long people might get the wrong impression about how well we&#8217;re (not) doing. I stumbled across this Warren Zevon song yesterday in a folder full of mp3s that I&#8217;ve had lying around forever. It felt like it struck a nice middle ground. A reminder of reality, but with a dose of good, sardonic humor. We can always use a little comedy with our tragedy. Lord knows we can use some f-bombs to describe it.*</p>
<p class='date'>October 17, 2010</p><p class='postscript'>* Unless the f-bomb really offends you, then you should not listen to this song. It sort of features it.</p><script type='text/javascript'>  
  $(function(){
    AudioPlayer.embed("audioplayer_1", {soundFile: "http://danielsjourney.com/files/01%20My%20Shit's%20Fucked%20Up.mp3",  
        titles: "My Shit's Fucked Up",  
        artists: "Warren Zevon"});
  });
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Married</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/14/Married.html' />
    <id>/2010/10/14/Married</id>
    <updated>2010-10-14 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4092/5081188250_01f7e9137d.jpg' title='Photo by Dylan Hollingsworth http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5081188250/in/photostream/' />
<p>&#8220;You weren&#8217;t married?&#8221; has been my favorite of the various responses since Sunday (I&#8217;ve heard it twice). It speaks to the reality not the formality. Still, I like seeing the ring on her hand. I like thinking about it. I like the one word titles. <em>Wife</em>.</p>
<a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5074317770/in/set-72157625021465965/'><img src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4106/5074317770_e65f4a163f.jpg' title='Daniel, Carissa and our ten guests' /></a>
<p>I liked <a href='http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2010/10/pinky-swear.html'>how we went about getting married</a>, in the end. It was more than a trip to the courthouse but way less than a typical wedding. I liked the constraints we had in terms of planning time and guest list and the simplicity* it helped engender.</p>
<a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5081188078/in/photostream/'><img src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4019/5081188078_d04079055a.jpg' /></a>
<p>There was one guest I had always imagined being front and center with her big smile and bright eyes. I hope she was smiling anyway.</p>
<p class='date'>October 14, 2010</p><p class='postscript'>* an aesthetic <a href='http://nonlinear.blogspot.com/search/label/simplicity'>near to my heart</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Penn</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/08/Penn.html' />
    <id>/2010/10/08/Penn</id>
    <updated>2010-10-08 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4128/5061075387_ce92ee5a60_z.jpg' title='Photo by Carissa http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5061075387/in/photostream/' />
<blockquote>
<p>Today Penn went to school, home with a friend, had his first den meeting, took a nap, ate a really big piece of pizza, did four pages of math homework, one practice spelling test, read one reading book and memorized the Cub Scout Promise. Also, he&#8217;s officially a pro at tying shoes. He had a better day than I did. &#8211;<a href='http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2010/10/busy-bee.html' title='Carissa Byers blog -- Busy Bee'>Carissa Byers</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I thought this terrible journey was going to make me a more understanding and compassionate person, especially in regards to Penn. If it is, it is not happening at a rate I can measure. I still get just as irritated at many of his six-year-old antics and machinations. (In ten years we&#8217;re going to miss how <a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/5061073725/in/photostream/'>sweet and cute six year olds are</a>.)</p>

<p>But tonight after tolerating a really long photo session with his mother and I, we went to eat and he thanked our waiter every time something was brought to him. We got home and he and I finished <a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aan6ZuI4z3o' title='we played the english version but I found this a funny yet accurate repesentation of the game'>Star Wars: Republic Heroes</a> on the Wii and then watched a couple episodes of the cartoon. He, out of the blue, told me he loved me and asked if he could sit beside me on the couch. I, instead of ignoring him or telling him to wait, paused the show every time he wanted to interject with a story or a &#8220;remember that time&#8230;?&#8221;</p>

<p>It&#8217;s important to remember the little things.</p>

<p>This shared experience is bonding our family together tighter. None of us have any choice but to travel through it. But Penn has the most to lose if he slows down in the fight. So many things have already required his brave face, I sincerely hope life provides him some easy progress for at least a while.</p>
<p class='date'>October 8, 2010</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>In the Light of Prior Suffering</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/04/in-the-light-of-prior-suffering.html' />
    <id>/2010/10/04/in-the-light-of-prior-suffering</id>
    <updated>2010-10-04 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img src='http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1038/1479737040_8ab5e230ea.jpg' title='# http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/1479737040/in/set-72157604534049552/' />
<blockquote>
<p>Maybe being totally perfect isn&#8217;t all it&#8217;s cracked up to be&#8230;</p>
</blockquote>

<p>&#8220;Maybe there is a fear that comes late at night, on a rare night alone, in the dark of a cold winter after the city has quieted its daily celebration. Maybe there is a fear that it might not last. Maybe there is a knowledge of terror, of that sun of success and comfort and ease making its way towards the horizon. Maybe there is an uncertainty of how long the ensuing night will last. A lack of experience of how long that closest star will be pointed at the other side of the world.</p>

<p>&#8220;Or maybe it&#8217;s because that sun has already made a trip around. Darkness had already visited a life, and that life decided during the night that the stars were not to be trusted. It was the longest night of her existence, and she swore in the middle of cold, early morning hours that if the sun ever came up again, she would revel in it, full of spite for whoever or whatever sent it back across the sky. They were not to be trusted. They were not to be thanked.</p>

<p>&#8220;And then I think, this night is beautiful. The stars form patterns against the haze of the city. A candle casts subtle tones over the pages of a book. The silence allows other voices to be heard.</p>

<p>&#8220;The pain allows for the pleasure. The loneliness teaches what affection is. The darkness reminds us that without the light we bump our knees on countless coffee table corners.</p>

<p>&#8220;We can&#8217;t pretend that the day will last forever. We can&#8217;t force the dawn with our anger and betrayal.</p>

<p>&#8220;We can live. We can learn. We can accept our fates of suffering, and if we are lucky, that suffering will teach us how not to force the sun to set on other lives sharing this universe with us.&#8221;</p>

<p><a href='http://docs.google.com/Doc?id=dfhn8fjc_140fjp8hcgc' title='Spiritual Conflict in the Everyday'>From an old ramble of mine</a></p>
<p class='date'>October 4, 2010</p><p class='postscript' />]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>No Ground</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/03/no-ground.html' />
    <id>/2010/10/03/no-ground</id>
    <updated>2010-10-03 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='281' width='500'><param name='allowfullscreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><param name='movie' value='http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=15091562&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=0&amp;show_byline=0&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1&amp;autoplay=0&amp;loop=0' /><embed allowfullscreen='true' allowscriptaccess='always' height='281' src='http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=15091562&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=0&amp;show_byline=0&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1&amp;autoplay=0&amp;loop=0' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' width='500' /></object></p>
<p>On one hand, this is just an awesome video of an awesome project.</p>

<p>On the other hand, it churned up feelings of helplessness. The first-person view of the unstoppable ascent, it reminded me of how fast and hard my heart fell, and how lightheaded I became, when I got that phone call in the lobby of <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Los_Angeles_International_Airport' title='Los Angeles International Airport'>LAX</a>, having just landed 15 minutes prior. Even as I ran across the airport to buy and board a flight back to Dallas, what was happening was an impossibility.</p>

<p>On the other hand, seeing the Earth from that vantage point, it is easier to understand just how small we are. It&#8217;s a view that speaks to our greatest hope and strength&#8211;that Margot is in a better place, and for all our turmoil and pain, she has its equal in peace and love and understanding.</p>
<p class='date'>October 3, 2010</p><p class='postscript' />]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Denial</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/10/02/denial.html' />
    <id>/2010/10/02/denial</id>
    <updated>2010-10-02 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img src='http://farm1.static.flickr.com/110/267363155_7d166fb22c.jpg' title='photo by Seven Morris http://www.flickr.com/photos/sevenmorris/267363155/' />
<p>Believe it or not, despite most of my time being spent in the depression or anger stages, I still sometimes slip into denial, now, more than a month and a half later. I fantasize about turning a corner and seeing her there, her turning towards me and smiling that amazing smile of hers. I try to comprehend how this nightmare is so real that I can&#8217;t wake up from it, and try.</p>

<p>It just still seems so impossible.</p>
<p class='date'>October 2, 2010</p><p class='postscript' />]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Carry the Weight</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/09/30/carry-the-weight.html' />
    <id>/2010/09/30/carry-the-weight</id>
    <updated>2010-09-30 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<p class='media'><object height='360' style='margin-bottom:2em;' width='640'><param name='allowfullscreen' value='true' /><param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /><param name='movie' value='http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=4639508&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=0&amp;show_byline=0&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1&amp;autoplay=0&amp;loop=0' /><embed allowfullscreen='true' allowscriptaccess='always' height='360' src='http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=4639508&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=0&amp;show_byline=0&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1&amp;autoplay=0&amp;loop=0' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' width='640' /></object></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Motivation &amp; Mood</title>
    <link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2010/09/29/motivation-mood.html' />
    <id>/2010/09/29/motivation-mood</id>
    <updated>2010-09-29 00:00:00 -0500</updated>

    <author>
      <name>Daniel Miller</name>
      <uri>http://danielsjourney.com</uri>
      <email>dealingwith@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    <summary></summary>
    <content type='html' xml:lang='en' xml:base='http://danielsjourney.com/'>
      <![CDATA[<img src='http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4130/5034311951_56be087c86.jpg' title='# http://www.flickr.com/photos/dealingwith/5034311951/' />
<p>It&#8217;s hard to stay motivated when the only thing I want in life I can&#8217;t have. It&#8217;s difficult to do anything when the reason I did everything is gone.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s hard to concentrate when so many things can carry my mind down a path that robs it of any focus. It&#8217;s impossible to think when all I can think about is her and to think about her is to experience the loss.</p>

<p>The random show we watch on television might have a split second moment that reminds us of her or of the tragedy. Or that starts a thread that leads to the same.</p>

<p>I would be lying if I said I didn&#8217;t wonder, when I see other children her age, why it wasn&#8217;t them. She&#8217;d be walking now. Saying words.</p>

<p>Certain random things sometimes help lead me away into sanity. Sometimes the more narrow the subject, the better the results. The frustrating vagaries of CSS have never been so welcome.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m at once grateful and infuriated that life continues along with or without me. I can&#8217;t keep up, but bills continue to arrive, Penn&#8217;s school life continues apace, responsibilities don&#8217;t disappear, hair continues to grow, health problems don&#8217;t defer to grief.</p>

<p>You all have moved on, more or less. You might remember her when you read this blog or when I post something weird to Twitter. But we are still in the midst of this. It is only getting harder. The pain-over-time graph has not peaked. And there&#8217;s no way to know when it will, how far we are from that apex.</p>
<p class='date'>September 29, 2010</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
